<add><doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">CDU executive meeting confirms Schaeuble </field>
<field name="text">CDU president Wolfgang Schaeuble is said to resign. These rumours surfaced in connection with the meeting. Possible successors are said to be Baden-Wuerttemberg State Premier Erwin Teufel and Governing Mayor of Berlin Eberhard Diepgen. Before the meeting, Schaeuble was strongly criticized. Thuringia's State Premier Bernhard Vogel said, someone who has failed could not be leader of the party. After the executive meeting, the president of the CDU faction of the North Rhine-Westphalian legislature Linzen and Baden-Wuerttemberg's State Premier Teufel said, the CDU presidency had made clear that if Schaeuble resigned the entire executive board would resign as well. The party leaders also called on ex-chancellor Helmut Kohl in a motion to suspend his honorary presidency until he has named his donators. At the same time, the presidency apologized to the Jewish citizens for Manfred Kanther's lies in connection with the million mark transfers from foreign accounts. The most dramatic paragraph of the motion by the CDU leadership was probably that for the first time, the leadership clearly distanced themselves from former Chancellor Kohl.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Helmut Kohl resigns as honorary president of CDU </field>
<field name="text">Former chancellor Helmut Kohl has resigned as honorary president of the CDU. In a statement released on Tuesday in Berlin, Kohl defends his decision with the CDU's request to suspend his office until he has made his contribution to resolve the party donations affaire.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">CDU and FDP against self-dissolution of Hesse's parliament </field>
<field name="text">The CDU and FDP factions of the Hesse legislature have argued against a self-dissolution of the parliament. CDU faction leader Kartmann said after the deliberations that the factions continued to support State Premier Roland Koch. In a joint motion, SPD and Greens intended to dissolve the legislature because of the CDU finance affair. SPD and Greens need the support of at least two members of the coalition to pass the motion. Federal Foreign Minister Joschka Fischer called on CDU and FDP to support the opposition's motion. The Green minister argued they should do so not only because the Christian-Democrats had illegally financed their election campaign and thus distorted the rules of competition, but also because there would be further disclosures in the affaire and the dissolution of the legislature would become obligatory.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Prosecution searches Hesse's CDU headquarters </field>
<field name="text">The prosecution is said to have searched the headquarters of Hesse's CDU. News magazine "Der Spiegel" reports that investigators have also searched the office of economic advisor Horst Weyrauch and former state treasurer Casimir Prinz zu Sayn-Wittgenstein. Both are being investigated for embezzlement and fraud in connection with the CDU finance affaire.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Schilly announces bill on so-called small firearms licences </field>
<field name="text">The minister of the interior Schily has announced the arrival of a bill on a so-called "small firearms licence". His intention is that, in future, owners of blank guns and Very pistols must demonstrate their ability to handle them properly and responsibly. The chairman of the ministry of interior conference Behrens, will also strive to attain a ban on the possession of  'Butterfly' knives and spiked metal throwing discs.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Former SED-official Kleiber begins prison sentence today </field>
<field name="text">Guenther Kleiber, the last former SED-official to receive his sentence, began his prison term today. As did Guenther Schrabow, Kleiber received a three year sentence. Egon Krenz is having his six-and-a-half year sentence reviewed by the European Court for Human Rights.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Government aid for Holzmann examined by EU-commission </field>
<field name="text">The Holzmann company will probably have to wait a few months longer for the agreed on 250 million DM aid from the government. It was announced in Brussel today that it may take as long as that for the EU-commission to determine on the necessity for government aid.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Monika Boettcher released on probation </field>
<field name="text">Monika Boettcher, divorced from Weimar, is being released on probation. Following a decision by the provincial high court, she must hand in her passport and report to the police regularly. Boettcher was sentenced to life imprisonment for the murder of her two daughters. The sentence has not come into force as yet.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Quality control criticize advice banks on building financing </field>
<field name="text">Banks often give their customers poor advice on construction financing. The organisation for quality control reached this conclusion after a nation wide investigation. The consumer protection organisations criticize the fact that, after purchasing real estate, customers often discover that they have paid too much or have taken on excessive credit, despite consultation with the bank. Only two of the 20 investigated institutions received a positive evaluation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-18</field><field name="title">Bayern's IG Metall support a 5.5 percent wage increase and interest of 60 </field>
<field name="text">Bayern's IG Metall company has decided to support a 5.5 percent wage increase and an interest of 60 for the imminent pay round. With this, the metal trade unions are the first to act on the proposal made by the trade union committee.  </field></doc></add>