<add><doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">Day Before State Parliament Elections in Hesse </field>
<field name="text">A new state parliament will be elected tomorrow in Hesse.  Approximately 4.3 million registered voters will have 17 parties and electoral coalitions to choose from. The CDU and FDP have made it their goal to break up the SPD and Green majority that has ruled for the past 8 years. However, according to opinion polls, the government, led by Minister President Eichel (SPD), will probably strengthen its lead over the opposition and its challenger Koch (CDU).  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">NATO Increases Pressure on Partners in the Kosovo Conflict </field>
<field name="text">The USA has warned that a breakdown of the Kosovo conference will have consequences. At the international security conference in Munich, US Secretary of Defense William Cohen said that NATO will reserve the right in that event to carry out air attacks. All participants in the security conference appealed to all parties of the conflict to reach an agreement at the peace talks in France.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">Alleged Amnesty for Tax Evaders </field>
<field name="text">According to the "Spiegel," German Finance Minister Oskar Lafontaine is apparently planning to institute a radical reform in the taxation of interest and an amnesty for tax evaders. Lafontaine wants to enact an amnesty for tax exiles. Whoever reveals their hidden finances to the treasury will not be punished under the amnesty and can keep the appropriated funds. However, in return he or she will be forced to purchase low-interest government bonds. There was no official statement from the Ministry of Finance on this matter.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">AOK Approves the Closure of More Hospitals </field>
<field name="text">According Mr. Ahrens, the federal chairman of the AOK [Germany's largest health insurer], it will only be possible to keep current contribution levels stable for another year if more hospitals are closed. Ahrens claimed that up to 20 percent of patients could be treated on an outpatient basis. Ahrens referred to a recent European study that claims that there are 85,000 unnecessary hospital beds in Germany as a whole and that patients are also often kept in hospitals longer than necessary in order earn more money. Ahrens claims that this nonsense must stop.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">DAG Also Approves of Pension at the Age of 60 </field>
<field name="text">The German white-collar union (DAG) is calling for a deduction-free pension as of 60 years of age. The labor market can quickly be relieved of the strain of one and a half million unemployed persons through early retirement. At the same time the federal government must increase the contributions to the pension scheme. The DAG thereby supports the German Federation of Labor Unions which will make these recommendations in talks meant to draw up the Alliance for Work.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">Will There be Another Design Competition for the Holocaust Memorial? </field>
<field name="text">The American architect Eisenmann strictly refuses any further reduction of his field of steles for the Berlin Holocaust memorial. His original design had planned 4,000 concrete pillars; the second reworked design had 2,700. The Berlin State minister of culture is now assuming that there will have to be another design competition for the memorial. Eisenmann told the newspaper "Berliner Tagesspiegel" that he would take part. ["Stele" is a relatively rare architectural term for a memorial slab found near tombs. Eisenmann uses it to describe the rectangular pillars of various heights that make up his proposed memorial.]  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">One-third of All Criminals in Germany Are under the Age of 21 </field>
<field name="text">According to police statistics that were presented at a seminar of SPD law students in Hamburg, almost every third criminal in Germany is under the age of 21. A total of 2.3 million suspects were recorded in 1997. 140,000 of these suspects were children under the age of 14, 290,000 were teens between the ages of 14 and 18, and 230,000 were young adults between 18 and 21. More than one in two suspected car burglars and robbers are less than 21 years of age.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">Chaos on the Roads in Bavaria and Austria </field>
<field name="text">Massive snowfalls have created considerable chaos and delays on the roads of Bavaria and Austria and led to kilometer-long traffic jams heading north as well as south. The Tauern autobahn in Austria was closed near Flachau after an avalanche and will probably be open again for traffic tomorrow morning at the earliest. According to the Austrian automobile club, all of the alternative routes are also overloaded. The Inntal autobahn is also chaotic. Other streets, for example the approach to Arlberg, were closed due to the danger of avalanches.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">International Soccer: USA-Germany </field>
<field name="text">The German national team lost 0:3 against the United States in an exhibition game in Jacksonville, Florida. Hopeless confusion reigned among the German 11 from the very beginning. The Americans tied up the Germans in their own half of the field for most of the game.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-06</field><field name="title">From the Editors' Desk </field>
<field name="text">For technical reasons, the Friday edition of GermNews/DE-News could not be published yesterday.  </field></doc></add>