<add><doc><field name="date">1999-06-25</field><field name="title">Parliament for holocaust monument </field>
<field name="text">A vast majority of the members of parliament (Bundestag) voted against the "Eisenman II" draft for a holocaust monument. The draft provided for rows of columns and a small information stand. Theologian Schroeder's proposal to put up a monument with the inscription "Do not murder", however, was voted down. Earlier on, parliament had decided that they did not want to do away with a monument altogether (439 for, 115 against). Then they voted for building a monument for the murdered European Jews only (325 for, 218 against).  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-25</field><field name="title">Reactions to parliament's decision on holocaust monument </field>
<field name="text">After the decision for the holocaust monument, most politicians across all parties were happy and relieved. President of the Central Jewish Council in Germany, Mr Bubis, was glad that parliament's vote for the monument had also been what the people wanted. One of the backers of the monument, Ms Rosh, said she wanted to work with the trust fund set up to look after the project - though she anticipated delays caused by the state of Berlin.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-25</field><field name="title">Chancellor Schroeder: no tax-hikes </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Schroeder ruled out more tax-hikes before the next federal elections. When interviewed by the tabloid BILD, he stated that the debate was closed as far as this legislative period was concerned. Tax-hikes and more spending would not fit the picture. Referring to ideas by the SPD parliamentary group about re-introducing the tax on private assets (Vermoegenssteuer), Mr Schroeder said that checking them out wouldn't cost a red cent. But he was adamant that he wanted to lower taxes, not raise them.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-25</field><field name="title">Life assurances to be taxed </field>
<field name="text">Government decided to save money and that's why all capital life assurance policies will attract tax at the rate of 25% after 22 June. That's when cabinet agreed to the new scheme, according to the Finance Minister. Existing policies or policies with monthly subscription payments would not be affected. Also Labour Minister Riester allegedly wanted to window-dress numbers so he could lower pensions. According to the newspaper HANDELSBLATT, child benefit payments (Kindergeld) would not be included in the average net wage any more (used for the calculation of pensions). Government, however, countered that they had to do it, to comply with EU-rules  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-25</field><field name="title">Minister for Internal Affairs lifts deportation stop </field>
<field name="text">As of today, federal borderguards (Bundesgrenzschutz) may deport persons whose applications for asylum have been turned down, even if they are expected to vigorously resist deportation. This virtually ends the preliminary stop on deportations in similar circumstances, ordered by Minister for Internal Affairs Schily following the death of a Sudanese man. Allegedly new rules had been worked out, and as of today no more bike-helmets would be used. The Baden-Wuerttemberg government stated that they would not deport anyone themselves in this manner.  </field></doc></add>