<add><doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Unemployment down in May </field>
<field name="text">Last month saw another drop in unemployment, according to federal government spokesperson Hauser (down by 120,000 to 4,075 million, as of May). The average unemployment rate within Germany now stands at 10.5% - compared to 10.9% last year. The Nuremberg Federal Labour Office (Bundesanstalt fuer Arbeit) will release their official figures on Tuesday. Mr Hauser justified his jumping the gun as the press had done worse and already published wrong data.  Chancellor Kohl said the new numbers meant a trend-reversal in the labour market. He was convinced that the number of unemployed persons will drop below the 4 million mark this autumn (fall). Mr Lafontaine, of the SPD, said that Mr Kohl's optimism was part of his electioneering: prior to elections usually more work-schemes would be set up. And apart from that, there would always be more people in work in summer than in winter.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Mr Kohl defends government's policies regarding foreigners </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Kohl defended his government's policy regarding foreigners. Last night he said in Erlangen/Bavaria that the boat was full, as far as the number of refugees was concerned: it would be hopeless endeavouring to solve the world's plights and misery within the small territory of the Federal Republic of Germany. People in need should get assistance in their home countries. This had nothing to do with xenophobia - the dislike of foreigners.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Morsleben shipments also broke nuclear activity limits </field>
<field name="text">Shipments of radioactive waste to the final depository at Morsleben/Saxony- Anhalt now had high radio-activity readings. According to the newspaper BERLINER ZEITUNG, the Federal Environment Ministry had confirmed this. The material would have come from the de-commissioned reactor at Wuerggassen. One of the transport-containers had shown readings above the set threshold of 5 becquerel/square centimetre. Procedures had been followed, at the time, when they had briefed the federal supervisory agency  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Poland's Seym criticises Germany's resolution concerning expulsions </field>
<field name="text">Poland's parliament, the Seym, criticised Germany's resolution on expulsions after World War II, as ambiguous and containing dangerous tendencies. In May Germany's parliament had passed a resolution (using the votes of the coalition partners) determining that the expulsion of approx. 5 million Germans from currently Polish territory had broken international law. And it also voiced hopes that, once Poland and Tchechia had become members of the EU, they would not single out German refugees but grant them the right to settle there, too.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Arsonists who helped put refuge to the torch sentenced </field>
<field name="text">The Regional Court sentenced the masterminds of the arson attack on the Dolgenbrot refuge to between 15 months and 2 years jail, suspended. They had paid the arsonist and manufactured the accelerants. The refuge had burned down just before 86 persons who had applied for asylum were to move in.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">Baden-Baden's Festival Centre managers sacked </field>
<field name="text">The managers of the privately-run local Festival Centre have been sacked. Reiner Voegele (sp?) and Klaus Klein had made sure the cultural events venue - opened less than three months ago - made it into the headlines and bad books all the way. As ticket-prices were too expensive, there was little patronage, but they kept giving away tickets to keep appearances.  Mr Andreas Moelig-Zehphauser (sp?), who has a background in musicand theatre-science, will take over now.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-03</field><field name="title">French policeman beaten up by hooligans on the mend </field>
<field name="text">The French policeman hurt by German soccer hooligans, is recovering, according to the doctors treating him. Mr Daniel Nivelle (sp?), however, still is in a coma and on a respirator. After the Worldcup soccer game between Germany and Yugoslavia, he had been almost bludgeoned to death. Two of the alleged criminals have been remanded in (a French) prison.  </field></doc></add>