<add><doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Schroeder and Dalema discuss Italian peace plan </field>
<field name="text">Federal Chancellor Schroeder met with Italian leader Dalema in Bari. Main topic was the newest Italian peace plan for the settlement of the Yugoslavian War.  Dalema's proposal entails a NATO cease-fire, should Russia and China vote against Belgrade in a UN resolution.  Should Yugoslav President Milosevic renege on a pullout of his troops from Kosovo, Dalema would plead for the deployment of NATO ground forces. Foreign Minister Fischer foresees no majority in the Bundestag for sending in ground troops.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Eichel challenges Ministries to save </field>
<field name="text">Finance Minister Eichel challenged the Federal Ministries in writing to share in the coverage of financial gaps according to share in the Federal budget.  Eichel wrote  in a letter to his ministry colleagues that the rehabilitation of the budget is an economic task for the whole federal government.  Each department must contribute.  Only thus can the march into debtor status be stopped.  The financial situation of the Federal Republic is dramatic; a deficit of  30 billion Marks in the 2000 budget, and though 2003 50 billion.  The strictest cutbacks of 13 billion fall upon Employment and Social Minister Riester.  The Defense Ministry has to cut 3.5 billion Marks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Muentefering refuses speed limit </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Environmental Bureau and Traffic Minister Muentefering are fighting over the speed limit.  The Bureau is for a 100 km/hr. limit on highways and 30 km/h within cities, which should bring more travelling security, and lower noise and pollutants.  Muentefering refuses these speed limits, saying there's nothing about it in the coalition contract with the Greens.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Attack on residence of German Ambassador to Athens </field>
<field name="text">An attack was made on the residence of the German Ambassador to Greece last night.  According to Greek police, 2 bazookas were fired at the building, which was damaged.  Ambassador Kuna and his wife were in the house at the time of the attack, but were not injured.  Nine days earlier a bomb exploded near by at the Dutch Ambassador's residence.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Deutsche Bank not merging with Italian bank group </field>
<field name="text">Deutsche Bank denied a newspaper report about a supposed planned merger with the Italian bank group Unicredito.  The rumors were completely unfounded, said a spokesperson in Frankfurt.  The Duesseldorf Handelsblatt reported that there were signs that Deutsche Bank would propose a takeover or stock exchange offer today.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">French Telecom wants to sue Deutsche Telecom </field>
<field name="text">France Telecom wants to sue Deutsche Telecom for damages due to the planned merger with Telecom Italia.  The previous partner of the Germans turned to the International Chamber of Commerce for a judgement.  The damages amount to several billion Euros.  The French see a breach of contract, because Deutsche Telecom allegedly made merger plans with the Italians without putting it to a vote.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Rhine flood subsides </field>
<field name="text">The flooding in southern Germany and Switzerland had gone down last night.  According to Mannheim's River Police, the flood waters are sinking or stagnating.  The Rhine transport is further resting at about 280 km between Rheinfelden and Mannheim.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">Dillingen massacre presumed to be revenge </field>
<field name="text">The fugitive assassin from Dillingen had allegedly acted out of revenge.  One of the victims occasionally worked for the police as an informant.  He incriminated accused perpetrator Guenther Ewen last year due to a series of robberies.  A total of 5 are dead, and 11 are wounded in Dillingen and in France from yesterday's bloodbath.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-17</field><field name="title">No expansion of air traffic from Duesseldorf airport </field>
<field name="text">The Upper Administrative Court of Muenster stopped the expansion of air traffic from the Duesseldorf airport.  The judgement followed the complaints of residents.  According to the judgement, the State government falsely estimated the effect on the population of the expansion in business.  </field></doc></add>