<add><doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Annan welcomes the establishment of the International Criminal Court </field>
<field name="text">UNO Secretary General Annan has welcomed the establishment of the International Criminal Court for the investigation and prosecution of genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity and aggression. Annan spoke at the signing ceremony in Rome and spoke of a giant step for more justice. The delegates of 120 states voted in favor of the establishment of the Criminal Court in the Hague, Netherlands. Seven countries - including the USA, China, India and Libya - voted against the statute. They felt the tribunal will have too much power.  According to Foreign Minister Kinkel, the German government wished that the Court had more authority. Kinkel said in the German radio station "Deutschlandfunk" that the agreement is nonetheless historic, and he believes that ratification of the statute will occur quickly.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">SPD wants to buy fewer Eurofighters in case of election win </field>
<field name="text">The SPD wants to discuss the Eurofighter again should they win the elections. The speaker for defense politics Kollbow (sp?) said in the Cologne newspaper "Sonntagsexpress" that the government had decided to purchase 180 new fighter planes against the will of the Social Democrats. 375 million Marks from the 1999 budget were allotted for the purchase alone. The Eurofighters cost the taxpayers approximately 30 billion Marks or more. In order to save money, new ways could probably be found to purchase fewer Eurofighters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">The Greens: Federal Government neglects Eastern Germany </field>
<field name="text">The committee speaker of the Buendnis 90/Greens, Roestel, has accused the Federal Government of neglecting Eastern Germany. She claims that is also the reason for the election of the right-wing extremist party DVU (Deutsche Volksunion) in Saxony-Anhalt. At the Eastern German Green party conference, Roestel also added that the party wanted to make the five new federal states into ecological high-tech states and that this is only possible with an ecological/social tax reform.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Police breaks up NPD meeting </field>
<field name="text">The police broke up an illegal meeting of NPD (Nationaldemokratische Partei Deutschlands) supporters. The right-wing extremists had apparently switched the location of their meeting to Magdeburg, since a meeting in Tangerhuette in Saxony-Anhalt was declared illegal by the Upper Administrative Court (Oberverwaltungsgericht) in Naumburg. The police had transferred several groups of a hundred to Tangerhuette to avoid riots.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Mining accident in the Steiermark </field>
<field name="text">Contrary to earlier information, one miner has survived the pit accident in the Steiermark. When ten workers died trying to rescue their buried coworker, the eleventh worker managed to get himself to safety at the last minute. He initially ran away under shock and notified the authorities later.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Kohl for stronger measure against sexual assault on children </field>
<field name="text">Federal Chancellor Kohl announced he will initiate stronger international actions against child abuse and sexual assault. The Chancellor said that the newly discovered case in the Netherlands is shocking.  The Belgian citizen initiative "Werkgroep Morkhoven" does not want to turn over their evidence on the child pornography ring and refuses to work with the Dutch police. The initiative explained that the reason for their hesitance is that their methods are considered criminal in the Netherlands. The Dutch press has reported on the initiative's controversial methods. Apparently the broke into apartments to secure the incriminating evidence. Approximately 10,000 pornographic pictures and numerous addresses of manufacturers and customers are saved on many diskettes.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Many traffic jams due to vacation begin </field>
<field name="text">Many traffic jams on the Autobahns to the south have occured due to the begin of school summer vacations in several German states as well as in the Netherlands. The cars queued up to 25 kilometers on the A8 near Salzburg. Similar situations have also occurred on the other main routes through the Alps. For example, vacationers queued up in traffic jams of more than 20 kilometers in front of the Gotthard tunnel in Switzerland.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-18</field><field name="title">Bicycle racing: Tour de France </field>
<field name="text">Jan Ullrich, the defending champion of the Tour de France, won the time trial from Merygnec l'Eglise to Correze and took over the yellow jersey, emblematic of the overall lead, by a total of one minute 18 seconds over Bo Hailton, who rides for the US Postal team.  The Tour de France is over for the Festina team. The team decided to follow the tour's request to leave the race after the doping scandal that found three Festina officials under police investigation. The director of the Tour de France Leblanc announced the team's disqualification. He had met earlier with Festina riders. Virenque, second in the Tour last year, drove in the team van past the starting line on his way to the team hotel and cried from disappointment. Some Festina riders had stated that they wanted to start in the time trials. However, the race directors made clear that the team had been disqualified and that their times would not be considered in the standings. Festina team director Roussel and team doctor Ryckaert admitted to systematic doping in police custody in Lille.  </field></doc></add>