<add><doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Suessmuth: call for better protection of children from sexual assaults </field>
<field name="text">The president of the Bundestag (Lower House) Rita Suessmuth has called for better protection of children from sexual assaults. During the central rally opening World Children's Day, Ms. Suessmuth also said that children whose parents are unemployed should not be pushed into welfare. According to the children's advocacy group "Kinderhilfswerk", one and a half million children in Germany depend on welfare. The organization views that as an expression of hostility against children. Mr. Krueger, the president of the organization  has called for a fight against child poverty. He also lobbied for a lowering of the voting age to give teenagers more influence.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Kohl wants to reform labor law </field>
<field name="text">German Chancellor Helmut Kohl wants to reform German labor law should his party win the coming elections.  In an interview with the paper "Die Welt", Mr. Kohl stated that unemployed people who reject reasonable job offers have to expect for welfare cuts. This will have an effect on unemployment numbers. He said that there must be further aid for the labor market in the East which is unable to sustain itself at this time.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Kohl outraged about debate on Clinton's sex affair </field>
<field name="text">German Chancellor Helmut Kohl has expressed outrage at the public debate about  US President Bill Clinton sex affair. In an interview with the daily newspaper "Die Welt", Mr. Kohl said that he is not the judge of Mr. Clinton's private life. He himself has to stand for that. But that the world public follows most private occurrences with hypocritical greed on the Internet "makes me sick", the Chancellor said. It is bad that the most important power in the world indulges in an interior debate, as if there was nothing else that mattered.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Identity of Arabic terrorists uncovered </field>
<field name="text">The identity of the suspected terrorist arrested near Freising has been uncovered. Bavarian Minister of the Interior  Beckstein announced in the afternoon that it is Mamdu Mahmut Salim who is on wanted lists throughout the world. Mr. Beckstein said the man has admitted to knowing of the Saudi terrorist Bin Laden, but disputed having anything to do with the terrorist actions of the Bin Laden group. The American Secret Service believes the arrested man is the financial manager of the terrorist group. He also is believed to have procured weapons. The group is considered instrumental in the attacks on two US embassies in Africa which killed 260 people.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Demands for reorientation of Bavarian SPD </field>
<field name="text">The Secretary General of the Bavarian Social Democratic Party (SPD) Hoderlein had demanded a reorientation of his party when choosing top candidates in the future. Mr. Hoderlein said that the SPD has to find a completely new strategy if not even a woman like Renate Schmidt can undermine the Christian Social Union's (CSU) position. He can imagine that his party could find an experienced federal SPD Minister or a popular Bavarian SPD Mayor to run against the CSU. In the last state election the SPD received only 28.7 percent of the vote.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Record numbers of visitors in the opening days of Octoberfest </field>
<field name="text">Octoberfest number 165 saw record numbers of visitors on its first day: 700,000 according to police sources. The climax today [Sunday] was the traditional parade in traditional costumes. Approximately 7,500 people in Bavarian costumes marched through the center of the city, accompanied by bands and decorated carriages. The first Octoberfest weekend is overshadowed by one fatality: a 24 year old collapsed after a trip on the ship-swing. He died of heart and circulation collapse. He was severely inebriated and might have consumed other drugs as well.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Marathon world record in Berlin </field>
<field name="text">Brazilian runner Ronaldo da Costa has won the Berlin marathon in world record time. During the 25th edition of the largest marathon in Germany, he ran 42.195 kilometers in 2:06:05 hours, improving the ten-year-old record of Belaine Densimo from Ethiopia by 45 seconds. In addition to the prize money of 40,000 marks, the surprise winner also received 100,000 marks for beating the world record. 25,530 runners were at the start of the marathon in Berlin.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-20</field><field name="title">Stefan Effenberg confirms resignation from national team </field>
<field name="text">During a press conference, Stefan Effenberg confirmed that he is resigning from the national football team. Three weeks after his comeback on the DFB team, the 30-year-old mid field player from "FC Bayern Muenchen" said: "As long as I play soccer professionally, I will not play for the national team." He said he wanted to concentrate on the Bavarian team in the next three years and wants to spend free time with his family.  </field></doc></add>