<add><doc><field name="date">1999-12-18</field><field name="title">Political Contributions </field>
<field name="text">The Hamburg businessman Karl Ehlerding has decided to make no further political contributions for the time being.  He told the newspaper "Bild am Sonntag" that contributors to parties are worried that they will get caught in an ambiguous situation.  Until now, the CDU has received roughly 6 million marks from Ehlerding. Ehlerding is the majority stakeholder in a real estate company that is supposed to buy 31,000 railway workers' apartments. It has been recently suggested that the company could only have gotten the contract because of its contributions to the CDU.  Ehlerding protested against accusations that his millions in contributions already influenced the sale of 114,000 federally owned railway workers' apartment. In previous years, the contract was awarded to a consortium of which Ehlerding was a part by Matthias Wissmann, who was then the transport minister.  Ehlerding said that the SPD under Chancellor Schroeder was if anything a stronger advocate on behalf of the consortium.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-18</field><field name="title">Possible cutbacks in public campaign financing </field>
<field name="text">Because it accepted concealed funds, the CDU is now threatened with a 46 million mark cut in public financing.  This could come about if a full disclosure is not made for 1998 accounts, showing all the names and amounts, by the 31st of December, according to the "Sueddeutsche Zeitung." Helmut Kohl, the former chairman of the CDU, has so far resisted disclosing the names of contributors from whom he annually collected around 300,000 marks. Hildegard Bamm-Bruecher (FDP) has in the meantime called for an overall cut in public funding for political campaigns.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-18</field><field name="title">Party funding scandal </field>
<field name="text">The chairman of the committee investigating the CDU party funding scandal, Volker Neumann, has confirmed that the Leuna files are missing from the Chancellor's office.  The SPD politician said it could turn out to be a case of suppression of evidence or burglary.  According to a government spokesman, documents are being examined in connection with the sale of the east German Leuna refinery to the French company Elf-Aquitaine.  The former head of the Chancellor's office, Friedrich Bohl, told "Suedwestrundfunk" that absolutely no files were removed or destroyed during his term in office.  If they have disappeared, he continued, it must have happened after last year's change in government.  Bohl said that the 1992 sale of the Leuna works had nothing to do with party contributions.  The Thyssen company, which participated in the sale, has already said that it will turn its files in the matter over to the investigating committee. Thyssen will also deliver its files relating to the sale of tanks to Saudi Arabia, another contract that is suspected have having been influenced by bribes.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-18</field><field name="title">Business tax reform </field>
<field name="text">The federal government will present its plans for business tax reform before Christmas.  Finance Minister Hans Eichel announced that he and Chancellor Schroeder will lay out the main ideas this coming Tuesday rather than on the 15th of January.  In total, business are supposed to pay 8 billion marks less in taxes starting in 2001.  </field></doc></add>