<add><doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">54th day of air raids on Yugoslavia </field>
<field name="text">NATO continued its air raids last night targeting in particular electricity works and fuel storage tanks. Furthermore, on the 54th day of air raids on Yugoslavia the Alliance bombed industrial areas and bridges. East Serbian mines and industrial regions around the city of Bor were targeted for the first time. Six people were apparently injured in these attacks, according to the news agency in Belgrade.  The neighbouring country of Albania has called of the state of emergency which they hand instituted as a result of the huge wave of refugees from Kosovo. Only a few refugees crossed the border to Albania yesterday.  NATO has announced that the air raids will continue despite the danger for civilians. The Commander Clark of NATO's alliance said during a visit to Tirana that the air raids will increasingly concentrate on Yugoslavian ground troops. He said that he was aware that refugees from Kosova are being used by the Serbian military as a human shield as happened in the village of Korisa in the Kosova. However, he continued that he also has great faith in NATO's ability to accurately select their targets.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Italian prime minister presents peace plan for Kosovo </field>
<field name="text">Dalema, Italian prime minister, has presented a new peace plan for Kosovo. His suggestions, according to the newspaper "La Republica", include a one-sided cease-fire, the condition being that Russia and China vote against Milosevic in a UN resolution. Mr. Dalema suggested that NATO ground troops should be sent in if, after a cease-fire, the Yugoslav President still doesn't withdraw his troops from Kosova. Mr. Shay, NATO spokesman, said that the Alliance welcomed all diplomatic activities towards finding a peaceful solution to the conflict. All NATO states would however carry on supporting the air raids until Milosevic gave in, continued Mr. Shay. However, the peace plan put forward by Mr. Dalema was welcome.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Riester says changes to the DM 630 regulations unlikely </field>
<field name="text">Walter Riester, Federal Minister of Labour says that it is unlikely that the tax regulations for so-called "630 mark jobs" will be changed. In a newspaper interview he said that he did not believe that the Chancellor would give in once again on this issue. Chancellor Schroeder had said to his parliamentary group that he did not think that the regulations had to be changed.  According to Mr. Riester, there have been no discussions about statements from leaders of the SPD concerning allowing possible exceptions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">State party conference of SPD in Bavaria </field>
<field name="text">The SPD in Bavaria's state party conference continued with an appeal from Mr. Ude, Mayor of Munich, for party members to keep party affairs private. Mr. Ude said that the SPD cannot allow itself to be divided into modernist and traditionalist groups. Mr. Hanzog, a state parliamentarian, had previously tried to get onto the agenda a renewed vote regarding the operation in the Kosovo. The board had rejected this application saying that a new party conference would be necessary to discuss such an item. To conclude the party conference, party delegates plan to reach a decision as regards a referendum opposing six levels at secondary grammar schools.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Water levels drop </field>
<field name="text">Water levels in the upper Rhine area have dropped visibly. Levels in Germany are expected to drop further by tomorrow. The water level in Karlsruhe fell to 8,63 meters and remained at half a meter below the critical point. Areas near river banks have been flooded in Karlsruhe and Mannheim, however residential areas are not endangered. According to the Ministry for the Interior of Baden-Wuerttemberg, dams are stable.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Unknown gunman kills four </field>
<field name="text">Four people were killed early this morning (Sunday). According to police reports, an unknown gunman shot the owner of a disco, who has subsequently died in hospital, several times. A couple were shot with the same weapon in their home later in the morning. The gunman has been able to flee. The background to the crime is at this stage unknown.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Soccer Bundesliga 1st Division </field>
<field name="text">Schalke 04 - 1. FC Kaiserslautern  2:0  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">Double victory for Ferrari in Monte Carlo </field>
<field name="text">The Ferrari team has won a double victory in the grand prix in Monte Carlo. Michael Schumacher has won the race with his team-mate Eddi Irvine taking second place. Mika Hakkinen, the reigning world champion, came third in McLaren-Mercedes beating Heinz-Harald Frentzen who was fourth. This victory brings Schumacher into the lead with 26 points. Irvine is second with 18 points and Hakkinen is third with 14 points.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-16</field><field name="title">"Black" weekend on Bavarian roads </field>
<field name="text">Three people were killed in two motorbike accidents this afternoon (Sunday). A young man was killed on his 24th birthday near to Erlangen. His front wheel had locked when braking after he had overtaken a car at great speed. The young man, who was from Nuremberg, skidded and crashed into the pole supporting the crash barrier. His injuries, according to the police, were so severe that he died at the scene of the accident. Another bad motorbike accident took place in lower Franconia in the Main and Spessart area. A 56 year old driver and his girlfriend riding pillion were killed as their machine for unknown reasons skidded into an oncoming caravan. Five young people between the ages of 10 and 26 had been killed in the morning while overtaking a car. Their car was torn to pieces when it crashed into a bridge railing. All the occupants were killed instantly.  </field></doc></add>