<add><doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Committee investigating party donations begins work </field>
<field name="text"> The parliamentary committee investigating the party donation scandal will begin work today to discover whether decisions by former chancellor Helmut Kohl's government were for sale. The committee chairman, Volker Neumann (SPD), expects that it will take until the end of February before they have looked through all the documents and interviewed the first witnesses. Neumann came out in favor of rescinding former Chancellor Kohl's immunity should the public prosecutor's office in Bonn find probable cause for suspicion in connection with slush fund accounts during his tenure as head of the CDU. The task of the committee is to determine "to what extent contributions were made to members of the former governing coalition, i.e., CDU, CSU and FDP, and did these influence political decisions, including the sale of tanks to Saudi Arabia and the privatization of the East German oil refinery Leuna?" According to statements by Neumann, the committee will also investigate the two new accusations made against the CDU/CSU.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Bundestag votes on federal budget for 2000 </field>
<field name="text">The Bundestag voted today on the results of the mediation committee's deliberations. The committee decided yesterday evening to cut the budget by only 27.5 billion DM instead of the 30 billion DM originally proposed. Finance Minister Hans Eichel was able to push through most of his savings package. The Bundestag passed the compromise made in the mediation committee. Life insurance benefits will continue to be tax-exempt; in two weeks the child benefit will increase to 270 DM or, alternately, the child tax allowance will increase to 10,000 DM. The housing benefit for low-income households will increase in 2001 an average of 83 DM and more people will qualify. On the other hand, the homeowner's bonus will be eliminated for homeowners with high incomes. Increases in civil servant salaries, however, remain open. With the watered-down health care reform, the budgets of the individual sectors have been maintained, some were even increased. However, certain operations can now only be performed on an out-patient basis.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">US victims' attorney still has questions about compensation for forced laborers </field>
<field name="text">The attorney for the US victims still has many questions about the compensation of former NS forced laborers. In particular, the question of who is to receive how much of the 10 billion DM settlement must be clarified.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">SPD states want to contribute to forced laborer settlement </field>
<field name="text">Those states led by SPD governments want to participate in the compensation of forced laborers. This was announced by the State Premier of Rhineland Palatinate, Kurt Beck, before a meeting of the state premiers with Chancellor Schroeder.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Former Chancellor Kohl reiterates incorruptibility </field>
<field name="text">Former Chancellor Helmut Kohl reiterated that he was never bribable. Kohl said in an interview with ZDF television that he had never accepted money for himself, no money had gone into his personal accounts. The former chancellor admitted again, however, that he had worked with secret accounts as the head of the party.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Accusations against Rau in the WestLB scandal dismissed by public prosecutor </field>
<field name="text">The Public Prosecutor's Office has dismissed the accusations against German President Johannes Rau in connection with the scandal surrounding the Westdeutsche Landesbank (WestLB). A spokesperson stated that WestLB's contribution toward the celebration of Rau's 65th birthday had already been examined and no grounds were found to suspect illegal activity.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Escaped convict recaptured </field>
<field name="text">The convict who had escaped from a prison in Mecklenburg-West Pomerania was captured this morning. The convicted murderer slipped away from 2 guards while on day parole to visit his parents.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Regional Court in Dortmund sentences youths to long prison terms </field>
<field name="text">The Regional Court sentenced four youths to prison terms of between 4 1/2 and 7 1/2 years. The youths had confessed that they had kicked a homeless man to death out of frustration and anger.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">Tire manufacturer Michelin to participate in Formula 1 again in 2001 </field>
<field name="text">The tire manufacturer Michelin is returning to Formula 1 racing in the 2001 season. The French firm will participate in the Grand Prix as the partner of the Williams-BMW racing team.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-16</field><field name="title">From the editor's desk </field>
<field name="text">Wednesday's edition of GermNews/DE-News could not be published yesterday due to technical difficulties. We thank you for your understanding.  </field></doc></add>