<add><doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Explosion during Christmas service at Frankfurt church </field>
<field name="text">An explosion during the Christmas service at a Lutheran church in the Sindlingen neighbourhood of Frankfurt was most likely tied to a woman's suicide.  Police said it was a woman of about 30 years of age, but her exact identity was still unknown, and they could give no indication of her nationality or motive, although a terrorist connection has been ruled out. It is suspected that the woman was disturbed and wanted to die a spectacular death. This morning, investigators instituted a public search and asked for the public's help; they published a photo of the woman. According to police, she detonated two grenades at her seat in the third row from the back, blowing off her lower body, killing three others, and injuring several others. Most of the injured could be treated on site; ten were taken to nearby hospitals, some seriously injured. A 12-year-old girl, a man, and a woman remain in critical condition.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Engelhardt against security measures in churches </field>
<field name="text">Federal President Herzog reacted to the explosion with sadness and horror. The chairman of the Lutheran Church in Germany, Engelhardt, meanwhile rejects special security measures for churches. On Deutschlandradio Berlin this evening, he said that churches and church services must remain open for everyone seeking entry.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Bishop Lehmann calls for reconciliation in his Christmas sermon </field>
<field name="text">The chairman of the German Conference of Bishops, Lehmann, has called in his Christmas sermon for reconciliation. The bishop, from Mainz, said that there are not only war and terror in the world, but also - thank God - frequent signs of reconciliation. Among such signs, Lehmann counts the German-Czech Declaration, and compromises in the European Union. Bishop Lehmann calls for reconciliation in Germany between rich and poor, East and West, and unions and management. He said that Christmas was not supposed to lull the world into peace for a few hours and to hide oppositions, only to have it all resume after Christmas; genuine reconciliation required a genuine will to work together.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Diepgen favours selling state's assets </field>
<field name="text">Berlin's Mayor Diepgen has spoken out in favour of the short-term sale of parts of the state's assets. A member of the CDU, he said in a conversation with the news agency ddp that the move would represent sound financial and economic policy. He added that, regardless of the volume of this sale, the capital would have to shape its long-term budget so that it would balance out even without such additional income; the long-term goal must be the consolidation of the budget.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Wissmann wants to step up fight against crime in trade </field>
<field name="text">Federal Transportation Minister Wissmann wants to step up the fight against crime in the international goods trade. The CDU politician said today in Bonn that the task was Europe-wide in scope, in that the theft of goods, and illegal transactions harmed the development of trade relations. His main concern was customs and insurance fraud, which he said could seriously threaten the strengthening of the European market.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-25</field><field name="title">Break-out attempt at Heidelberg prison </field>
<field name="text">An attempt to break out of a prison in Heidelberg today was foiled. One guard was seriously injured when the escaping prisoner struck him down from behind. Officials think the attempt was carefully planned in advance. At almost the same time as the above attack was happening, a rope was thrown over the prison wall from outside. Accomplices were seen on the wall. The would-be escapee, a 25-year-old man awaiting trial, was overwhelmed by other guards. His accomplices fled.  </field></doc></add>