<add><doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Evacuation of check-in area at Rhein-Main Airport </field>
<field name="text">Due to heavy smoke, a check-in area at Rhein-Main Airport in Frankfurt had to be evacuated last night. According to the police, the smoke was probably caused by a smoldering fire in the air conditioning system. One woman had to be taken to the hospital for smoke inhalation. 100 firefighters and several fire engines answered the emergency call.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Herzog begins official visit to Japan </field>
<field name="text">Roman Herzog began the official part of his six-day visit to Japan. Emperor Akihito greeted him the Japanese government's visitors' quarters. Speaking after accepting an honorary PhD from Waseda University in Tokyo, Herzog called on Japan and Germany to face the challenges of the 21st century. He said that both countries had to accept an increased economic and political responsibility. The past decades' endeavors to reach a consensus between Germany and Japan should not be abandoned easily.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">New round of tax talks possible </field>
<field name="text">The SPD and the federal government intend to resume discussions about the tax reform. After his Easter vacation, Chancellor Kohl said that he would participate in an extended round table discussion if the SPD insisted on it, but the details of the tax reform could only be worked out in the joint committee. Finance minister Waigel expressed a similar opinion. The head of the SPD, Oskar Lafontaine, said the next tax summit could only lead to an agreement if the government reconsidered its position regarding several issues. The SPD approved Kohl's statement in principle. Lafontaine announced that a date would be agreed on within the next few days. He also emphasized that the SPD would only decide after the new tax summit whether to join the tax debates for good.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">SPD board meets in Bonn </field>
<field name="text">For the tax reform, the SPD demands an increase not only of the base tax-free allowance but also of child benefits. After a meeting of the board, SPD leader Lafontained said one should consider an additional ten to 30 marks a month. He also called on Chancellor Kohl again to state explicitly whether the financial framework of the tax reform according to the coalition's plan was to be taken seriously. Public budgets could not cope with the planned additional deficit of over 50 bio. marks. Lafontaine confirmed plans to present his own design for a tax reform but said that he wanted to wait until the tax estimates in May. He also said that the SPD sees no reason to name its candidate for Chancellor ahead of time and that this was a unanimous decision by the board. Chancellor Kohl's announcement to run for office again did not change the situation. According to Lafontaine, the Social Democrats welcomed Kohl's decision because now he would have to personally justify his policies to the voters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Ruettger warns of increasing dangers of infectious diseases </field>
<field name="text">On the occasion of World Health Day, Federal Minister of Reasearch Ruettgers warned of an increasing danger of infectious deseases. In a newspaper interview, Ruettgers said that there is a multitude of new infectious deseases. The question whether the mad cow desease (BSE) is transmittable to humans is of paramount importance. According to the minister, more and more germs become resistant against commonly used antibiotics.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Reduction of unemployment rate by the year 2000 impossible </field>
<field name="text">Employers and the German Employees' Union [Deutsche Angestellten Gewerkschaft - DAG] doubt that the unemployment rate could be cut in half by the year 2000. One day before the employment summit of the German Unions' Association [Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund - DGB], DAG president Issen said that this goal was out of reach. The National Organization of German Employers' Associations made similar statements. At the two-day employment summit attendees want to start further efforts to reduce the record unemployment. Among others, Federal Employment Minister Bluem, SPD leader Lafontaine and Employers President Hundt will attend the congress.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Spring upswing in employment market </field>
<field name="text">The usual spring upswing in the employment market has started. However, the unemployment rate is still at a record high. The German Unions' Association stated that only seasonal reasons were responsible for an estimated reduction in unemployment between 150,000 and 200,000, resulting in 4.5 million unemployed. This fact is not to be interpreted as a new trend on the employment market. There have never been this many people registered unemployed in March of any year. The Federal Labor Office will announce official figures tomorrow.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">DAG and Lufthansa take up wage negotiations again </field>
<field name="text">The German Employees' Union and Lufthansa took up wage negotiations again after disputes lasting several months. At the discussions in Seeheim, Hesse, it is to be examined whether the contract can be accepted that Lufthansa and the OeTV already had agreed on last October. A major critical issue for the DAG is the contract's 27-month validity. Both unions demand a special termination right and intend to push through an improved profit-sharing plan for the company's employees.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Trial against two skinheads begins in Potsdam </field>
<field name="text">The trial against two skinheads began at the Potsdam district court this morning. The public prosecutor's office accuses the defendants of attempted murder and grievous bodily harm. The two men supposedly beat up two Italian construction workers in Trebbin, Brandenburg, last December. The verdict is expected by the end of this month.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Iran announces a trial against 24 German companies </field>
<field name="text">The Irani judiciary officially announced the start of a trial against 24 German companies three days before pronouncement of a verdict in the 'Mykonos-Trial' in Berlin. According to the official news agency IRNA, Tehran had definite evidence that these companies had supplied materials to Iraq in the first Gulf war and also had incriminating evidence regarding some German politicians.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Internet to be better utilized by businesses </field>
<field name="text">In talks starting today, representatives of the governments and businesses of the seven most influential industrialized nations examine how the Internet can be better utilized by businesses. In Germany, medium-sized businesses are to be particularly encouraged to handle their business communications through electronic data transfer. Until now, only three percent of this target group is connected to the Internet. Federal Minster of Economics Rexrodt announced a national initiative named 'Electronic Commerce' to change this situation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Author Stefan Hermlin dies </field>
<field name="text">The author Stefan Hermlin is dead. He died shortly before his eighty-second birthday last night in Berlin, according to the Wagenbach publishing house. Born in Chemnitz, Hermlin's writing was considered a showpiece of socialist literature because of his communist position and his commitment to the WWII resistance movement. He was granted the GDR national award several times. At the same time Hermlin supported the cause of the vicitims of prosecution. Among other things, he protested Wolf Biermann's forced expatriation in 1976. Among his most renowned works are 'Abendlicht' and 'Bestimmungsorte'.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-07</field><field name="title">Beach at Cuxhaven polluted by oil lumps </field>
<field name="text">The beach at Cuxhaven is covered with oil lumps over a distance of 16 km. According to Lower Saxony's Environment Ministry it probably originates from heavy oil that ships drained into the sea. A pollution of large areas is not feared. The spa authorities have begun to clean the beach.  </field></doc></add>