<add><doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Thierse New President of the Bundestag </field>
<field name="text">Wolfgang Thierse (SPD) is the first Eastern-German politician as president of the German Bundestag (lower house of parliament). He was elected with 512 votes of 666 parliamentarians being present. Afterwards the deputies were elected. The Union had tried to prevent the election of the PDS-politician Petra Bless as vice president of the Bundestag with a request. But with the new majority situation this did not happen, because most parliamentarians of the SPD, the Greens and the PDS decided against this. Also the FDP did not support the request of its former coalition partner CDU/CSU. Thus each faction only had the chance to bring through one candidate. After the nomination of Rudolf Seiters, the CSU-candidate Geiger had no chance anymore. Finally, the PDS-candidate Bless won the close voting against Geiger. Bless got 355 votes, Geiger 285 and 19 MPs refrained from voting. Before that, the SPD-politician Fuchs, the CDU-politician Seiters, the candidate of Buendnis90/The Greens, Vollmer, and the nominee of the FDP, Solms, had been elected as vice presidents.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Kohl Awarded The Grand-Cross Of The Federal Order Of Merit </field>
<field name="text">Today, the parting Chancellor Kohl received a special honour. The German President, Herzog, awarded him the second highest order of the Federal Republic for his merits on Germany and Europe, the Grand-Cross of the Federal Order of Merit with Laurel Wreath. Germanys first Chancellor, Adenauer, was the only one being awarded this version of the order before Kohl.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Tax Reform With Two Stages </field>
<field name="text">According to plans of the new government, the tax reform in the next three years shall be arranged with two courses of legislation. In December, only the child benefit shall be increased. Until the middle of March, the second stage with the cutback of tax deductions shall come into retrospective effect by law.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Employers Criticise Plans For Healthcare System Reform </field>
<field name="text">The German Employers' Associations criticise the plans of SPD and Greens to reform the healthcare system. According to their calculations, these plans will bring additional costs of 4.7 billion DEM for the members of the health insurance.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Struck: Industries Interests Will Be Considered </field>
<field name="text">The SPD-faction in the Bundestag will take the criticism of the industry concerning the red-green coalition treaty into account. The new SPD-faction leader, Struck, said today on the radio, that several reflections, especially of the middle class, will be considered in the future legislation. Struck emphasised, that the financial situation prevents some desirable changes.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Illegal Storage Of German Nuclear Waste In France </field>
<field name="text">At the moment, more than 3,000 tons of nuclear waste from Germany are illegally stored in France. According to reports of correspondents, this nuclear waste had been reconditioned in the facility of La Hague. Referring to governmental circles in Paris, only two transports of nuclear waste with all together 84 barrels had returned to Germany since 1995. But the French Atomic Law specifies, that nuclear waste must not be stored longer than technically necessary. According to the reports, up to 250 tons of used nuclear fuel rods from German nuclear power stations are reconditioned in La Hague per year.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">German State Sells "Tank- und Rast-AG" </field>
<field name="text">The sale of the state-owned "Tank- und Rast-AG" is nearly done. According to the Federal Ministry of Transportation this evening in Bonn, a contract had been paraphed already last Thursday between the bidder-group, the Allianz trust and the Ministries of Finance and Transportation. The estimated price is 1.25 billion DEM plus the acceptance of debts of about 600 million DEM. The "Tank- und Rast-AG" owns 294 petrol stations, 326 restaurants and 56 motels.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Taking of Hostages In A Subway Station In Berlin </field>
<field name="text">A 3-year-old boy, taken as hostage in the subway station "Cottbusser Tor" in Berlin-Kreuzberg, became free after 6 hours. According to the police the boy was only slightly injured and the criminal had been arrested.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Train Crashed Into Overhead System </field>
<field name="text">The German Rail announced today, that an Intercity-Express crashed. It damaged the overhead system between Augsburg and Donauwoerth on a length of 3 kilometres. In this accident, several electricity posts were heavily damaged. The value of the damaged property is about 100,000 DEM. The railway traffic was delayed for 2.5 hours.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-26</field><field name="title">Autumn Storms Cease </field>
<field name="text">The stormy low-pressure area "Winnie" has lost its power last night. Until this morning, no greater damages in bigger German cities became known. Yesterday in Hamburg, the water-mark of the Elbe was about 2.5 metres above the average high-water mark. Near the river banks, the fire brigade had to pull several parked cars out of the water.  </field></doc></add>