<add><doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">First German-French summit after elections </field>
<field name="text">To kick off the first German-Grench summit following Germany's recent election, Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder greeted French President Jacques Chirac at Berlin's Tegel Airport.  After the welcoming ceremonies, Schroeder and Chirac met privately.  Schroeder explained afterward that a reduction of Germany's net payments to the European Union was discussed. Paris supported Bonn's wish for more justice, though a mutual agreement on method had not yet been reached.  All 15 EU members must agree to a new system of contribution.  Both politicians were expected in Potsdam that evening for a reception with military honors. Both governments want to reach an understanding on important EU plans during this summit.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">SPD against value-added tax hike </field>
<field name="text">SPD leadership spoke out against a hike on the value-added tax.  After a meeting of the Praesidium, Party chief and Federal Finance Minister Oscar Lafontaine said that such a step is out of the question, given the current economic situation. A hike on the excise tax was brought up originally by North Rhine-Westphalia's State Premier Clement.  There was no word from the chancery in Dusseldorf that Clement intended to push the issue.  The premier simply expressed consideration for European tax accords.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">Stoiber criticizes plans for European financial balance </field>
<field name="text">Bavarian Minister President Stoiber accused the federal government of scrapping national interests. Plans in the Chancellor's office for a European financial compensation scheme for the coordination of tax, employment and wage policy in the EU would mean more German payments to Brussels, Stoiber said to Bild newspaper.  All participants in the plan would have to stand on their own against keener competition in the 11 countries of the European Currency Union.  States that provide too high of wages and social standards should take responsibility for it themselves, stated the CSU politician. A compensation scheme in Europe benefitting other EU states would not be accepted by the German people.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">Hostage drama in Munich ends without bloodshed </field>
<field name="text">A hostage drama in a Munich pharmacy ended without casualty.  Two hostage-takers set both of their last hostages free unharmed, then turned themselves in.  Coming out of the store with hands raised, an operation official ordered them to their knees.  Police then apprehended the two after shoving them to the floor.  In the course of the exhausting ordeal, which lasted into the night, the armed men gradually released all four store clerks.  The women have been treated for shock, but are otherwise unharmed.  An attorney and a psychologist talked the masked men into surrendering by cell phone, after their robbery attempt this morning has gone awry.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">New extorsion against Nestle </field>
<field name="text">The grocery conglomerate Nestle is again being extorted.  According to a company spokesperson, a group known as "Fighting Group Robin Food" has threatened to poison 5 of the company's products in Hesse's EDEKA Supermarkets.  In an extorsion letter, published by the AFP news agency, the group threatened to poison Nestle's products weekly, until their demands are met.  The group based its threats on the company selling genetically altered products.  No monetary demands were made in the letter.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">Salim's extradition granted </field>
<field name="text">The Higher Regional Court of Munich declared the extradition of Mahmud Salim, the alleged confidant of terrorist leader Bin Laden, allowable. Salim is believed to be the finance head of Laden's organization.  Salim remains in protective custody.  The decison to actually extradite Salim now rests with the federal government.  The US petitioned German agencies for Salim's extradition in October.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">Referendum for Buss- und Bettag fails </field>
<field name="text">The referendum to reinstate Buss- und Bettag in Rhineland-Palatinate failed.  Only 7% of voters voted to reinstate the work-free holiday, short of the 20% needed to pass the referendum.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-11-30</field><field name="title">Soccer: Kaiserslautern beats Schalke </field>
<field name="text">In Sunday's game, Kaiserslautern beat Schalke by a score of 4:1. Kaiserslautern is now 3rd in the standings.  </field></doc></add>