<add><doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Massive protests against cuts in coal subsidies </field>
<field name="text">Tens of thousands of miners in the state of Saarland and the Ruhr Area have demonstrated against the planned cuts to coal subsidies before tomorrow's coal mining meeting in the Chancellor's Office. Several thousand protesters are still blocking the party centers of the CDU and FDP in Bonn. The government plans to cut the coal subsidies from yearly nine million DM to 3.8 million by the year 2005.  "It is not the ones who shout the loudest who get the most money", CDU secretary-general Peter Hintze reacted to the miners' protest in Bonn. He said that the State Premiers of Saarland and North Rhine-Westphalia, Oskar Lafontaine and Johannes Rau, had driven the miners out into the streets with their irresponsible expressions of opinion. Guido Westerwelle, secretary-general of the FDP, expressed his sympathy for livelihood concerns of the miners but said that the misguided state policy of the SPD, having neglected urgent modernizations in the mining areas, is to be blamed. Westerwelle stated that the offer for 3.8 million Mark subsidies by the year 2005 is the limit of what the government would be able to justify.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Lafontaine demands new plans to fight unemployment </field>
<field name="text">Oskar Lafontaine, the chairman of the SPD, has called on the government to present new concepts for fighting unemployment. Otherwise there would be no further negotiations on the tax reform, Lafontaine stated after an SPD executive board session in Berlin. In addition, he appealed once more to the government to reconsider its plans regarding the cutting of the coal subsidies.  In Munich, Federal Finance Minister Waigel presented the opinion that an agreement with the Social Democrats on the tax reform would be possible before Easter. According to him, the government will present a comprehensive plan next week. Then the SPD would have to decide between co-operation and confrontation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Seehofer establishes higher deductibles </field>
<field name="text">Ignoring the criticism of doctors and health insurance organizations, the government coalition in Bonn has apparently settled its health reform dispute. In addition to CDU social politicians, the FDP also expressed its consent to Federal Minister Seehofer's plan for raising deductibles on medications and other medical services. The chairman of the health committee of the Bundestag, Thomae (sp?), said on Deutschlandradio Berlin that the purpose of the measures was to increase the individual responsibility of the insured. At a board meeting in Munich, the CSU approved Seehofer's plans. Afterwards, the minister said that the new deductible plan would result in a lowering of costs and that it called for raising deductibles for medications and hospitalizations by mid- 1997.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">BSE cow Cindy not born in Germany </field>
<field name="text">According to the Federal Ministry of Agriculture, Cindy, the cow that died of bovine brain disease BSE in Germany at the end of last year, had been imported directly from the UK. DNA analyses by two scientific institutes had proved that, Secretary of State Feiter (sp?) said in Bonn. With a 95 per cent probability the cow, which in Germany had been called Cindy, was a British import cow called Scottish Queen.  Feiter said that thus there is no single case of cattle born here contracting BSE. The German housewife could presume that buying German meat in Germany meant no BSE risk, Feiter added.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Luebeck: Fire started from outside? </field>
<field name="text">According to an expert opinion by the Frankfurt fire expert Achilles (sp?), the fire in an asylum shelter in Luebeck might possibly have been set from the outside. The fire on January 18, 1996 killed ten people. The Lebanese citizen Safwan Eid is accused of setting fire as a revenge against a fellow resident.  Achilles disagrees with the public prosecutor's theory that the fire had started on the second floor of the shelter. The worst damage was located in a frontal building addition, and the three so-called through-burns could have originated from liquid fuels. Achilles also showed photos in which flames are visible, both in the addition and on the second floor. The drawback is that there is no evidence on the time of shooting of the pictures. Experts from the state (LKA) and the federal criminal bureaus (BKA) do support the public prosecution's theory that the fire was set on the second floor.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Construction industry: 7000 companies threatened by bankruptcy </field>
<field name="text">The construction industry is threatened by bankruptcy of about 7000 companies this year. About 8000 construction workers demonstrated in Berlin against cut-rate wages, wage contract violations, and for the reinstatement of bad weather pay.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Saftig new coach in Mainz </field>
<field name="text">Reinhard Saftig is the new coach of second-league team Mainz 05. The 45-year-old soccer teacher today signed a contract with FSV Mainz 05 until June 30, 1998. Saftig is the successor of Wolfgang Frank, who gave up his post surprisingly on February 2. Saftig had been without a contract after coaching in Istanbul until May 1995. He has worked in the Bundesliga with first-league teams Bochum, Leverkusen, Hanover, Dortmund and FC Bayern.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-03-10</field><field name="title">Stock Market </field>
<field name="text">Some exchange rates:   Some Indices:   (errors and omissions excepted)  </field></doc></add>