<add><doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Baden-Wurttemberg supplementary budget dispute </field>
<field name="text">The opposition parties in Baden-Wurttemberg's Landtag have strongly criticized the financial policies of the governing CDU/FDP coalition. Upon presentation of the second supplementary budget for the current budget year, they approved of the strict limitation of new borrowing, but said that savings were going to be realized in the wrong place - on the backs of families. Finance Minister Mayer-Vorfelder defended the budget, saying it would equal out a shortfall of 1.1 billion marks in state finances, which was caused primarily by tax losses. Cuts to investments and materials are expected to yield 800 million marks. Savings on personnel are estimated at 130 million Marks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Public Services and Transport Union boss presents 6-point plan </field>
<field name="text">The leader of the Union of r Public Services and Transport, May, has presented a 6-point plan at the union's national convention. The document outlines the course the union will take in the next four years. May calls for a new tax system, economic and employment programmes, additional training positions, and guaranteed continued education for all workers. May stated that unions should work together in future to assure that work will be fairly distributed - to which end work-weeks should continue to be shortened, otherwise the goal of full employment for everyone could never be achieved. He continued that the help of those who already have jobs was essential. However May did caution that present wage levels could not be maintained in a future of fewer work hours.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Criticism after workers' protests </field>
<field name="text">Following mass protests against cuts to sick pay, employer representatives and the CDU/CSU have criticized both employers and unions for their behaviour. The president of the Baden-Wurttemberg Employers' Association for the metals industry, Hundt, again rejected the protest action as illegal. At the same time he criticized the lack of solidarity among employers. The vice-chairman of the CDU-workers group, Ahrens, warned of an escalation in the dispute, saying that the employers had started down the road of confrontation, but the unions had readily followed. He urged both sides to begin negotiations.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">The banking industry: wage negotiations </field>
<field name="text">Negotiations on sick pay in the banking industry have been put on hold, with nothing to show so far. According to the Union for Trade, Banking, and Insurance, the employee side broke off the talks because employers were not willing to discuss the possibility of full sick pay.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Agreement on locally held former-East German debts </field>
<field name="text">After months of negotiations, federal, state, and county governments have agreed that the old debts of East German counties will be taken over by a special fund. "Old" debt refers to monies which the former East German government made available to the counties for such things as building schools and sporting facilities. This agreement means that the counties are completely absolved of financial responsibility for the debts. The secretary of the Chancellor's Office, Bohl, after talks with East German politicians and county groups, gave the total amount of debt in question as 8.4 billion marks, requiring 630 million marks a year to pay down. The German government is to pay half, the states together the other half. All participants called today's agreement a breakthrough. However, the cabinets of the federal government and the eastern states must still approve the proposal, and the Bundestag and Bundesrat must pass it as a law.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Lubeck arson trial: witness testimony </field>
<field name="text">In the trial concerning a case of arson at a residence for refugees, witnesses have testified that they saw three young men at the scene after the fire broke out. The two men told the regional court in Lubeck that there was a beige Wartburg parked in front of the house, with three young men standing in front of it. The witnesses said that flames could be seen on the second floor of the building. The public prosecution is accusing the 20-year-old defendant, Eid, of starting the fire on the second floor last January. An expert for the defence has identified the entrance to the building as the place where the fire started.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Deutscher Dom cathedral reopened </field>
<field name="text">Bundestag President Sussmuth has reopened the Deutscher Dom cathedral in Berlin after more than twelve years of reconstruction work. The Bundestag's permanent historical exhibition "Questions of German History" now has a new home there. It had been set up in the Reichstag building until two years ago, when it was displaced by renovations to make the building the new seat of the Bundestag  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">German Unity Day tomorrow: monument unveiled in Munich </field>
<field name="text">As a prelude to official celebrations of German Unity Day, Bavarian Premier Stoiber has called on Germans in the East and the West to talk to each other; that is the only way toward inner unity, Stoiber said while unveiling a new monument. The monument consists of an original piece of the Berlin Wall. Stoiber said that it had been intentionally placed within sight of the American consulate, and added "We are well aware how much we owe the United States for the role it played in the after-war period and in the process of reunification". Politicians from all parties had earlier used the occasion of tomorrow's anniversary of German reunification to call for the completion of that unity. Federal celebrations on the national holiday are held in the state which is chairing the Bundesrat; this year that is Bavaria.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-02</field><field name="title">Kohl calls on Germans to help shape the future </field>
<field name="text">On the occasion of the anniversary of German reunification, federal Chancellor Kohl has called on all Germans to help shape the future in peace and freedom. In a speech which will be broadcast tomorrow, Kohl said "We have every reason to be confident on our journey into the world of tomorrow". The Chancellor called reunification one of the very great moments in German history. He thanked the citizens of former East Germany who protested in favour of freedom in the fall of 1989. At the same time, Kohl reminded Germans that building up the eastern states would still take several years and require great efforts. He said that everyone was aware that there was still much to do in the united Germany.  </field></doc></add>