<add><doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">No work group for the financial adjustment reform </field>
<field name="text">In a fight for a reform of the financial adjustment of the states the positions are hardening. At a conference of the Finance Ministers of the 16 states in Bonn, Bavaria and Baden-Wuerttemberg did not succeed with their request to mobilize a working team. The conflict about equalization payments will now possibly be taken to the Federal Constitutional Court. Bavaria and Baden-Wuerttemberg threatened again with a suit in Karlsruhe in case no progress would be made with the discussions by summer break. Hesse also considers a financial adjustment reform necessary. State Premier Eichel told the "Deutschlandfunk" radio station that the stabilisation of the public budgets has to be accomplished before a reform can take place.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Kohl arrived in Riga for 2nd meeting of Baltic Sea Council </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Kohl arrived in the evening for the second meeting of the Baltic Sea Council in Riga. The expansion of economic cooperation with neighbouring states will be the main topic of the meeting with State Premiers from ten European countries. Another topic is the fight against organized crime. The last time the Council met was in 1996 on the Swedish island of Gotland.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Kanther and Schoenbohm introducing security concept for Berlin </field>
<field name="text">The Minister of the Interior Kanther and the Senator of the Interior Schoenbohm introduced a new security concept for the German capital. The two CDU politicians explained that within the scope of the statewide initiative called "Aktion Sicherheitsnetz" (Campaign "Security Network") a closer collaboration of security workers, a wider presence of police force and a persistent interference against minor crime are the important points. The campaign is also aimed at aggressive pan-handling, the so-called "hobo scene", and graffiti sprayers. Kanther stressed that nothing should be tolerated which could lead to crime.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Pope letter against proof of counseling for abortion </field>
<field name="text">The yet unpublished letter of the Pope regarding counseling for pregnant women has been issued to the German bishops. According to the Suedwestfunk the eight-page long letter is published in a fraternal tone, and avoids terms like "direction", "instruction", or "request". John Paul II is asking the bishops to reconsider the current rules, and explains where he sees weaknesses at the advisory centres of the Catholic Church. According to information provided, the Pope wants to prevent the Church from issuing a proof of counseling for unpunished abortions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Coalition apparently considers a gene card-index for sex offenders </field>
<field name="text">The coalition is apparently considering a central gene card-index for sex offenders. Politicians of the Union and the FDP told the magazine "BILD" that it would make sense to record and archive the so-called genetic fingerprints of sex offenders.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Tennis: Huber and Kiefer in third round of Australian Open </field>
<field name="text">Anke Huber and Nikola Kiefer reached the third round of the Australian Open Tennis Championship in Melbourne. Anke Huber beat the US American Anne Miller, and Nikola Kiefer defeated David Weaton. Barbara Rittner and Oliver Gross dropped out of the tournament.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-22</field><field name="title">Exchange rates and stock markets </field>
<field name="text"> Selected currencies:   Selected indices:    (Errors and omissions excepted)  </field></doc></add>