<add><doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Withdrawal from atomic energy </field>
<field name="text">There is some dispute in the  Green Party as to how long nuclear power stations should remain active. Juergen Trittin, Minister of the Environment, originally suggested that the time period should be limited thirty years. This has however been criticised by other party members. The leader of the Green Parliamentary Group, Kerstin Mueller, said that she cannot accept thirty years as a starting point in negotiations with atomic concerns. The leaders of state subgroups will be meeting in Berlin on Monday to try and find a unified approach to the problem. The Greens in the Saarland have demanded that the Party should demand nothing less than a limit of 25 years per atomic plant.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Schroeder calls for unity in the SPD </field>
<field name="text">In the run-up to the SPD state party conference, the leader of the SPD, Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder, has called for unity among his party colleagues. He said at a regional party conference for the SPD North German state factions in Hamburg that the last few days had shown that the SPD were able to make and act on decisions and that the had understood that they could be unified and successful. Chancellor Schroeder furthermore defended the strict austerity measures undertaken by his government. He said that the SPD's policy to state debts was to distribute from the bottom to the top, he emphasised to the approximately 1500 delegates attending the conference. He also elaborated that only the rich were interested in having a poor country. According to him, the social security system needs to be restructured. The decisive point would be financial security in old age. Schroeder again stressed his willingness to negotiate with the CDU/CSU as regards pension reforms. However, he warned the CDU/CSU against using these negotiations as a tactic for winning voters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">CDU donation scandal </field>
<field name="text">There is ever increasing pressure within CDU party ranks on Helmut Kohl, the Honorary Chairman of the party. Former managers of the party, Heiner Geissler and Walther Leisler Kiep have made public statements saying that Kohl, head of the CDU for many years, was aware of exact details regarding finances and donations to the party. Geissler, Kohl's former general secretary, said to the newspaper "Bild am Sonntag" that he did not believe that there were any larger financial transactions of which Kohl did not know about. Kiep, the former treasurer of the CDU, said he would be able to talk for hours when providing proof that the Kohl had known about, and been very interested in, the source of much smaller donations than that of a million marks. He said that the only thing stopping him providing concrete details is that he had given the State Attorney's Department in Augsburg his word that he would preserve confidentiality. Kohl, who has denied all allegations of irregularities, has confirmed that Kiep had reported to him on matters regarding CDU finances while Kiep was party treasurer, but that he, Kohl, denied that at any time had had any knowledge of the donation of a million marks from the arms dealer Schreiber. Volker Ruehe, acting leader of the CDU, said at an election campaign event in Kiel that he had called for this matter to be cleared up before Christmas. He continued that the CDU has to investigate and clear up the matter internally and that this should be given the highest priority.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Abortion counselling </field>
<field name="text">Despite the Pope forbidding Catholic Church participation in state abortion counselling, Bishop Lehmann, Chairman of the German Bishops Association, is still investigating other ways for the Catholic Church to continue their counselling within the state system. He said in a newspaper interview that he envisaged that a certified statement from those seeking an abortion that they had participated in counselling could be accepted instead of the prescribed certification. However, paragraph 218 of the law for abortion would have to be correspondingly amended. Christine Bergmann, State Minister for the Family Affairs, has however said that this would not be acceptable as the law is very clear in its formulation and that no-one wants to change the law at this stage. She said that the Bishops had excluded the Catholic Church from state abortion counselling when they had taken the decision that the Church would no longer issue the necessary certificates.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Criticism of the government </field>
<field name="text">The two largest employers' association of the SPD have accused the government of dismantling the social state. The spokesman for employers' associations and for women in the SPD said at a congress in Berlin that the SPD are antagonising their most faithful voters; that they were orientating themselves more towards a free-market policy and that woman, in particular, were disappointed with the Red-Green government.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Mannesmann Board to discuss take-over bid </field>
<field name="text">The Mannesmann Board is discussing the Vodafone take-over bid today in Dusseldorf (Sunday). The British mobile phone concern has offered Mannesmann shareholders Vodafone shares to the sum of 242 billion marks in exchange for their Mannesmann shares. The Mannesmann Board has rejected this offer. Mr. Gent, head of the Vodafone concern said before the meeting that the believed that the Mannesmann board might just agree to the proposal.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Stella musical concern optimistic </field>
<field name="text">The musical concern Stella, which is facing bankruptcy, is more confident that they will be able to surmount their current financial crisis. The Judicial Administrator said at an employers' meeting in Stuttgart that jobs were secure in the short-term.  Mr. Klein, the head of Stella, described the negotiations with new investors as very promising.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Fire in Munich </field>
<field name="text">A day after a serious fire in the Salvatorkeller restaurant the police are sure that the fire had been laid by arsonists. Director, Nagel, head of the C.I.D. responsible, said that the arsonists seemed to have been extremely familiar with the restaurant and had probably even had a key to the building. There are no indications regarding a motive at this point, however. The Salvatorkeller was practically totally destroyed by the fire. It is reported that damage amounts to around twenty million marks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Escape from high-security ward in clinic </field>
<field name="text">A man who is described as violent, escaped from a high-security ward from a clinic in Grafenberg. He already has a jail record for sexual abuse of children and culpable injury. The police have initiated a large-scale search for the man and closed childrens' playgrounds in the area.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-28</field><field name="title">Tennis </field>
<field name="text">Pete Sampras is tennis world champion for the fifth time. He beat the American Andre Agassi in Hannover 6:1, 7:5 und 6:4.  </field></doc></add>