<add><doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Riots during Students' protests in Bonn </field>
<field name="text">At least 9 people have been injured during the riots at a students' mass demonstration. Spokespersons from the police and organisers amongst the students reported that the demonstrations had been deliberately targeted by about 500 members of the autonomous scene. Two rioters were arrested. The students representatives distanced themselves from the rioters, but also critisised the police measures as relatively hard. The mass demonstration was attended by about 30,000 students, who demanded that tuition fees are ruled out as well as more money for the universities and more democracy within university commitees.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Federal education assistance will be increased </field>
<field name="text">The federal and the states governments have decided to increase the federal education assistance, but have not yet reached an agreement on a structural reform. The state premiers and Chancellor Kohl agreed to increase the benefit by 2 % from July next year. At the same time the amount parents can earn before means testing will lead to a reduction of federal education assistance will be raised by 6 %. According to the state premier of Baden-Wuerttemberg, Erwin Teufel, no attempts were made to reach a compromise on a structural reform, because the states couldn't even reach a compromise among themselves.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Bundesrat: Free sports in television </field>
<field name="text">The state permiers  have agreed that the upper house of parliament, the Bundesrat, should prepare a list of protected sports events by next March. This list will secure live-broadcasting of big sports events on freely accessible television channels and will include events like the Olympic Games and all matches of the German national soccer team.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">OeTV and DAG demand 4.5% </field>
<field name="text">The trade unions for employees in the public sector, OeTV and DAG will demand an increase of 4.5 % in the coming round of negotiations. Primarily the trade unions want to secure employment, the wage increase should just match the inflation rate. The federal Minister of the Interior, Manfred Kanter, called these demands unacceptable.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Federal government forces through the budget of the federal labour office </field>
<field name="text">The federal government has implemented the budget of the federal labour office against the wishes of the agency. The budget for 1998 contains cuts worth DM650 million. The national trade union federation fears that these cuts will lead to a reduction in employment policy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Another manager of the Dresdner Bank resigns </field>
<field name="text">Tax irregularities commited by managers of the Dresdner Bank have lead to a further resignation. The head of the investment operation, Mr. Hoffmann resigned shortly after he had accused himself of tax evasion worth millions of marks. He is the fourth manager of the Dresdner Bank, who has to resign over the affair.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-12-18</field><field name="title">Schwartau blackmailed using rat poison </field>
<field name="text">A second glas of poisoned jam has appeared in connection with the blackmailing of the food manufacturer Schwartau. Police do not exclude that even more glasses have been tampered with. In high doses the poison Warfarin is also dangerous to humans. The blackmailing of Schwartau started at least one week ago.  </field></doc></add>