<add><doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Preliminary official final result of German General Elections </field>
<field name="text">The SPD is the clear winner of the General Elections and its candidate, the State Premier of Lower Saxony, Gerhard Schroeder, will become the new Chancellor. According to the preliminary final result announced by election organisers this morning, the SPD obtained 40.9%. The CDU/CSU finished second with 35.1%, B90/The Greens reached 6.7% and the FDP achieved 6.2%. The fifth party in the Parliament is the PDS with 5.1%. This year, 82.3% of the eligible voters voted.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">SPD wants to start coalition talks with the Greens </field>
<field name="text">According to the future Chancellor Schroeder, the SPD will negotiate already on Friday with the Greens about government coalition. One day after his tremendous victory, Schroeder said that he sees no unbridgeable difficulties. The talks shall begin on Friday. The designated Chancellor mentioned Just Stollmann as one of the Ministers and as Minister of Finance, Gerhard Schroeder was talking of SPD-leader Oskar Lafontaine. By the end of the coalition talks with the Greens it shall be determined, who will do which job in the new government. Schroeder regretted that the Union refused coalition talks so early and reduced the options of the SPD by this.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Schroeder against an increase of gasoline tax </field>
<field name="text">The future Chancellor Schroeder sees only few possibilities for the increase of the gasoline tax, demanded by the Greens. On ZDF, Schroeder said he had defined himself as a "car man". It is very reasonable to increase the ecological aspect of the tax system, but there must not be any sole actions in Europe.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Good chances for Schaeuble to become chairman CDU </field>
<field name="text">For the Union as the loser of the elections the successors are partly clear. The resigning party leader, Helmut Kohl, did not hide his thoughts. He would like to see parliamentary party leader Schaeuble as new chairman. Next week, the CDU will announce proposals for a new team after this election disaster. After Kohl'S announcement of his resignation, parliamentary party leader Schaeuble has the best chances to become also chairman of the CDU. The CDU directorate is still discussing about a team, consisting of Schaeuble and the actual Minister of Defence, Ruehe. Once again, Kohl accepts the whole responsibility for the defeat.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Waigel wants to pass the CSU-chairmanship to Stoiber </field>
<field name="text">In Munich, also CSU-leader Waigel announced his resignation. Bavaria's State Premier, Stoiber, had been very surprised. This evening, Stoiber said to the BR (Bayerischer Rundfunk) that Waigel's decision deserves acknowledgement and respect. There had been no reason for the CSU-leader to resign. Nobody of the party had been prepared for this. Stoiber did not tell any details, if he will be a candidate next year as Waigel's successor. The CSU-parliamentary group in the Bavarian State Assembly denominated Stoiber unanimous for a second term as State Premier. On September 13th, the CSU won the elections and could increase its absolute majority up to 52.9%.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Reactions from abroad on SPD election victory </field>
<field name="text">Foreign Government Leaders congratulated Gerhard Schroeder on his election victory. The British Prime Minister, Tony Blair, said that at the moment the most important EU-countries have governments with the same point of view.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">This week Schroeder will travel to Paris for talks </field>
<field name="text">Already next Wednesday, Schroeder will travel to Paris for talks with French leading politicians. According to a speaker, he will first meet State Premier Chirac and after that a discussion with Prime Minister Jospin is scheduled.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">Final Result of the Regional Elections in Mecklenburg West-Pomerania </field>
<field name="text">Also in the Regional Elections in Mecklenburg West-Pomerania the SPD became the strongest party. According to the preliminary final result the SPD finished with 34.3%, that means 4.8% plus compared to 1994. The CDU lost 7.5% and finished with 30.2%. The PDS increased its share from 22.7% in 1994 up to 24.4%. All other parties did not make it into the parliament, because they had less than 5%. The state assembly in Schwerin looks now like that: SPD - 72 seats CDU - 24 seats PDS - 20 seats The leading candidate of the SPD, Ringstorff, announced negotiations with the PDS and the CDU about a coalition.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">SPD in Mecklenburg West-Pomerania decides talks with CDU and PDS </field>
<field name="text">The state directorate of the SPD in Mecklenburg West-Pomerania unanimous decided talks with the PDS and the CDU. SPD leading candidate, Ringstorff, said in Schwerin that first this week there would be talks with the CDU. The decision for the future coalition partner depends especially on the surroundings for a solid financial policy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">DIHT ready for negotiations about "Alliance for Labour" </field>
<field name="text">The DIHT (Council of German Chambers of Commerce) is ready for a discussion with the SPD about an "alliance for labour". DIHT president Stihl said that negotiations would be very difficult, if the SPD wants to take back reforms of the former government.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">56.4% in Schleswig-Holstein against orthography reform </field>
<field name="text">In Schleswig-Holstein, in the future the pupils will be taught the old orthography again. In a referendum, 56.4% of the electors voted against the enforcement of the orthography reform. Schleswig-Holstein is the only federal state, where the new orthography is not taught. The Minister of Cultural Issues, Boerg, regretted this result. Government leader Simonis announced to talk with her colleagues from the other states, but she does not expect the other State Premiers to take back the orthography reform.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-09-28</field><field name="title">No German edition of the Lewinsky report </field>
<field name="text">There will be no German edition of the Starr-Report, which had been publicly announced. According to the Muenchner Verlag there are 9000 orders for the book, but the printing and all marketing activities had been stopped. The company justified the stop with the exaggerated reporting after the publication of President Clinton's interrogation by the Grand Jury.  </field></doc></add>