<add><doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">US Foreign Minister visits Bonn </field>
<field name="text">This morning US Foreign Minister Christopher met with Chancellor Kohl in Bonn. Talks were mainly about the current situation in Iraq and Mr Kohl's visit to Russian president Yelzin. Mr Christopher supposedly also brought up the subject of Germany's relations with Iran. The US had repeatedly asked Germany to stop their so-called 'critical dialogue' with Iran. Previously, Mr Christopher had conferred with British and French governments in London and Paris.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Mr Stihl for more cuts to social net </field>
<field name="text">Mr Stihl, president of the Council of German Chambers of Commerce (DIHT), pleaded for more cuts to the social net. When interviewed by a newspaper, he asked for the insured person's excess (in case of treatment for illness) to be raised, and also for less (paid) sick-leave. And he wants government to privatise public old-age care insurance.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Commemoration of 50th anniversary of "Speech on hope" </field>
<field name="text">US Foreign Minister Christopher attended the Baden-Wuerttemberg government's celebration of the 50th anniversary of a speech delivered by the then foreign minister, Mr Burns. Mr Burns' speech had set the pace for a new US-policy towards Germany. One and a half years after WWII had come to an end, Mr Burns had pleaded for an economically united Germany, across borders drawn up by the Allies, and also for an independent German government. On 6 September 1946 Mr James F.Burns said in his historical speech at the Stuttgart Opera House, that the people of the United States would support Germany's economic re-building and her re-admission to the community of democratic countries. Mr Burns thus reached out to Germany, who was on her knees, offering peace and friendship. The speech, however, also sent signals to the other Allies: that the Unites States would discontinue the process of setting up and running an allied administration of Germany (as set out in the Potsdam Treaty). Today, 50 years after the event, German and American politicians wished to commemorate this turning-point in the relations between the two countries.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">SPD wants to cut tax-burden for average wage-earner </field>
<field name="text">The average wage-earner should pay less tax, according to the SPD's big tax-reform plans, and millionaires should pay more (surtax) for the re-unification of Germany. According to Mr Scharping, leader of the parliamentary group, the members of parliament had unanimously agreed to the concept.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">No change of direction for Greens party </field>
<field name="text">The Greens are not changing direction, according to Ms Mueller, head of the party in Bonn, when commenting on the elections to their parliamentary group. And she emphasised on radio Deutschlandfunk this morning, spokes-person Mr Fischer's getting less votes than 2 years ago, should not be seen as a way of penalising him; but rather as a reflection of what ordinary voters within the party thought. Ms Mueller, who allegedly is close to the left wing, emphasised that environmental politics were of fundamental importance to her party. Re-building Germany's economy under ecological aspects would also work wonders for Germany as a manufacturing site. Ms Mueller criticised government for not having realised the latter so far.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Schuermann building to be brought up to standard after all </field>
<field name="text">The building in Bonn's government quarter had suffered flood-damage around Christmas 1993, but will be finished all the same. The Federal Ministry for Construction stated, that they had agreed with the Federal Finance Ministry, to bring the building up to standard, and tenders would be published all over the European Union. Initial costs are forecast to be 400 million marks, though they are expected to be covered by damages to be awarded by the courts. And government were also firm about their decision to have German Radio (Deutsche Welle) move into the building.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Mr Waigel raises grants for Federal Labour Office </field>
<field name="text">Federal Finance Minister Waigel raised the grant for the Federal Labour Office (Bundesanstalt fuer Arbeit) by 7 billion marks to 11.3 billion marks. Today Bonn also stated that he would be prepared to earmark an unplanned 5.5 billion marks for unemployment benefit expenses. The reason given was the negative economic development during the last few months.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Round eight of award negotiations in North-Rhine/Westphalia </field>
<field name="text">Today round eight of the award-negotiations in the North-Rhine/Westphalia retail sector started in Essen. Unions are positive the award will be settled, similar to what has already happened in Rhineland-Palatinate, Saarland and Bavaria. It will be based on Bavaria's award, meaning 1.85% more pay, plus 20% penalty payments for work after 18:30 hours on weekdays, or after 14:00 hours on three Saturdays/month.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Arbitration for railways staff begins </field>
<field name="text">This afternoon both parties met at a secret place to begin arbitration for for some 180,000 railways staff. The union wants more pay and bring East Germany's rates up to West Germany's levels. A railways spokes-person said that saving jobs had to be a priority.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Day two of Graf tax-trial </field>
<field name="text">Day two of the Graf tax-trial at the Mannheim Regional Court saw more depositions by Mr Graf's consultant, Mr Eckhardt. Yesterday Mr Graf had stated that the tax authorities had not informed him on time about any initial suspicions they would have had. Messrs Graf and Eckhardt are alleged to have evaded tax to the tune of 20 million marks. According to Mr Eckhardt, Steffi Graf did know that her revenues from advertising would be channelled in order to evade tax. His predecessor, Mr Schmidt, had told him that the whole Graf family had been informed about the tax-saving scheme. He did not know, however, if Mr Schmidt had warned about the inherent dangers of getting found out and taken to court. In 1992 he had learned about the splitting of sponsors' contracts and money transfers.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Opel saves more than 100 million marks by implementing staff's proposals </field>
<field name="text">The company saved some 118 billion marks last year, thanks to staff proposals how to improve things and procedures. They, in turn, paid out about 17 million marks for more than 50,000 proposals. The pay-out is capped at 100,000 marks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">Germans drink less alcohol </field>
<field name="text">Germans drink less and less schnapps, wine and beer. According to the Ministry of Agriculture, consumption is down some 9% compared to what it used to be 4 years ago, whereas per head consumption of alcohol-free drinks went up by more than 10%. Top of the list is coffee (165 litres/year), and next is beer (130 litres/year). And Germans also drink some 100 litres of mineral water, plus the same amount of milk.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-09-06</field><field name="title">This summer's bad weather helps travel industry </field>
<field name="text">Travel agents in Germany would have suffered catastrophic results, according to their federation, if the bad weather had not provided a powerful incentive to travel to far-way places after all. This year the industry would only just break even, whereas the travel agents would actually lose a bit of money.  </field></doc></add>