<add><doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">EU Commission warns parliament against withholding of exoneration </field>
<field name="text">The EU Commission has warned the European Parliament not to withhold the exoneration for the 1996 budget year. The night before the vote in Strasbourg the Commission presented a statement saying that the authority and credibility of the Commission were at a stake. This was especially important because the reform package "Agenda 2000" depended on future important joint decisions. A large number of members of the European Parliament had announced they would not exonerate the Commission because of the latest financial scandals and the criticism by the European Court of Auditors of the Commission's financial management.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">Meeting of coalition parties regarding withdrawal from nuclear energy </field>
<field name="text">In the tug-of-war concerning the withdrawal from nuclear energy SPD faction leader Peter Struck has called for moderation on the part of Buendnis90/Die Gruenen. The coalition contract must not be interpreted in only one way, said Struck in Bonn. Earlier, government spokesman Mr. Heye had stated that the coalition partners would meet on January 13 to remove controversial argument that could hamper the negotiations with the energy industry. The controversy centers on the nuclear waste disposal. Environment Minister Juergen Trittin (B90/G) wants to have a law that nuclear waste must not be reconditioned.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">Bertelsmann reviews company activities during Third Reich era </field>
<field name="text">Media group Bertelsmann wants to have the company's activities during the Nationalsocialist regime reviewed by an independent scientific committee. Thus, the company reacts to statements by Mr. Fischler (sp?), a sociologist from Duesseldorf. He allegedly found out that Bertelsmann had published books containing Nazi propaganda during that period.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">Finance Ministry: eco tax to start April 1999 </field>
<field name="text">The Finance Ministry has clarified that the eco tax would be introduced in April 1999 for sure. Referring to reports about EU objections against details of the reform plans, the ministry stated that Brussels had not at all questioned the introduction of the eco tax. Currently, certain details would be checked by the commission as is customary in these kinds of proceedings. The Commission had not come to any final conclusion about the details. The daily Hamburger Abendblatt had reported that the EU Commission rejected the eco tax because the exemption of 27 industries presented a subsidy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">Wienerwald-founder Jahn dead </field>
<field name="text">Two weeks before his 75th birthday, Friedrich Jahn, the founder of the chain of Wienerwald restaurants that feature mostly chicken dishes on the menu has died. The Austrian died in a Zurich, Switzerland, sanatorium after a long and serious illness. Jahn who was known as the Hendl-Koenig (King of Chickens) had build a chain of 1500 restaurants from just one.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-12-16</field><field name="title">Soccer: Bayern Munich heads on </field>
<field name="text">FC Bayern Munich has secured its top position in the first division. Last night, the Munich team played Moenchengladbach 2-0. Both goals were scored by former Gladbach player Stefan Effenberg. Thus, the FC Bayern Munich is 6 points ahead of Leverkusen. Surprisingly, the 1. FC Kaiserslautern lost tonight's second rescheduled match against MSV Duisburg 1-3.  </field></doc></add>