<add><doc><field name="date">1999-03-25</field><field name="title">Renewed military attack on Yugoslavia </field>
<field name="text">NATO began another wave of attacks against Yugoslavia at nightfall. A US destroyer stationed in the Adriatic as well as other military ships fired numerous cruise missiles. Simultaneously, several fighter jets took off from Italian military bases heading in the direction of Yugoslavia. Before this second attack, NATO threatened to intensify the bombings systematically. NATO Supreme Commander Wesley Clark did not exclude the complete destruction of their forces and support facilities.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-25</field><field name="title">Diplomatic ties severed </field>
<field name="text">In reaction to the attacks, Yugoslavia has apparently cut diplomatic relations with several western countries, including the US, Great Britain, France, and Germany. The government in Belgrade declared that these countries had committed a crime against the people of Yugoslavia. The Federal Republic was accused of reopening the unhealed wounds of World War II through this act of aggression.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-25</field><field name="title">PDS suit challenging NATO operation dismissed </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Constitutional Court dismissed a suit as inadmissible that was brought by the PDS parliamentary group challenging German participation in the NATO operation in Yugoslavia. The second senate determined unanimously that the PDS was not authorized to file the petition since neither its own nor the rights of the German Bundestag had been infringed upon. The justices also noted that the petition did not address the legality of German participation in the operation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-25</field><field name="title">Further discussions on Agenda 2000 </field>
<field name="text">After many individual discussions, the heads of state and heads of government from European Union countries are again formally negotiating the reform program Agenda 2000. The negotiations in Berlin have thus entered the decisive phase. It is considered questionable whether an agreement will be reached by tomorrow (Friday) morning. Points still being debated are cuts in future EU expenditures for agriculture as well as the amount of funds that will be used to support the poorer countries and economically weak regions. Foreign Minister Joschka Fischer said that the discussions were very difficult. Swedish Prime Minister Goran Persson said that he was not optimistic.  </field></doc></add>