<add><doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Germany boots support for earthquake victims </field>
<field name="text">Germany boosted efforts to help the earthquake victims in Turkey. Johanniter, Caritas and Help sent sniffer-dogs, water, tankers, blankets, food and medication to the stricken area. The Diakonische Werk and Caritas International raised 400,000 marks between them, and Bavaria's state government another 150,000. Meanwhile Munich's Council for Foreigners appealed to all companies and government departments, to be generous when granting Turkish staff special leave for travel to their former home-country.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Radio WDR sets up earthquake info-hotline </field>
<field name="text">Radio Westdeutscher Rundfunk set up a hotline in Turkish. Native speakers can call 24 hours a day and find out about the search and rescue actions in the area hit by the earthquake, in Turkish. A team of experts, including doctors and psychologists, give advice to callers. The freephone number is: 0800/5678990.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">German Association of Tenants thinks state housing is in danger </field>
<field name="text">The German Association of Tenants (Deutscher Mieterbund) thinks that state housing is in its last throes. They accused government of neglecting this area and using it as the "Finance Minister's piggy-bank". Since 1994, the budget had been trimmed by close to 3 billion marks to currently 1.2 billion marks. Therefore the Association appealed to the Finance Minister to stop further cost-cutting, and raise income-thresholds for government subsidies instead. Government pays income-tested subsidies to owner-occupiers.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">State Education Minister Schavan for modernising schools </field>
<field name="text">State Education Minister for Baden-Wuerttemberg Schavan is for fundamentally modernising schools. She wants teachers' pay to be performance-based, for example, or pay teachers a bonus if they supervise students in after-school activities. The CDU-politician also wants curricula to get rid of unnecessary detail information.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Mr Zurwehme confesses murders </field>
<field name="text">Mr Dieter Zurwehme was arrested yesterday and confessed having murdered two elderly couples at Remagen. Koblenz police said that he had already been seen by the police court. He is to be remanded in prison, where there will be more interviews. After nine months on the run, two police on the beat detained Mr Zurwehme yesterday at Greifswald, walking the streets. Last year in December the 57-year old man escaped from an open penitentiary at Bielefeld. Now he will probably get another life-sentence.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Alleged murderer of 12-year old Carla taken to court </field>
<field name="text">More than 18 months after 12-year old Carla from Wilhermsdorf was murdered the alleged offender was taken to court. Last year in December the girl had been found in a pond, unconscious. She died five days later in hospital.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Shops will have to stay closed on Sundays in Leipzig </field>
<field name="text">Following Halle, Berlin and other East-German cities, Leipzig as well will have to keep shops closed on Sundays. The Higher Regional Court banned any attempts to grant exemptions, when their purpose was to avoid breaking the law on opening-hours.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Medical practitioners give in </field>
<field name="text">Doctors relented in the renewed dispute between medical doctors and the Health Ministry, offering excuses for a letter their deputy president had written to the ministry, and emphasising that they intended to honour the recently struck compromise. Last Tuesday doctors, (public) health insurers and the ministry had agreed to make sure they did prescribe cheaper alternatives instead of the original drugs. This put paid to a week-long dispute about staying within the budget for drugs.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Travel agents to charge for advice </field>
<field name="text">According to a travel magazine, travel agents will ask their customers to pay for advice in the future. Advice on train travel is to be at least 3 marks. Written individual itineraries could be up to 100 marks. This plan is to be realised until the middle of the year 2000, at the latest. Booking classical package-travel will be exempt, for the time being. The magazine quoted lower commissions by airlines and German Railways, for example.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Federal Borderguards investigate their own staff </field>
<field name="text">Federal Borderguards (Bundesgrenzschutz) are faced with one of the biggest criminal cases in their own organisation. After having arrested several staff-members working at Frankfurt Airport for dealing in narcotics, investigators now have discovered a network of Ecstasy-consumers and -dealers involving at least 25 staff-members. Mr Hasslinger, president of BGS-Central, was very concerned as he had never had a case of these proportions before.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Alleged war-criminals arrested </field>
<field name="text">German Kosovo-peacekeepers arrested several alleged Serbian war-criminals in the western part of the area. They are suspected of having been accessories to the murder of Kosovo-Albanians.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Ms Heike Drechsler flags away World Championship </field>
<field name="text">Days before the World Championship, Ms Heike Drechsler had complained about problems with injuries. In the end, an injury in her left upper leg she had suffered in a tournament in Switzerland last Sunday, made her throw the towel. Ms Drechsler had arrived in Seville only yesterday. Practising sprinting this morning broke the camel's back. Mr Drechsler and her coach and de-facto husband Alain Blondelle said they were even relieved at the decision, after all the hassles during the last days. Ms Drechsler, who is long jump world-champion 1983, will return to Germany today.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Mr Schumacher back behind steering-wheel </field>
<field name="text">Someone else, however, apparently has had a successful comeback, and we are talking of double Formula-1 world-champion Michael Schumacher. Mr Schumacher is back in Italy and behind the wheel of his beloved red Ferrari. 40 days after his accident at Silverstone/England, he did his first trial-rounds at Mocello/Italy. And he was even a little bit faster than his team-mate Eddie Irvine. In spite of that, management in Italy do not believe he will be able to take part in the Spa/Belgium race at the end of August; they rather think he will be back in style at Monza/Italy in September. The medical specialists in Geneva, who had examined him yesterday, said that he was fit, but would need another 3 to 4 months for a full recovery  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">Mr Kiefer reaches quarter-finals in Washington </field>
<field name="text">Mr Nikolai Kiefer from Holzminden reached the quarter-finals at the Washington Tennis Tournament (worth 725,000 dollars). He beat Mr John van Lotter, from the Netherlands, 7:5 and 6:2. Mr Bjoern Pau, from Leverkusen, was not as lucky: he lost 1:6 and 3:6 against Mr Andre Agassi, USA, who is number three in the world-rankings.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-20</field><field name="title">German Soccer Association: a minute's silence for earthquake victims </field>
<field name="text">The German Soccer Association (DFB) asked for a minute's silence during this weekend's games, for the earthquake victims in Turkey.  </field></doc></add>