<add><doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Mr Eichel wants to soldier on as far as budget-cuts are concerned </field>
<field name="text">Federal government will soldier on, as far as budget-cuts are concerned, regardless of any lobbying, as Finance Minister Eichel said. The SPD-politician said in Bonn that there was an obligation to put the financial house in order. It would be irresponsible and antisocial to leave the next generation with a state that was burdened with too much debt. Mr Eichel also announced that cabinet would decide on the matter on 25 August.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Mr Gerhardt wants new elections in case Red-Green coalition falls apart </field>
<field name="text">Head of the FDP Gerhardt categorically ruled out a coalition with the SPD, in case the existing Red-Green coalition broke up. When interviewed on ZDF television, Mr Gerhardt said that in this case new elections should be called. Then voters would decide on new policies in Germany, and that would set the scene for a CDU/CSU-FDP coalition.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Federal borderguards arrested for allegedly smuggling narcotics </field>
<field name="text">8 members of the Federal Borderguards (Bundesgrenzschutz) have been arrested in Frankfurt/Main for allegedly smuggling the drugs cocaine and Ecstasy via the city's airport. They had been suspended immediately, according to Federal Minister for Internal Affairs Schily. Mr Schily said that there would be an inquiry into the matter with neither black-outs nor gaps.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Prison inmate kills deputy boss and himself </field>
<field name="text">A prison inmate of Uelzen jail, Lower Saxony, killed the deputy boss and wounded three more inmates using a kitchen knife. According to the Lower Saxony Ministry of Justice the inmate, who had been serving a sentence for manslaughter, then killed himself. Police said that none of the wounded persons was in a serious condition.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">No way to solve stock-feed scandal </field>
<field name="text">There probably is no way to determine if stock-feed containing sludge, or animals that had been fed the mixture, had been imported from France. The Federal Institute for Consumer Health Issues declared that as the scandal was several months in the past, there was no usable evidence any more.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">More and more environmental crime in Germany </field>
<field name="text">More and more environmental crimes are being committed in Germany, though less and less of them are being investigated and solved. As the Federal Environmental Agency (Umweltbundesamt) noted, illegal disposal of refuse still was the main issue.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Ms Steffi Graf calls it quits </field>
<field name="text">Today Ms Steffi Graf called it quits, after a tennis career spanning 17 years. In the middle of December there is to be a farewell tour, starting with South Africa. Ms Graf won 22 Grand-Slam tournaments, she was number 1 in the world-rankings for 377 weeks, a unique tennis-career indeed. After the San Diego tournament she had lost interest in playing tennis, something she had already realised when flying out to San Diego. "After Wimbledon there's nothing left for me to achieve." Ms Graf said that her decision had been a relief for her, though she would not be drawn on what she planned to do in the future.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-13</field><field name="title">Mostly respect for Ms Graf's decision </field>
<field name="text">The Women's World Tennis Association regretted that one of the sport's darlings called it quits. Many top sportspeople and other prominent persons respected her decision. It was a sad day, however, for former coach of the ladies Mr Klaus Hofses, but he was glad about her graceful exit. Ms Graf was the best female tennis-player of all times, according to him.  Mr Franz Beckenbauer called Ms Graf one of the best players in German history. Her decision was a pity, but had to be respected.  Baden-Wuerttemberg State Premier Teufel said Ms Graf was one of the state's most popular persons. Her success had helped raise Germany's perception in the rest of the world.  Mr Walter Troeger, president of the German Olympic Committee, praised Ms Graf for having kept going, even after she had reached  the summit of her career. Every sportsperson should be free to decide how long they wanted to enjoy to keep going.  </field></doc></add>