<add><doc><field name="date">1998-10-27</field><field name="title">Change of government in Bonn </field>
<field name="text">Today was an occasion to see Germany's constitution in action. Four weeks after the general election, the constitutional bodies of the Federal Republic of Germany carried out the orderly shift from one government to the next. Most important topic on the agenda was at noon the election of Gerhard Schroeder as Chancellor. The Social-Democrat was installed into the most powerful office of the state by a surprisingly strong majority. In secret ballot he received six votes more than the red-green (Social-Democrat with Buendnis90/Gruene) coalition has members. Mr. Schroeder was then appointed by President Roman Herzog and sworn in in parliament by Parliamentary President Wolfgang Thierse. Finally, the red-green cabinet consisting of 15 ministers, eleven men and four women, was formally introduced. President Herzog handed them their installation certificates and wished them well. A new era of German post-war politics may begin.  The addresses of the former and the new chancellors did not take even a quarter of an hour. Helmut Kohl, obviously touched, wished his successor Gerhard Schroeder much success and a lucky hand in governing the country. He, Schroeder, would take over the office in a time with completely different norms and especially with different challenges than what he, Kohl, had experienced 16 years ago. Kohl added that in his opinion it made little sense to always try to rewrite history. "You are history" was the new chancellor's answer. According to Gerhard Schroeder, Kohl showed particular greatness in the hour of his defeat. He complimented Kohl on the way Kohl had shown that a democratic change is natural and normal. This had helped all of them. Kohl had talked rightfully that that had increased Germany's reputation in the world. Schroeder wanted to put it that simple. Schroeder promised he would mention Kohl honourably again in his government declaration; but that would be the end of it. Both, the new and the former chancellor showed humour tonight: the new chancellor, Gerhard Schroeder, to make the departure more easy for the leaving chancellor, Helmut Kohl. But this departure was evidently difficult after 16 years in the chancellor's office that are now over.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-27</field><field name="title">Head of Hamburg's intelligence service becomes head of federal services </field>
<field name="text">Gerhard Schroeder's latest personnel decision was announced this morning. Hamburg's head of police Ernst Uhrlau will become co-ordinator of the German secret services. The 51-year-old Social-Democrat who also once headed Hamburg's domestic intelligence service is succeeding Bernd Schmidbauer.  The new Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder has personally invited the Hamburg head of police into his Bonn team where starting next week, Uhrlau will co-ordinate the work of the domestic, the foreign and the military intelligence service. In contrast to his predecessor, Uhrlau will have a lower administrative rank. Even before his selection the Social-Democrat had counselled the SPD's working group for interior security. For 15 years Uhrlau has worked for the Hamburg intelligence service, five of which as its head. He has studied politics at is considered a brilliant analyst and expert for extremism. Uhrlau did not want to talk yet about his exact duties but he rejected doubts about the necessity of secret services as have been voiced in the past by Green politicians. The role of the secret services would be important even in the European Union. They represented security services, intelligence services, also as early warning systems of future developments in Europe or in relation to areas of conflict that were important for Europe.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-27</field><field name="title">Karlsruhe turns down the Bavarian special law for abortion </field>
<field name="text">The SPD handed in several emergency motions after today's judgement in Karlsruhe. The government has been asked to immediately withdraw the Bavarian special laws and not to initiate any further legal steps. In the morning, the Federal Constitutional Court declared the Bavarian special law for abortion as being unconstitutional. With this judgement the judges in Karlsruhe agreed to the action of five medical doctors against the Bavarian law. After today's judgement the two abortion specialists, Andreas Freudemann and Friedrich Stapf, can continue to unrestrictedly ran their practices, where most of the abortion in Bavaria were done. The requirement of the controversial law to be a medical specialist will not be valid at least for the two medical doctors mentioned before. The Federal Constitutional Court declared the restriction of the admissible income from abortions to a quarter of the total revenue to be completely invalid. According to the Federal Constitutional Court, the federal legislator do not allow the states enough latitude, therefore Bavaria has already exceeded its legislative competences. The Bavarian consultation law is not affected by the judgement in Karlsruhe.  The judgement is a tough lesson for the Bavarian government. The Bavarian government has left it open whether they are going to initiative further steps towards the abortion law. Barbara Stamm announced that the votes of the three judges who supported the Bavarian initiative, will be examined very carefully. But one thing is certain and that is that the dispute about abortion in Bavaria is not over yet. The SPD announced  several emergency motions in the Landtag (state parliament). With it the party wants to avoid a further initiative of the CSU and the state government. The SPD politician, Renate Schmidt said that it was about time for a law peacetime: " We ask the Bavarian government to immediately withdraw the Bavarian special laws and finally to attain a federal legislation also in the Free State of Bavaria and to take a bit of distance towards all the initiatives that question the compromise negotiated with difficulty towards the protection of the unborn child and the legal security of women." The Greens hope that qualified gynaecologist will be able to improve their methods of treatment for abortions and therefore the medical care.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-10-27</field><field name="title">Guenter Krause in a catch-22 situation </field>
<field name="text">Three warrants have been issued for the former federal minister of transport's arrest. This was confirmed by the district court in Rostock. This should force Krause to either pay its debts or to swear an oath of manifestation. The reason for the legal proceedings are the financial claims against him from three contracting parties of the real estate agent company Kraus Aufbau Invest. According to those claims, the former minister owes them a total of 1.1 million DM.  </field></doc></add>