<add><doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Over 4 million jobless again </field>
<field name="text">The number of unemployed in Germany has again risen over the four million mark. At the end of December 4,047,000 people were without work. This is just under 147,000 more as in November. These figures were reported this morning by the president of the Federal Labor Office, Bernhard Jagoda. This represents a rise in the unemployment rate of 0.3 percent, to a total of 10.3 percent.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Local FDP party congress in Stuttgart </field>
<field name="text">A day prior to the traditional high-level January summit of the federal FDP, the Baden-Wuerttemberg arm of the party today gathered for a local party congress in Stuttgart. The approximately 400 delegates discussed new approaches to education policy, reform of old age pensions, and private financing of road construction, among other topics.  Walter Doering, head of the FDP in Baden-Wuerttemberg, would like to see deficit spending forbidden by the state constitution. This measure is needed, he says, because otherwise we will continue to live at the expense of the next generation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Bernhard Wicky dies </field>
<field name="text">Actor and film director Bernhard Wicky is dead. He died in Munich at the age of 80 from heart failure. Wicky's 1959 anti-war film "The Bridge" is world renowned. It concerns the fate of several students, who - there being no soldiers left - were senselessly sent to defend a bridge from American forces in 1945. The film exerted a fundamental influence on post-war cinema in Germany. Born in Austria, the Swiss citizen received numerous awards. The last, the day prior to his death, was the Austrian Cross of Honor for Art and Science, first class. State Premier Stoiber of Bavaria honored Wicky's precision as a director, his expressiveness as an actor, and in Stoiber's own words, "the untiring strength he brought to all his endeavors."  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Police arrest gang of youths </field>
<field name="text">The police in Voehringen in the Neu-Ulm region have arrested a gang of young criminals. A 19 year old student is alleged to be the ringleader responsible for leading brutal assaults. According to police reports, for at least a year a total of nine youths between the ages of 16 and 19 have been attacking persons who were travelling alone, and in many cases were drunk. Their primary objective was the victim's cash cards, and the PIN numbers for them, which were beaten out of the victim.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Diether Krebs dies </field>
<field name="text">The actor Diether Krebs has died at age 52 from cancer. Krebs was best known for his role on the television series "One Heart and One Soul", and later the comedy program "Sketchup".  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Fritz Leonhard dies </field>
<field name="text">World renowned civil engineer Fritz Leonhard is dead. He died in Stuttgart last Thursday at the age of 90, according to a statement first given by his family today. Leonhard was responsible for the 217 meter tall television tower in Stuttgart, that was, at its completion in 1954, the eleventh tallest structure in the world.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Prosecutor calls for high penalty in railway extortion case </field>
<field name="text">The public prosecutor's office has called for life imprisonment of the defendant in the railway extortion case now being heard in Berlin. In an attempt to extort 10 million marks from the Deutsche Bahn railway company, the 47 year old came within a hairsbreadth of snuffing out hundreds of human lives, they said. The man is alleged to have loosened ties on three stretches of track, with full knowledge of the possible deaths of railway engineers and travelers.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-05</field><field name="title">Crime and Punishment: Cops get stopped </field>
<field name="text">In Nuremberg, a teenager dressed as a policeman conducting an ostensible traffic patrol wound up making the wrong stop. The 18 year old would-be officer stopped, of all things, a police car. Dressed in a dark leather jacket and a police cap, the young apprentice also had two blank pistols and handcuffs in his car. The real officers assume his motive was to show off. Preliminary proceedings have been opened against the youth on charges of impersonating an officer.  </field></doc></add>