<add><doc><field name="date">1998-08-21</field><field name="title">Kohl endorses US military action </field>
<field name="text">German Chancellor Helmut Kohl agrees with US military attacks against targets in Sudan and Afghanistan. Kohl said in Bonn the German government condemns vehemently any kind of terrorism. It is therefore supporting any action that serves the fighting of this scourge of the international community. Yesterday, the USA had attacked presumed terrorist bases in Afghanistan and Sudan as a response to bomb attacks on US embassies in East Africa.  SPD deputy faction leader Guenther Verheugen called the military action a tough and decisive response to a murderous, terrorist threat. A final judgement of the attacks, however, could only be made when it has become clear which targets the USA had really attacked in Afghanistan and Sudan. Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel stressed that the government agreed with American President Bill Clinton that the attacks were not targeted against Islam or Afghanistan or Sudan but only against international terrorism. Both Kohl and Verheugen refuted speculations that Clinton had tried to use the attacks to divert from the Lewinsky affaire.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-21</field><field name="title">Part-time jobs increasing in Bavaria </field>
<field name="text">The Bavarian Statistics Office reported that last year 588,000 persons were employed part-time. This is a new high. Since 1996 the number of part-time workers increased by 2.2 percent. Ninety percent of the part-time workers are women.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-21</field><field name="title">New diary of Anne Frank </field>
<field name="text">The world-renown diary of the Jewish girl Anne Frank will be published in an extended version early next year. The five additional pages that had been discovered recently purportedly contain critical remarks about Anne Frank's parents' marriage. The Frank family had been able to hide from the Nazis in Amsterdam from 1942 to 1944 before the family was betrayed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-21</field><field name="title">Kohl appoints council </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Helmut Kohl has appointed a voluntary council. The council for Future and Innovation headed by Jenoptik CEO Lothar Spaeth is to make suggestions for the further reform of Germany as a business location. The experts are to keep an eye especially on the restructuring of the new federal states. Kohl and Spaeth did not want to make the council's foundation an election action. In support of this notion, Spaeth wants to name the 15 members of the council only after the federal elections. His aim is to re-organize political communication because the speed of changes is increasing continuously. The Chancellor had asked the former state premier of Baden-Wuerttemberg and now president of Jenoptik AG to lead the council; a surprising step. Nine years ago, Spaeth was one of Kohl's fiercest opponents within his own party. Today, CDU leader Kohl points out joint experiences. In particular, Kohl praised Spaeth's great experience in politics and economics. The rouble crisis and the financial difficulties in Asia show, in Kohl's view, the importance of external expertise.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-21</field><field name="title">Five people killed in shelter </field>
<field name="text">Last night five people were killed in a fire in Alzhausen, Herpensburg District. Ten other homeless people who passed the night in the shelter were seriously injured. The cause of the fire remains unclear. Currently, police do not assume arson. The house was occupied mainly by homeless people who were older ore required care.  </field></doc></add>