<add><doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Chancellor Schroeder: War in Kosovo will take its time </field>
<field name="text">UN General Secretary Annan has widened the scope of his endeavours to come to a solution in the Kosovo crisis. According to his spokesperson in New York, he has scheduled meetings with the ambassadors of the five permanent members of the World Security Council, to work on a solution. Last night Chancellor Schroeder said on ARD-television that Mr Annan's trying as well as Germany would on the one hand raise hopes that there could be a diplomatic solution, though on the other hand he did not believe that the war would be over soon.  Prior to that, Defence Minister Scharping spoke about new atrocities committed by Serbian soldiers. He announced that he would pass on the relevant documentation to the International Court for War Crimes in The Hague. According to UN-Human Rights Commissioner Robinson, there are indications that executions of Kosovo Albanians have been committed by Serbian soldiers.  According to US sources an alleged mass grave has been discovered near the provincial capital of Pristina. Today NATO continued with more airstrikes. This afternoon the allied forces in Brussels have refuted claims they were to blame for the death of numerous civilians in western Kosovo two days ago. In Washington US Defence Minister Cohen stated that he wanted to call up a substantial number of reserve forces for deployment in Jugoslavia. Meanwhile the flow of refugees into Albania and Macedonia is as strong as ever. According to the UN refugee organisation, more than 12,000 refugees crossed the border within the last 24 hours. Obviously Belgrade was planning to expel all Kosovo Albanians, according to a spokesperson in Geneva.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Financial help for the 12 countries sharing the coast of the Mediterranean </field>
<field name="text">The European Union agreed on financial help for the 12 countries sharing the coast of the Mediterranean. At the end of the EU-Mediterranean Conference in Stuttgart, a spokesperson for the German Foreign Office stated that probably billions of marks would be available towards the year 2006, though the exact amount had not been set yet. In the past 4 years, the amount had been more than 4 billion euros. The participants also agreed on formulating a charter about peace and stability. The charter is to be drafted till the next meeting in two years' time.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Tax-refunds for 4.5 million German families </field>
<field name="text">Some 4.5 million families will get a tax-refund, as their exemptions for children had been set at too low a level. This would affect the years 1985 to 1995, so there was no need to apply for the refund (as these years were still 'current', according to the tax-office). The refunds will hit federal and state finances to the tune of almost 1 billion marks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Volkswagen and banks' awards talks stalled without a result </field>
<field name="text">Awards talks for the approximately 100,000 workers employed by Volkswagen in West Germany have been postponed without having reached a result. Both sides are to have another go next Thursday. The employers had offered 2.5% more pay, as of 1 August, plus a bonus of 1000 marks, depending on profits. They also agreed to convert 6000 temporary jobs to permanent jobs. The union declined the offer as insufficient. They want 3.2% more pay plus a one-off bonus of 1% of an annual pay. The banks also have not settled their awards either. According to the unions some 12,000 staff went on strike today, mainly in Frankfurt, Hamburg and Munich.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Finance Minister Eichel for a "Marshall Plan" for the Balkans </field>
<field name="text">Federal Finance Minister Eichel asked for a long-term commitment by the European Union as far as the Balkans were concerned. At a meeting of the EU economics and finance ministers in Dresden, Mr Eichel said that there would have to be something similar to the Marshall Plan, that after WWII brought Germany back on track. But it was not only money that was needed, but also support for building up democracies in the former communist countries. The ministers were halting repayments of loans for the countries of Macedonia and Albania which are taking in the bulk of the refugees from the Kosovo region.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-04-16</field><field name="title">Negotiations about fund for forced labourers during Third Reich </field>
<field name="text">Federal government thinks that agreement on the planned fund for forced labourers during the Third Reich will be reached soon. Mr Hombach, speaking for Chancellor Schroeder, said that the concept had been finalised. But there were still judicial problems with the companies concerned. That's why he wanted to meet the US government and Jewish organisations once again, within a fortnight. Deutsche Bank would only agree to the fund if the classaction suits in the United States were withdrawn. The Nurnberg Labour Court began the first of 58 lawsuits: forced Ukrainian labourers vs the military equipment conglomerate Diehl.  </field></doc></add>