<add><doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Analysis of Hamburg election results </field>
<field name="text">Former First Mayor of Hamburg Henning Voscherau wants to substantially reduce his activity in politics. During a press conference at the SPD headquarters in Bonn, Voscherau announced he would also resign from his position as SPD negotiator for finance politics in the Bundesrat (upper house of parliament). It stands to see whether he will participate one last time in Thursday's discussions about tax reform in the mediation committee. The current senator for finance, Ortwin Runde, is the person most often named as Voscherau's successor. Before assuming his present post, Runde  headed the Social Welfare Office for many years. Runde has detailed knowledge of Hamburg's problems and the internal workings of the governing party and would probably be capable of heading a red/green coalition government. His one handicap is that he is not the charismatic orator who can present himself to the public and to the media as Voscherau could. This might rather be expected from the current senator for environmental affairs, Fritz Vahrenholt. But the latter belongs to the right wing of the party and might not easily agree to a red/green cooperation. Voscherau himself also considers his close collaborator, Thomas Mirow, a possible successor. The Hamburg SPD achieved its worst post-war election result with 36.2% of votes. Preliminary analyses attribute this fact to the SPD campaign. Centering the election campaign on internal security proved disastrous for SPD. In districts with a high crime rate, high unemployment rates, and high percentages of foreigners, many voters switched over to the Green-Alternative List (GAL) and to the radical right-wing DVU. REP-voters this time gave a strategic vote to DVU. Wherever the SPD lost votes, the CDU gained (30.7%); SPD voters and blu-collar workers turned their backs on the party. The CDU also succeeded in recovering votes formerly lost to the STATT party. STATT, DVU, and FDP did not achieve the 5% of the vote necessary to win seats in the state parliament.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Analysis of Hamburg election results by Bonn </field>
<field name="text">After the Hamburg State elections, party headquarters in Bonn and in Hamburg presented their analyses. The CDU is getting optimistic: In spite of the reform bottleneck in Bonn, the party increased its share of the votes in Hamburg. Party Chairman and Chancellor Helmut Kohl sees this as a positive sign for next year's national elections. Kohl's hope is that the SPD will form a "grand coalition" with the Christian Democrats in Hamburg. The SPD is still discussing the consequences of yesterday's defeat. The Social Democrats need a new first mayor as well as a new financial coordinator for the tax debates with the ruling coalition in Bonn, an office from which Voscherau also intends to resign.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">SPD discusses Voscherau's succession </field>
<field name="text">The SPD state executive board met to discuss the succession of former First Mayor Henning Voscherau. Voscherau had said that his resignation should make it easier for the party to make a new start after Sunday's electoral defeat. Meanwhile, the CDU commented on the election results in Hamburg as being the logical consequence of the SPD's blocking tactics in the matters of tax and social security reforms. They consider the result of the elections as proof of the fact that citizens don't like blocking tactics. SPD national chairman Oskar Lafontaine declared that the Hamburg results had nothing to do with Bonn's tax policy - a clear sign that the Social Democrats do not intend to change their course.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Green Party counts on red-green coalition in Hamburg </field>
<field name="text">The Green party expects a red/green coalition in Hamburg as a consequence of election results. This was declared by both Ms. Roessel, spokeswoman for the national board of the Green party, and Krista Sager, Hamburg's top GAL candidate. Both consider a red/green coalition in Hamburg to be an excellent starting signal for a change of power in Bonn. They expressly warn against a "grand coalition" between SPD and CDU in Hamburg, which would only strengthen the right wing.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Temporary workers have no guarantee for continuous employment </field>
<field name="text">Persons who had contracts to substitute for an employee who is temporarily off the job cannot claim a right to continued employment. This was a basic decision issued by the Federal Labour Court. The court reasoned that the employer had an undissolved employment contract with the temporarily absent employee, who had a right to return to the job. A temp worker cannot claim to be accepted into an unlimited employment situation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Ghana citizen dies of Lassa fever </field>
<field name="text">Health authorities are looking nationwide for about 50 persons who had contact with a Ghana citizen who died of Lassa fever in Mainz on Saturday. Lassa fever is a potentially deadly disease if not detected in time. It is also highly contagious. The deceased patient had been to Wiesbaden and Duesseldorf. Lassa fever is mainly transmitted by rats. Infection between humans is less dramatic. There are no working vaccines at this time. The mortality rate is 15 to 20%, according to the Robert Koch Institute; other sources claim a mortality rate of as high as 30%. As the mortal disease is transmitted by way of bodily fluids, e.g., during sexual intercourse, authorities are now on the lookout for persons who had close contact with the man from Ghana.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">BSE suspicion confirmed </field>
<field name="text">Suspicions about a BSE-infected head of cattle imported into Bavaria from Switzerland has now been confirmed. A second analysis of cerebral matter showed a substance typical of the cattle disease. The imported animal had been killed as early as May, together with another 2,700 cattle.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Trial of additional suspects of terrorist attack in Cairo </field>
<field name="text">In the course of investigations around the firebomb attack on German tourists, police have taken four more suspects before a military court. They are accused of having procured the weapons and incendiary devices for the attack.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">East German construction business in a recession </field>
<field name="text">According to the Federal Dept. of Statistics, the recession in the construction sector in the new states continues. During the first seven months of this year, new orders were 13% below last year's level. The recession was especially severe in the area of commercial and public construction. In comparison, numbers for western Germany show a 3.7% decline of new orders.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Memorial service for victims of crashed Bundeswehr plane </field>
<field name="text">Close to 1,000 persons attended an ecumenical memorial service for the victims of the Bundeswehr plane lost in last week's accident. The plane had collided with a U.S. military plane off the coast of Namibia. All 24  passengers and crew of the Bundeswehr plane and the nine crew members of the U.S. plane were killed. Searchers have to this date only recovered the body of one flight attendant from South Atlantic waters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Crashed Tupolev was off course laid down in flight-plan </field>
<field name="text">The Bundeswehr Tupolev that collided with a U.S. plane off Namibia was off the course set down in the flight schedule. This is the finding of an investigation presented by Minister for Defense Volker Ruehe. Ghana flight safety agreed to the change. Also, the flight elevation as stated in the flight schedule did not completely comply with international regulations. According to Ruehe, it is still to early to attribute culpabilities.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Consumer protection organizations warn against credit for minors </field>
<field name="text">The Consumer Association of North Rhine-Westphalia accused a large number of credit institutes of transgressing regulations when it comes to authorize loans to minors. For instance, many banks waive parental signatures on opening a credit line or issuing EC-cards to 14 to 17-year-olds.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-09-22</field><field name="title">Soldier killed in shooting-range accident </field>
<field name="text">A drafted soldier was accidentally shot to death on Army training grounds near Daden. According to a Bundeswehr communique, the 20-year-old soldier from Erfurt was probably hit by a bullet shot by one of his comrades during a shooting exercise.  </field></doc></add>