<add><doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Mr Kanther for conscientious objectors serving in police-force </field>
<field name="text">Federal Minister of the Interior Kanther was in favour of having conscientious objectors serve in the police-force. This would free sworn police-officers from time-consuming paperwork enabling them to re-concentrate on fighting crime.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">SPD: there still is a chance contributions to pension-scheme will not rise </field>
<field name="text">The Social Democrats think there still are chances the contribution-rate to the public pension scheme would not have to rise to 21%. Yesterday cabinet had decided on the rise, but also declared that they were looking for compromises until the Upper House (Bundesrat) had had their say. Head of the SPD Lafontaine now stated, that his party would offer raising excise-duty on motor-spirits and sales tax, while lowering contributions to the public pension-scheme and the public unemployment-scheme by 1% each. Today Lower Saxony's premier Schroeder tabled this proposal in the Upper House (Bundesrat).  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Mr Roestel thinks there should be a change of power in Bonn </field>
<field name="text">Head of the Greens party Roestel asked for a change of power in Bonn. The current government had jeopardised Germany as a country for doing business in, what with bleeding dry patients, putting pensions at risk and continuously raising taxes and contributions. After the upcoming federal elections, a straight swap of Chancellor Kohl for Chancellor  Lafontaine or Chancellor Schroeder would not do. They would, however, only talk about compromises if and when they had been successful at the polls.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Ministry of Defence confirms part of TV-documentary </field>
<field name="text">The Ministry of Defence confirmed parts of a TV-documentary produced by WDR-magazine "Monitor" about the mid-air collision of a German air-force Tupolev and a US air-force plane off the coast of Namibia. All 24 passengers were killed in the crash. Now the ministry admitted that some details of the flight-plan, e.g. flight-levels, had been provided by a private company. The data, however, had been checked by the crew - contrary to what the documentary had stated. Wrong flight-levels allegedly had been the cause of the crash.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Mr Solana on Bosnian peace-keeping mission </field>
<field name="text">NATO General Secretary Solana said that he expected all countries who were currently involved in the international peace-keeping mission in Bosnia to keep doing so after June 1998, when their current mandate will expire. At a meeting of the Konrad-Adenauer-Fund in Berlin, he added that he expected all war-criminals to be taken to court - though, according to the Dayton Accords, NATO would have no say in the apprehension of alleged criminals.  Previously the General Secretary had had talks with Berlin's Lord Mayor Diepgen. Mr Diepgen emphasised that he would keep re-patriating refugees from former Yugoslavia in a consistent manner.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Suspended sentence for former GDR border-guard </field>
<field name="text">A former GDR border-guard got a suspended sentence of 16 months' jail. The Berlin Regional Court had convicted him of having killed a 21-year old man, who had tried to flee in 1969. He had set his firearm to automatic and shot without prior warning - in full knowledge that this would kill the victim.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">7 German tourists killed in traffic-accident in South Africa </field>
<field name="text">7 German tourists were killed in South Africa's Grahamstown when their bus crashed, according to German Press Agency dpa (which in turn quoted South African Radio). 15 more passengers had been injured and treated in hospital. The group had been travelling in a small tourist bus.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-07</field><field name="title">Soccer Europe Cup: Stuttgart makes it into the quarter-finals </field>
<field name="text">In spite of having lost against Belgium's Germinal Ekeren club, the VFB Stuttgart made it into the quarter-finals of the Europe Cup of the Cup Winners - as they had previously won the first game 4:0.  </field></doc></add>