<add><doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">River Oder's water-levels keep dropping </field>
<field name="text">Flood-levels keep falling, mainly in the southern part of the area. The river Oder's level at Ratzdorf was 1.5 metres lower than when it peaked several days ago, and local residents may return to their homes now.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Minister Rexrodt will help businesses affected by floods </field>
<field name="text">When visiting the area, Federal Economics Minister Rexrodt assured businesses affected by the floods that they would get quick help without the red tape, pointing out that federal and state governments would pool resources to the tune of 40 million marks. This would be enough to pay out an emergency cash-grant of up to 10,000 marks/case. According to the minister, more than 900 businesses in the state of Brandenburg were hit by the floods.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Chancellor Kohl: Compromise with SPD in tax-reform matters possible </field>
<field name="text">Gilgen. Chancellor Kohl, who was holidaying in neighbouring Austria, was confident that there would be a compromise with the SPD as far as the tax-reform plans were concerned, otherwise this would become an issue for the upcoming federal elections, and the SPD would then lose them. Come rain or shine, his government would reform pensions this year, and he ruled out any interference from the Upper House (Bundesrat) in this matter. He also declined to comment on plans to change the constitution in order to clip the Upper House's (Bundesrat) wings, stating that this was a non-issue as no-one had the required majority for this sort of amendment.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">More wrangling about spelling-reform </field>
<field name="text">The president of the parliamentary committee on judicial matters, Mr Eilmann, of the CDU, wanted the spelling-reform put on hold. He asked the state ministers of education to negotiate a solution together with federal government.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Discussion about scrapping conscription </field>
<field name="text">Coalition partners keep discussing the eventual scrapping of conscription, as well as opening up the armed forces to females. Defence Minister Ruehe was all for getting females into the armed forces, but said that this required a 2/3-majority decision in parliament. FDP Secretary General Westerwelle, however, stated that female recruits carrying arms should be volunteers only. The FDP is planning to have their party-members vote (internally) on the matter in autumn.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Vietnamese cigarette-Mafia trial in Berlin </field>
<field name="text">Today the so far biggest trial of the Vietnamese cigarette-Mafia began at the Berlin Regional Court. 16 perpetrators were accused of having committed 9 murders. Defence counsel were trying to buy time by asking for a recess, to enable them to check on court staff. The 16 persons use 2 duty-lawyers each. Defence counsel had their doubts if the prosecution had enough evidence to convict them of 9 murders and taking hostages. In 1996 a tip-off by a female chief-witness had led to the arrest of the alleged gang-leader, and she will be very important for the trial. The lady, from Vietnam, had witnessed the execution of her husband (a Mafia-member). The accused will be protected by bullet-proof glass and several police-officers. The 32 lawyers will be assisted by 7 interpreters.   </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Ambulances refute claims they were cheating </field>
<field name="text">The association of ambulance services refutes claims that they were cheating, claiming that 99% of them would file claims with public health insurers without fiddling. The system was to blame, not individuals. A mere 1% of the 11,000 ambulance services had got into the firing-line because of manipulations. The paperwork, however, had grown over the years, quite often becoming too much for many staff, but they intend to fix that with more staff training.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Baden-Wuerttemberg public health insurers do not plan to give refunds </field>
<field name="text">Contrary to what the public health insurers in the states of Berlin, Hamburg and Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania did, Baden-Wuerttemberg was not planning to refund contributions. In return, they intended to cap the current contribution-rates at 13% until the end of 1998. Refunding contributions to patients who had made little or no claims had raised other insurers' hackles.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Trial of alleged killer of police-officer in Luebeck </field>
<field name="text">Today the trial of Mr Kai Diesner, who allegedly killed a police officer, began at the Higher Regional Court. Prior to the trial Mr Diesner, a right-wing radical, had already admitted to having shot a police officer at a road-block, though he denied that this was murder, claiming that he did what he did because he hated government. A few days before the killing, the 24-year old had caused grievous bodily harm to a Berlin bookseller.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Skinheads attack campers on the shores of Lake Constance </field>
<field name="text">Friedrichshafen/Lake Constance. Skinheads attacked a group of young people holidaying at a campground at Hagnau, injuring two persons. The youths aged between 16 and 18 years came from the Suebian Alps and wanted to have a week's holiday on the shores of Lake Constance. The attack lasted for a mere two minutes. Supposedly the skinheads had been evicted the day before for having been too noisy and unruly, and that was their way of getting back at the 'system'. The caretaker thought they originated from the Ludwigsburg area, and from his memory they had been to this campground before, together with their parents. That's why their faces looked familiar to him.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-08</field><field name="title">Ariane-rocket launches US-satellite into orbit </field>
<field name="text">A European Ariane-rocket launched from French Guyana brought a US-satellite into orbit. The satellite is to be used for TV-transmissions from South America.  </field></doc></add>