<add><doc><field name="date">1998-01-01</field><field name="title">Employers demand heavier cuts in social security </field>
<field name="text">Employers demand heavier cuts in the social security system than are to date planned by the government. Chairman of Employers' Association Hundt said today that public social security organizations in Germany have grown into a paralyzing catchall welfare system that is no longer financially bearable. Hundt demanded a rapid reduction in pension levels. Public health benefits should be limited to the medical essentials.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-01</field><field name="title">Bluem plans on government subsidy for low-income pensioners </field>
<field name="text">=46ederal minister for labor Bluem pretends to subsidize private  pension plans for low income population with government funds. According to the daily "Handelsblatt", Bluem is working out an amendment to the "Vermoegensbildungsfoerderung" (a program to help and encourage people to build nest-eggs) that would help low-income persons to offset the reduction of social security pensions with private pension plans. The asset building program is to be increased and to cover all citizens above 16 years of age. Among other provisions, the limit of subsidized amounts is to be increased from the present DM 936 to DM 1,200.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-01</field><field name="title">Skinhead attack on home for disabled injures several persons </field>
<field name="text">=46our skinheads injured several inmates of a home for the physically disabled in Saxony-Anhalt. According to police, one of the orderlies of the home caused the melee. He allegedly hit one of the female companions of the skinheads in the face, from which a bad free-for-all resulted. The 15 to 24 year olds started beating up the inmates and broke up the furniture. A deaf-mute suffered a brain concussion from a bottle on his head. Another disabled man was kicked in the scrotal parts and had to be hospitalized.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-01</field><field name="title">Food poisoning among inmates of home for aged </field>
<field name="text">26 inmates of a senior citizens' home in Munich suffered food poisoning. 6 of them had to be hospitalized. The others received on-site medical treatment. Immediately after lunch, they suffered attacks of diarrhea and vomiting. The exact origin of the poisoning has not yet been established. There seems to be no peril of life.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-01-01</field><field name="title">New Year ski jumping contest in Garmisch-Partenkirchen </field>
<field name="text">Japan's Kasoyoshi Funati repeated his success in Obersdorf and won the New Year jumping contest in Garmisch-Partenkirchen in his second victory in the 4 towers' tournament. Michael Wagner on place 7 was the highest-ranking German. Dieter Thoma came in 8th.  </field></doc></add>