<add><doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Foreign Minister Fischer criticizes American security policy </field>
<field name="text">Federal Foreign Minister Joschka Fischer criticized the American security policy. At the start of his visit in Washington, he opposed the US government's plans to change the anti-ballistic missile treaty limiting defense missiles. The development of a new missile defense system would, according to Fischer, violate the ABM treaty with Russia.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">China wants to discuss human rights and democracy with Germany </field>
<field name="text">China is prepared to discuss human rights and expansion of democracy with Germany, Chinese Premier Zhu Rongji said after a meeting with Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder. Schroeder said that he was highly satisfied with the state of the relations between Germany and China.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">China shows interest in maglev train Transrapid </field>
<field name="text">German companies and China signed contracts this morning worth a total of 5.9 billion DM. The German firms BASF and Bayer plan to build two plastics factories in China. According to a member of the German delegation, China is also allegedly interested in building a maglev Transrapid train line between Shanghai and Beijing.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">BASF to sell subsidiary to finance compensation </field>
<field name="text">The German company BASF wants to sell one of its subsidiaries in order to be able to pay 534 million DM in compensation in the US. BASF and six other international chemical companies are to pay a total of 2.2 billion DM to their customers for fixing prices for vitamins since 1990.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Bundestag votes on health care reform 2000 </field>
<field name="text">The German Bundestag voted on the government's health care reform plan today. The CDU announced that it plans to block the bill in the upper house or Bundesrat. The most controversial items in the bill are the global budget and the planned closing of many hospitals. Before the decisive debate in the Bundestag, Health Minister Andrea Fischer invited the CDU/CSU as well as the states to compromise talks on health care reform. CDU/CSU parliamentary party leader Wolfgang Schaeuble responded that the Union would only be willing to talk after the bill had been withdrawn. During the debate, the usual arguments were heard. The SPD's social policy expert Rudolf Dressler said that health care expenditures had to be limited or the premiums for health insurance would rise. Quack remedies therefore had to be removed from the health care system, he added. The CDU/CSU's health care spokesperson Wolfgang Lohmann maintained that the planned introduction of a global budget would lead to patients not receiving necessary treatments. He continued that the bill would not make it through the Bundesrat. After heated discussions, the Bundestag passed Health Care Reform 2000 and rejected a motion by the CDU/CSU and the FDP to postpone the vote until Friday.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Federal government does not abolish diesel subsidy for farmers </field>
<field name="text">The federal government has abandoned the plan to abolish the diesel subsidy for farmers. Farmers will be reimbursed 0.30 DM of the mineral oil tax per liter of diesel fuel starting in 2001. This amount represents 0.11 DM less than before.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Environment Ministry on the expansion of Grundremmingen nuclear power plant </field>
<field name="text">The Environment Ministry apparently intends to get involved in the process of expanding the Grundremmingen nuclear power plant. Environment Minister Juergen Trittin intends to ask Bavarian Environment Minister Werner Schnappauf not to grant permits for the time being.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Possible speaker change for 10th anniversary of the fall of the wall </field>
<field name="text">Bundestag President Wolfgang Thierse deems it possible that the list of speakers for the festivities surrounding the 10th anniversary of the fall of the wall could still be changed. The Greens had demanded that former GDR civil rights activists be permitted to make a speech. The Bundestag's Parliamentary Advisory Committee (Aeltestenrat) rejected the Greens' demand yesterday evening.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Berlin likely to continue to be governed by SPD and CDU </field>
<field name="text">The capital will most likely continue to be governed by a grand coalition of CDU and SPD. A slight majority at the state party conference of the SPD voted to begin negotiations with the CDU.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Exhibit on Wehrmacht atrocities temporarily closed </field>
<field name="text">The exhibit on crimes committed by the Wehrmacht during World War II is temporarily closed. The director of the Hamburg Institute for Social Research, Jan Philipp Reemtsma, announced that the exhibit would be shut down for three months, during which time some of the photographs would be replaced. Critics of the exhibit have pointed out that some pictures did not show the Wehrmacht committing crimes. Independent experts will examine the photos while the exhibit is closed to the public.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">European central bank increases interest rates </field>
<field name="text">The European Central Bank raised the interest rate for the first time since the introduction of the Euro. The ECB's council increased the main refinancing rate from 2.5 to 3 percent. The increase is intended to prevent rising inflation, however credit will also become more expensive. The decision was widely expected.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Trial against alleged members of Camorra postponed </field>
<field name="text">The trial in Regional Court of 10 alleged members of the Italian organized crime group Camorra was postponed shortly after it began. One of the attorneys protested that police officers were wearing their guns in the courtroom.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-04</field><field name="title">Bayern Muenchen and Hertha BSC advance in Champions League </field>
<field name="text">Bayern Muenchen and Hertha BSC have advanced to the next round in the Champions League. The team from Munich beat the Glasgow Rangers 1:0. Hertha BSC advanced despite a 0:2 loss to Chelsea London because AC Milan also lost 2:3 against Istanbul.  </field></doc></add>