<add><doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Greens Will Not Coalesce with PDS </field>
<field name="text">Coalescing with the PDS would be out of the question during the next few years, states leadership spokeswoman of Alliance 90/The Greens, Ms. Roestel.  The party congress of the Greens in Suhl gave an unambiguous signal concerning the year 1998, Ms. Roestel told the  MAGDEBURGER VOLKSSTIMME on Sunday.  To be sure, no decision could be reached at this time concerning the situation at the end of the millennium.  Ms. Roestel emphasized that the possibility that the PDS might change its outlook should not be ruled out.  The party should not be forced into playing the role of martyr, which the CDU did with its "red socks campaign."  The Coalition Greens member of the Bundestag, Mr. Poppe, declared that he would turn his back on his party in the event of a coalition with the PDS. To be sure, he considered such a coalition impossible, Mr. Poppe told the BERLINER MORGENPOST.  This was the reaction of the former DDR-citizens' rights advocate to delegates' Laengsfeld and other former DDR-Opponents' conversion to the CDU.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Ms. Suessmuth Rejects Charges </field>
<field name="text">President of Parliament Ms. Suessmuth has once again rejected charges that she used federal military planes for private travel.  In WELT AM SONNTAG, the CDU politician emphasizes that she sees no reason to distance herself from the statements she made previously.  She had availed herself of these planes only for official business.  Ms. Suessmuth stated that she had privately booked and paid for trips to Switzerland.  In connection with her flights abroad, she mentioned for the first time that there might be a campaign to do long term damage [to her reputation].  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Mr. Schaueble: No Reduction of Solidarity Surtax after 1998 </field>
<field name="text">According to the chairperson of the Union's parliamentary faction, Mr. Schaeuble,  as of now, the solidarity surtax will not be further reduced in 1998. During an interview with BILD AM SONNTAG, the CDU politician stated that there was much to say for not continuing the reduction of the solidarity surtax at the rate once considered possible.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Protestant Church Objects to Search of Parish Rooms </field>
<field name="text">The leadership of the Protestant Church [Evangelische Kirche] in Berlin-Brandenburg  has lodged a protest against the Prosecutor's Office search of parish rooms. The church leadership declared that this occurrence was a singular one in the history of the Federal Republic and constituted  the exacerbation of the State's  policies in regard to congregations which offered their protection to refugees in danger of deportation.  The action in Berlin at the beginning of December had been against the members of a congregational council who are said to have granted church asylum for a year to a Vietnamese person.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Major Fire In Munich's "Euroindustriepark" </field>
<field name="text">A major fire occurred in a warehouse of the European Industrial Park [Euroindustriepark] in the north of Munich. Evidently, the fire department had major problems in controlling the blaze.  Hours after its outbreak, the fire was not completely put out.  The flames also touched adjoining buildings.  The cause of the fire has not been determined as yet. Only after more than five hours,  was the leader of the fire fighters able to report that the fire was under control.  It still had not been put out at the time of this report. Replacements were requested in the morning for the 120 professional and volunteer fire fighters.  It has not been determined as yet why the fire broke out around 1:30 A.M. in the building measuring 5000 square meters.  At any rate, when the first fire fighters arrived, the flames, already several meters high, were already shooting out of the building which could not be entered a few minutes later because it was about to collapse.  The fire-proof walls failed to prevent the flames from spreading rapidly from the construction warehouse of a roofing company to the neighboring buildings.  At this time, the firefighters, using hoses among other devices, were able to combat the flames only from the outside.  It has not been determined when investigators from the Munich criminal police will be able to enter the site to investigate the cause of the fire.  The Munich fire department stated that damages will run in the millions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">Heavy Christmas Traffic Causes Traffic Jams </field>
<field name="text"> The heavy traffic caused by Christmas travel has created traffic jams, especially on the Bavarian highways. On the A8 from Munich to Salzburg, cars were stopped for 40 kilometers.  Long waiting lines are also formed at the border crossings.  The police does not expect the lines at the borders to be cleared before tomorrow.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-12-21</field><field name="title">The Weather </field>
<field name="text">In the northern half, mainly sunny; cloudy  to the south of the Moselle and Main, but occasional rain or snow, only in the upper Rhine region, as well as south of the Danube. Highs in the north around 21 degrees F.; in the south, 36F. Lows at night 32F to 5F.  Long range, until Tuesday: heavily overcast in the south and southwest and periods of rain or snow.  In the north, sunny, cloudy at times, generally, no precipitation.  </field></doc></add>