<add><doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">No agreement on pension reform in sight </field>
<field name="text">One day before the second talk on pension reforms between the governing coaition and the SPD, an agreement is not likely. The SPD's expert on social issues, Dressler, said his party would only participate in the talk as a token of good will. According to Dressler, there would only be formal negotations with the government parties if they give up plans to lower the old-age pension level from currently 70 to 64 percent. The SPD introduced its own pension plan, which includes a release of the pension insurance from unrelated payments and the extension of the group of contributors. The SPD design would include mandatory contributions from parttime workers, the self-employed and the so-called seemingly self-employed. The head of the FDP, Gerhardt, rejected this demand. Theo Waigel, finance minister and head of the CSU, called the SPD's position incomprehensible and asked the Social Democrats to compromise. He called the party's plan unsuitable and accused the SPD of using pensions as an election campaign topic. Waigel also said that basically he considered positive the willingness to compromise shown by individual SPD politicians over the past few days. Labor minister Bluem announced that he would fight for a compromise.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Jewish victims remembered on Holocaust Memorial Day </field>
<field name="text">On Holocaust Memorial Day, Israel remembered the six million Jewish victims murdered by the Nazis. In the morning, sirens went off all over Israel. Remembrance events were also organized in Hamburg and Berlin, where a 28-hour reading of the names of 55,000 murdered Jews from Berlin concluded.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Australia and Germany to increase cooperation </field>
<field name="text">Australia and Germany intend to increase cooperations and find joint solutions in environmental policies, an agreement reached by chancellor Kohl and the Australian prime minister Howard after a meeting in Canberra. The countries also signed an agreement on culture and science which will facilitate an increased exchange of scientists and scholars as well as a closer cooperation between universities in both countries. At a joint press conference, Kohl called on Australian businesses to invest in Germany.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">SPD demands reform of citizenship laws </field>
<field name="text">The Social Democrats intend to employ a parliamentary motion to force the governing coalition to introduce a bill on the reform of the nationality law by the end of the parliamentary term. The deputy chairman of the SPD parliamentary group, Schily, said that the government remained disgracefully indecisive and unable to act in this matter. He said that this inactiveness endangered internal peace because it prevented the integration of many aliens born in Germany. According to Schily, their naturalization should be facilitated and dual citizenship be accepted to a moderate extent. At the same time, the SPD demands a law to regulate immigration into Germany.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Schroeder says SPD should emphasize economic competence </field>
<field name="text">The minister president of Lower Saxony, Schroeder, called on the SPD to emphasize the party's competence in economic matters in the upcoming election campaign. Schroeder said in an interview that the party had to compete against the Christian Democrats on this issue. Citing the British elections, Schroeder warned against underestimating Chancellor Kohl, saying that Kohl was a much more dangerous opponent than John Major had been for the Labour Party.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Second round of arbitrations in construction industry </field>
<field name="text">Arbitrations continued in the collective bargaining dispute for workers in the German construction industry. Led by the CDU social politician Geissler, both sides entered a second round of negotiations to find a compromise. On the ZDF morning show Morgenmagazin, the industry's main negotiator Kuechler demanded a new direction but admitted it would not be easy to find a solution. While the construction workers' union IG Bau demands a 2.9 percent wage increase, the industry is set on enforcing a zero round in order to create new jobs. In the evening, negotiations were adjourned and will be resumed on Wednesday. The arbitrator said there were chances to come to an agreement.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Protests against discrimination of the disabled </field>
<field name="text">Several thousand disabled citizens all over Germany protested against discrimination. The focus of today's Day of the Disabled was on educational integration. The Kassel-based action group "Gemeinsam leben, gemeinsam lernen" (Live Together, Learn Together) emphasized that the frequent compulsory attendance of special schools is a discriminatory practice as defined by the Basic Law. These schools did not prepare students to lead independent lives.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Seehofer praises success of AIDS prevention </field>
<field name="text">Ten years after the introduction of the first prevention campaign, the federal minister of health, Seehofer, emphasized the successes in the fight against AIDS. Seehofer said that the apocalyptic scenarios had not become reality and that the federal government would continue to emphasize prevention because there still are no vaccines and true remedies. According to Seehofer, the campaign's results are positive. As late as the mideighties, estimates had put possible HIV infections in Germany at one million. In reality, 50,000 to 60,000 people have been infected since the outbreak of the epidemic. By the end of 1996, about 19,000 of those infected with HIV had developed AIDS and 14,000 had died. The annual infection rate is about 2,000. Seehofer called these numbers a success, saying that Germany ranked at the top in AIDS prevention worldwide.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Civil employees of Armed Forces end strike </field>
<field name="text">The labor dispute between civilian employees of the Allied Forces in Germany and their employers has been settled. According to the public employees' union  OeTV, the results of the strike ballot showed that almost 80 percent of the voters supported the proposed wage agreement. The OeTV said that the German employees' union DAG's ballot had also brought the necessary majority. 35,000 German employees of the Allies in Germany had been on strike since March 3.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">German industrial production declines </field>
<field name="text">In March, German industrial production suffered a considerable decline. According to the federal ministry of economy, production decreased by 2.3 percent compared to March 1996. In February, industrial production had grown by 2.2 percent and in January by 1 percent.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">SAP investigated for inside trading </field>
<field name="text">The software manufacturer SAP has agreed to cooperate fully with investigators regarding the suspicion of inside trading of the company's shares but said that so far there were no reasons to doubt the SAP employees' discretion. The public prosecutor in Frankfurt is investigating the southwestern German company's boards of directors and executives, examining whether internal information had been used for stock transactions, which has been illegal since 1994. SAP shares had lost almost 25 percent in value last October after profit increase predictions had not come true.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-05-05</field><field name="title">Large increases in turnover and profit for Volkswagen </field>
<field name="text">The Volkswagen corporation increased its turnover for the first quarter to almost 27 bio. marks, resulting in a profit of 172 mio. marks. According to the largest European car manufacturer, more than one million vehicles were delivered in the first three months of 1997. Increases in turnover and profit result almost exclusively from sales abroad. For Germany, the company reported a 5.2 percent decline in turnover.  </field></doc></add>