<add><doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">EU ambassadors condemn Bangemann's abrupt departure to Telefonica </field>
<field name="text">The ambassadors of the European Union have condemned the actions of EU Commissioner Bangemann, who is on a leave of absence. They criticized his behavior in taking a job with the Spanish telephone company Telefonica as ethically objectionable. Based on an initial legal examination however, a complaint against the FDP politician in the European Court would seem to have little chance of success. The EU ambassadors intend to continue their consultations tomorrow. Bangemann has been criticized for taking a job in an industry which he was until quite recently in charge of regulating. If a complaint is filed, the aim would be to revoke his EU pension. The German government, according to remarks by government spokesperson Heye, would cooperate in pursuing a European Court trial. FDP party leader Gerhardt said nobody in his party has any understanding or sympathy for Bangemann's behavior.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">Taxes on capital life insurance profits to start only at end of year </field>
<field name="text">Profits from capital life insurance will now only be taxed starting at the end of this year. The word from the Ministry of Finance is that the original retroactive date that would have been applied to new contracts, June 22, is no longer being considered. The date is now planned to be the day that the new tax law goes into effect. This should be toward the end of the year.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">Schroeder and private sector establish "Germany 21" initiative </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Schroeder, in conjunction with the private sector, wants to promote information technology in Germany. To this end, Schroeder and the heads of 70 companies have created the initiative "Germany 21". The goal of the initiative is, among other things, to enable easier access to the Internet and to assist children and young people in gaining familiarity with computers. The Chancellor pointed out that the information technology industry has a shortage of 80,000 skilled laborers.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">Lufthansa cargo jet crashes in Nepal </field>
<field name="text">A Lufthansa cargo jet crashed shortly after takeoff from the Nepalese capital of Kathmandu. According to Lufthansa headquarters in Frankfurt am Main, the 5 member crew of the Boeing 727 consisted of 4 Indians and 1 American. Nepalese police report their fate is unknown. Rescue teams are on their way to the mountain crash site. The aircraft belonged to a subsidiary of Lufthansa which operates out of India.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">US air base in Frankfurt am Main shifts to Rhineland-Palatinate </field>
<field name="text">German and American authorities have finally come to an agreement regarding the move of the US air base in Frankfurt am Main to Rhineland-Palatinate. State Premier Beck of Rhineland-Palatinate said the negotiations were a great success. As a result of the forthcoming departure of the Americans from the Frankfurt airport, the bases Ramstein in the Palatinate and Spangdalen in the Eiffel region will be enlarged. Beck estimates this will bring nearly 600 million DM in investments to the region.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">Government postpones atomic energy talks until September </field>
<field name="text">The federal government apparently sees no possibility for a rapid settlement of the controversy surrounding the abandonment of nuclear power generation. A high level meeting of the federal government coalition partners, the SPD and the Greens, was called off on short notice. Government spokesperson Heye explained that a working group at the undersecretary level now has until September 30th to come up with a solution for a compensation free exit strategy. The Ministry for the Environment will take the leadership role. Ministers Trittin (Environment) and Mueller (Economy) have publicly contested the timetable for the abandonment of atomic energy. Trittin insists that some atomic power plants must be taken off line prior to the next federal elections in 2002.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-07</field><field name="title">Germany to participate in international police force for Kosovo </field>
<field name="text">Germany intends to participate in the international police force in Kosovo with a force of 210 police. This was announced by government spokesperson Heye after a cabinet meeting in Bonn. These units will protect returning refugees and will help the province to establish its own independent police force. In addition, 60 German investigators and forensic pathologists will assist with the investigation of war crimes in Kosovo.  </field></doc></add>