<add><doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Federal government regrets bombardment of the Chinese embassy </field>
<field name="text">The federal government in Bonn expressed its regret over the destruction of the Chinese embassy in Belgrade by NATO.  However, Under Secretary Wichert also pointed out that, with the high number of sorties -- the count so far is approximately 17,000 -- technical and human error can never be completely avoided.  In a letter to Chinese prime minister, Zhu Rongji, Chancellor Schroeder, said that he regretted the bombardment of the embassy, and that the incident is the result of the inhuman policies of the Belgrade government. 4 people were killed and at least 5 injured in the attack.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Schroeder meets with Chernomyrdin and Rugova </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Schroeder is meeting with Viktor Chernomyrdin, the Russian special Balkan envoy, and the UN ambassador in Bonn.  They intend to discuss the situation in the Balkans.  Schroeder then plans to meet with the political leader of the Kosovo Albanians, Ibrahim Rugova.  Before leaving for Germany, Rugova declared that NATO should continue its air strikes on Yugoslavia.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Ruehe to compete with Heide Simonis next year </field>
<field name="text">Acting CDU chair Volker Ruehe has been elected by his party as the top candidate for the Schleswig-Holstein regional elections in February 2000. The former minister of defense received 96% of the votes cast at the CDU regional convention in the seaside town of Damp.  Ruehe will now be challenging Heide Simonis, the state leader of the SPD.  Ruehe emphasized in his speech to the delegates that he would not be available to run as a candidate for chancellor should the CDU take control of the government in Kiel. Instead, he wants to finish his entire parliamentary term as Minister President.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Riester: no changes in the law regarding 630 DM jobs </field>
<field name="text">Federal Minister of Labour Riester appears unyielding in the debate around the "630 DM jobs" law. In an interview with "BILD am Sonntag," Riester said that he sees no reason to change the law.  However, he did not rule out changes and amendments to the new law on nominally independent contract work, which is just as controversial. Riester rejected possible nullification of the laws, which are also being criticized within the party, or his resignation as Federal Minister of Labour.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Morsleben can not yet be shut down due to radioactive nuclear waste </field>
<field name="text">According to the news magazine "Der Spiegel," the permanent nuclear waste disposal site at Morsleben can not be shut down for the time being. Apparently nuclear waste that is giving off too much radiation is being stored in the underground salt mine. The containers from the Greifswald nuclear power station should apparently remain in Morsleben despite the radioactive emissions. The authorities feel that the radiation level will eventually decline enough to allow permanent disposal of the waste.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-05-08</field><field name="title">Soccer: It is still not certain that Bayern will be the champion </field>
<field name="text">In the German soccer league, the champagne bottles at FC Bayern Muenchen will have to remain unopened until tomorrow.  After a 2:0 victory against Bochum, pursuer Leverkusen is still theoretically in the race for the title.  The Bavarians still need 1 point in tomorrow's game against Herta BSC Berlin.  </field></doc></add>