<add><doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">Schroeder reproaches Russian action in Chechnya </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Schroeder voiced an oblique reproach of Russia's use of force in Chechnya. During a meeting of the Inter-parliamentary Union, he said: "War ought not to be the answer to terrorism." He continued saying that Russia, too, was bound to honor its commitments as a member of the Organization for European Security and Co-operation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">Preliminary Berlin election returns </field>
<field name="text">According to preliminary official reports on yesterday's Berlin state elections, CDU can book a gain of 3.4%, with 40.8% of the vote as against 37.4 in the preceding elections. SPD dropped 1.2% from 23.6% to 22.4%. Third place was gained by PDS with 17.7% of the vote, a gain of more than 3%. The Greens lost 3.3%, attaining a total of 9.9%. FDP received 2.2% and is again out of the running. Next week will show whether the grand coalition will continue governing the city-state. Eberhard Diepgen, sitting Lord Mayor and election winner, has already extended an offer to the SPD, but the answer - whether SPD will choose governing or acting as opposition -will come pending consultations within the party leadership.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">Gerhardt aspires to stay on as FDP boss </field>
<field name="text">FDP boss Gerhardt aspires to remain in place despite the recent electoral setback in Berlin. He said today that he would stay on as party leader and would also stand for the position as faction leader on Oct. 26th. During a leadership meeting today he met criticism but also gained wide support. The FDP intends to work a comeback, under Gerhardt's leadership, after 5 successive electoral defeats. Pundits say that the fate of both the party and of its leader will be determined by the outcome of the spring elections in Schleswig-Holstein an North Rhine-Westphalia.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">Schroeder felicitates Nobel laureate for medicine </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Schroeder wired his congratulations to the new winner of the Nobel prize for medicine. In the telegram, he said that the biologist with his brilliant research work had decisively contributed to the understanding of human hereditary diseases. His trail-blazing discoveries in the protein area were immensely significant for modern medical research. Blobel was born in Waltersdorf, Silesia, and became a US citizen about 12 years ago.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">Lafontaine will continue to meddle in politics </field>
<field name="text">On launching his controversial volume of memoirs, former SPD boss Lafontaine announced that he pretends to continue meddling in politics. He said his concern was the direction social democracy would take in Europe. He intends to participate in the debate on the SPD's fundamentals. Schleswig-Holstein's state premier Ms. Simonis challenged Lafontaine to justify his scathing judgment on chancellor Schroeder during the December party convention.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">DGB opens festivities for 50th anniversary </field>
<field name="text">With a call to close ranks, DGB [German trade union confederation] boss Schulte opened the festivities around the DGB's 50th anniversary. The fight for more jobs and social justice would continue to be the organization's central issue. Those who want progress must be willing to carry people along, Schulte said. Bavaria's minister for social issues, Ms. Stamm, said that the unions had decisively contributed to make the German model of social market economy exemplary on a world scale.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">German railway co. under fire for monopoly abuses </field>
<field name="text">Action has been brought by the federal anti-trust office against the German railway co. Deutsche Bahn AG for abusive manipulation of their monopoly status. A spokesman for the anti-trust office confirmed a report by radio Suedwestfunk in which competitors complained against the Deutsche Bahn's abuse of monopoly status. Private railway companies and other service providers accused the company of granting its own affiliates prices well below those practiced with third parties. A spokesman for the Railway co. denied the accusation that they were virtually blackmailing their competitors.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-10-11</field><field name="title">No proof of Eid's guilt in asylant haven arson case </field>
<field name="text">During the re-trial of Safran Eid, accused of having set fire to a Luebeck asylant haven, no evidence of guilt have been found. The re-trial was ordered by the federal high court after Eid had been acquitted in the original trial, on the grounds that not all existing evidence had been produced. 10 persons died in the fire in early 1996.  </field></doc></add>