<add><doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Floods spread to Brandenburg </field>
<field name="text">The floods on the River Oder are now also threatening Brandenburg. According to the Ministry for the Environment, the areas most at risk are the region around Eisenhuettenstadt and the Oder marshes.  In Frankfurt the crisis committee is expecting river levels to reach a new high of 6.50 meters around tomorrow lunchtime.  That would be 15 cm higher than the floods of 1930, the highest so far this century.  Evacuations are at present not planned, since most districts lie above the level of the expected flood.  In Ratzdorf at the confluence of the Rivers Oder and Neisse near the Polish border, the first dike has already been breached. Relief workers struggled in vain to raise the level of the dike with sandbags.  A level 4 flood alert has been issued for the Oder/Spree district.  The River Oder has risen almost 50 cm since this morning.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Technical Relief Agency steps up work in flooded regions </field>
<field name="text">The Technical Relief Agency has stepped up its work in the flooded regions of Poland.  The organization announced in Bonn that measures to safeguard drinking-water supplies are to be extended by another two weeks.  In addition, a further team of 30 experts has been sent to Breslau.  The number of people who have fallen victim to the floods has meanwhile risen to 46.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Hanseatic towed free </field>
<field name="text">The cruise ship Hanseatic which ran aground outside Spitzbergen was towed free early this morning.  Previously, all 145 passengers, most of them German tourists, were transferred to a Norwegian coastguard's tug.  The Hanseatic's hull will now be examined by divers for possible damage.  If there are no problems, the ship should be able to continue its journey to Spitzbergen docks unaided.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">German-Austrian-Italian meeting re: Schengen Agreement </field>
<field name="text">This evening saw the start of a meeting between the heads of government and the Interior Ministers of Germany, Austria and Italy regarding the Schengen Agreement.  Discussions will focus on a step-by-step plan for the lifting of border controls between the three countries.  The governments in Rome and Vienna have long been pressing for full membership of the Schengen Agreement and for the abolition of border controls on their EU-internal borders.  Germany, however, had expressed concerns about the security implications of such a step.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Nolte on official visit to Japan </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Minister for the Family, Claudia Nolte, has arrived in Japan for a week-long stay.  In Tokyo Ms. Nolte will visit a women's support center as well as an retirement home.  A meeting with former participants of the German-Japanese youth exchange is also planned.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">VW recalls vehicles </field>
<field name="text">Volkswagen is recalling 12,000 of its Sharan sedan model.  The 5-point seat-belt restraint system for children's seats is not functioning correctly.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Travel agent deceives customers </field>
<field name="text">A travel agent has deceived hundreds of holiday-makers.  The firm Travelservice specialized in budget long distance trips and other cheap travel offers.  The catch with the cheap offers was that they always had to be paid for in advance.  It seems that in many cases the proceeds were insufficient for the travel agency to pay the tour operators.  Many customers paid, without ever receiving their travel documents.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-07-17</field><field name="title">Tennis: Becker pulls out of second round match in Stuttgart </field>
<field name="text">Boris Becker has pulled out of the Weissenhof tournament in Stuttgart. He was unable to compete in his second round match because of a calf injury.  </field></doc></add>