<add><doc><field name="date">1998-07-11</field><field name="title">Kinkel arrives in Moscow to discuss Kosovo crisis </field>
<field name="text">Federal Foreign Minister Kinkel has arrived in Moscow to consult with his Russian counterpart Primakov on the Kosovo crisis.  He briefed Primakov on his latest visit to the region.  Prior to the meeting, Kinkel said he intended to obtain Russia's consent for a military intervention in the conflict, if necessary even over the objections of Yugoslavia.  Kinkel suggested that Moscow should use its leverage over Belgrade to effect a cease fire and to reopen a dialogue between the warring parties.  Russia, however, continues to oppose a military NATO intervention in Kosovo and is insisting on a diplomatic solution. Nonetheless, Kinkel has reported that new proposals for defusing the conflict are being discussed.  These have to be considered by the other western allies, and Kinkel did not give any details.  Despite all efforts to restore peace in the region, the fighting continues.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-11</field><field name="title">Schroeder supports juvenile detention centers </field>
<field name="text">The SPD candidate for Chancellor, Mr. Schroeder, has come out in favor of detaining juvenile criminals in closed correction facilities.  On Norddeutscher Rundfunk radio, Schroeder said crimes are being committed at younger and younger age.  Hence, more drastic measures are called for. The crimes committed by some juvenile are so severe in their nature that closed facilities are needed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-11</field><field name="title">NPD protest march in Chemnitz </field>
<field name="text">Some 500 followers of the right-wing extremist party NPD staged a protest march in Chemnitz under police escort. The protestors demanded that the German mark be retained and that preference be given to German nationals in the distribution of jobs.  The Saxon police accompanied the extremists and controlled the march.  Shortly before the beginning of the demonstration, the police took several people into custody.  No details are known.  Early in the morning, police set up checkpoints on all access roads into the city.  Cars and buses were stopped and searched for illicit material and weapons.  Immediately prior to the NPD event, there was a counter-demonstration against racial hatred and intolerance.  They formed a chain of people 3 kilometers long.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-07-11</field><field name="title">10th Love Parade in Berlin </field>
<field name="text">Some 600,000 fans of techno music have gathered in downtown Berlin for the 10th Love Parade.  The organizers expect the number of participants to surpass one million.  In two separate parades with 50 floats apiece, the fans are moving to the Siegessaeule where the final concert will take place.  </field></doc></add>