<add><doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">BfA: Pensions will continue to remain secure </field>
<field name="text">According to the Federal Social Insurance Office for Salaried Employees (BfA), pensions in the future will continue to remain secure. The president of the BfA, Rische, said in an interview that the present old-age pension insurance system has been in existance and functioning for 100 years. With necessary and sensible adjustments, it will continue to function for another 100 years. Further, he said that to date there had been no practical alternative which could have made possible a transition to a new system for one, and that was affordable, for another. In addition, the costs of the proposed basic federal pension have at this stage not been precisely calculated. The BfA estimates, however, that a basic pension system would cost more than the revenue earned from sales tax. Mr Rische said, furthermore, that he rejects the notion that pensions should be privately financed. The consensus remains that the workforce carries the responsibility for financing old-age pensions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Economic and financial policies criticised </field>
<field name="text">The chairman of the board of the Deutsche Bank, Kopper, has criticised the German government's economic and financial policies according to a report in the newspaper "Welt am Sonntag". Mr. Kopper said in a talk in January to CDU and SPD politicians in Bonn that there is a lack of coordination between the responsible ministries. The economics portfolio did not contain enough impetus or initiative. As far as financial policy is concerned, Mr Kopper also rejects drastic austerity measures. He considers the goal of leading politicians' to halve unemployment by the year 2000 to be unrealistic.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Considerations regarding essential health-care benefits </field>
<field name="text">Statutory health insurance is to continue to pay for massages, private nursing and a number of preventative measures. However, the criteria for establishing medical necessity will be stricter said a health-care spokesman for the CDU/CSU, Lohmann, to the newspaper "Bild am Sonntag". According to Mr Lohmann, health insurances, doctors and professional organizations had got together to determine which treatments were applicable for which illnesses. Certain medication and treatments will not generally be paid for by health insurance, rather only when they are considered effective according to the newly defined schedule of benefits.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Sudeten German Association against German-Czech declaration </field>
<field name="text">The Sudeten German Association wanted to close their two-day national conference in Munich today with a manifesto against the German-Czech declaration of reconciliation. In their statement, the association upheld their "No" to the declaration. The draft proposal accuses the government in Bonn and Munich of having abandoned the exiles.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Wilhelm calls for improved protection of children </field>
<field name="text">The CDU member of parliament, Wilhelm, wants to better protect children against criminal acts by the use of mini-transmitters. He said to the newspaper "Bild am Sonntag" that such transmitters could be hidden in childrens' schoolbooks, clothing or jewellery. If kidnapped, the children could then be more easily traced. Greater protection could be attained by implanting electronic microchips under the skin. The Federal Minister of Research has promised to look into Mr Wilhelm's idea.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Final phase of the carnival season commences </field>
<field name="text">The final phase for the carnival season have begun in the traditional carnival regions of Baden-Wuerttemberg. Hundreds of thousands of spectators are expected to view carnival processions in the numerous towns and villages between the river Main and Lake Constance. In Mannheim alone over 300,000 spectators are expected at the wineland carnival processions. Large processions, some of which have a long tradition, have already taken place in the town centres of Konstanz, Schwennigen, Donaueschingen, Rottenburg, Neuhausen auf den Fildern and Karlsruhe/Durlach.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-02-09</field><field name="title">Weather report </field>
<field name="text">Clouds and scattered showers in the north. Sunshine in the south. Highs between 4 and 12 degrees Celsius. Night-time lows from -4 to 5 degrees Celsius.  </field></doc></add>