<add><doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">Kohl comments on Taxes and Chechnya </field>
<field name="text">German Chancellor Helmut Kohl called the reducing of tax burdens the most important goal of the planned large scale tax reform. Interviewed by ZDF TV, he said  the goal was mandated by the individual citizens' interests and the desire to stimulate the economy. Kohl also called for an end to the discussion about the timetable and financing of the reform and criticized the coalition partner FDP. Kohl explained that the Liberals (FDP) had not made a single suggestion how to realize their  demands for the enactment of the reform by 1998 already. Kohl called on Russian President Yeltsin to find a way to end the war in Chechnya. The Chancellor said he would call Yeltsin upon his return from vacationing, the middle of the month. Kohl expressed his sympathies for the endeavours through negotiations by Russian security advisor Lebed. Kohl didn't comment on him possibly running for Chancellor again in the 1998 elections. He assumed that SPD and Greens would join with the PDS to replace the governing coalition. The CDU should try to win over potential PDS voters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">Ruehe meets French counterpart </field>
<field name="text">German Minister of Defense Volker Ruehe met in the French Alps with his counterpart in the French government to talk about common armament projects. The talks were about future cooperations in the face of the French military reforms. During recent cutbacks, both countries had agreed to scrutinize joint projects . France will abolish conscription by the year 2001 and establish a professional army of 350,000 soldiers.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">German companies provided illegal aid to Lybia. </field>
<field name="text">Two German companies from Moenchengladbach are suspected of illegally delivering high tech installations to Lybia. According to Suedwestfunk Radio, these could be used to manufacture poison gas and chemical warfare agents. ARD TV investigations showed that the installations were transported to Lybia between November 1991 and July 1993. Two leading employees of the companies were arrested August 9. According to the Duesseldorf customs investigations department, the deal was worth several million DM.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">German President denies newspaper reports </field>
<field name="text">The German President's office called a report by the "Bild am Sonntag" newspaper wrong that had speculated about a possible second term of German President Roman Herzog. There were no grounds for such considerations, a speaker for the office said in Bonn. So far, Herzog has always refused running for a second time. Chancellor Kohl, in a ZDF TV interview, had previously voiced his opinion that this topic was not up for public discussion. Herzog, 62, was voted for the five year-term of German President in 1994.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">Protestant church commemorates Oskar Bruesewitz </field>
<field name="text">The Protestant church of Sachsen today commemorated Oskar Bruesewitz, a priest in the former DDR who 20 years ago burnt himself to death. Bishop Dehmke said that this act of desperation was on one hand a indictment of the repressive system of the DDR [the former East Germany] and on the other hand criticism of a church that supposedly had tied itself too closely to the State. Out of protest against the political conditions in the DDR, Bruesewitz on August 18, 1976 had poured gasoline over his body and set himself on fire in front of the church in Zeitz.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">Traffic reports often jammed </field>
<field name="text">According to the German car drivers association ADAC, reports of traffic jams are often wrong. The ADAC reported that one out of five reports of traffic jams in the police computer is outdated. Also, 30% to 40% of all traffic problems would not even register there.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-08-18</field><field name="title">Vogts calls disciples to order </field>
<field name="text">Berti Vogts, coach of the German soccer team finally made his voice heard in the battle of words between players from the dominant Bundesliga teams. In a "Bild am Sonntag" interview, he threatened to expel all players from Borussia Dortmund and Bayern Muenchen from the national team. "They better put their feet on the ball instead of in their mouths", he noted.  </field></doc></add>