<add><doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Unions calling for defeat of red-green coalition in Hesse </field>
<field name="text">Members of the CDU and CSU parties have called for a defeat of the red-green coalition at the state assembly election in Hesse. Bavaria's State Premier Stoiber and his colleagues from Baden-Wuerttemberg and Thueringia, Mr Teufel and Mr Vogel, supported a change in power in Wiesbaden. The top candidate of the CDU, Mr Koch, is supposed to replace the social democrat Mr Eichel as chief of government. The election has importance throughout the states because the intention is to break the SPD's majority in the Bundesrat, said Mr Stoiber. He also turned against dual citizenship as a normal case. Mr Koch thinks that in case of a success for the CDU, the social democrats will renegotiate this topic.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Gesamtmetall decides on wage increase close to 3% </field>
<field name="text">In negotiations between union workers and their bosses, Gesamtmetall- President Stumpfe decided on a 3% maximum wage increase. He claimed more would be impossible. The IG Metall, one of the country's most influential unions, accused the employers of extortion. IG Metall Vice-President Peters said the employers threatened to burst the alliance if the union did not comply. The IG Metall said it would not allow being blackmailed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Dresden Bank offered loans to Auschwitz concentration camp </field>
<field name="text">The Dresden Bank helped to finance the construction of the concentration camp in Auschwitz. The company announced that their branch office in Kattowitz in Upper-Schlesien had granted loans for construction services.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Federal High Court rules regarding bargain offers </field>
<field name="text">When a company advertises bargains, a customer can assume that these goods are offered in sufficient quantities. If that is not the case, the company is acting in unfair competition, ruled the Federal High Court today. In the current case, the MediaMarkt TV-HiFi-Elektro GmbH offered a mini PC tower for DM 2000 in one of their flyers. When a competition's test customer asked for it after 13 days, the computer was not available. The case is considered a guideline for the consumer: The buyer may expect to see the goods in the store for one week after reading the flyer over the weekend.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">British military plane crashes next to autobahn </field>
<field name="text">A British military plane crashed into a field in Wesel and burst into flames next to the autobahn. Both pilots were saved by ejector seat, one of them was injured and taken to the hospital.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Objection denied in head-scarf case </field>
<field name="text">The Muslim teacher applicant Ludin is still not allowed to teach in Baden-Wuerttemberg. The Higher State Board of Education in Stuttgart denied her objection. The Board sees the neutrality of the state and the educational rights of the parents in danger.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Lawsuit against former Gestapo man </field>
<field name="text">The Regional Court in Stuttgart started a lawsuit against a former Gestapo member accused of murder and accessory to murder in several ten thousand cases. Alfons G. volunteered for the German Wehrmacht in 1942. Later he was a member of the security police in Loblin in Poland. The sentence accuses the 79-year-old man of participating in a mass murder. 17,000 people were shot during the "Aktion Erntedankfest" (Campaign Harvest Festival) in the concentration camp Meindanek in 1943. Alfons G. is accused of shooting 500 people himself, and then loading the guns again. Accessory to murder of additional 45,000 people is under investigation. An expert opinion will show whether the 79-year-old man can be trialed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-02-04</field><field name="title">Schily unsatisfied with doping decisions in Lausanne </field>
<field name="text">Federal Minister of the Interior Schily criticised the decisions made at the World-Doping-Conference in Lausanne as insufficient. The planned suspension of 2 years for doping offences is not long enough, considering the fact that it includes exceptions which have not been put in concrete terms. According to Mr Schily only a harsh penalty by law would cause prevention.  </field></doc></add>