<add><doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Lassing rescue team hopes to rescue survivors tonight </field>
<field name="text">The rescue team in Lassing believes that it will be able to bring the ten missing miners to safety by tomorrow morning.  Austrian television quoted a fireman as saying, "Tonight something amazing will happen, just wait and see."  Drilling on the mine shaft where the accident took place was resumed in the afternoon. An additional seven meters of the rescue shaft must be completed in order to reach the bunker where the ten miners are believed to be located. Although the victims have shown no outward signs of life, the Lassing team is optimistic that they will rescue survivors. It has been determined that oxygen is circulating in the underground bunker.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Smuggling of illegal aliens is on the rise </field>
<field name="text">The number of foreigners smuggled into Germany has dramatically increased. This is according to the Federal Minister of the Interior, Mr. Kanther, in an interview with the newspaper "Welt am Sonntag." In the first half of 1998, almost twice as many foreigners crossed the borders into Germany illegally as in the previous year. The number of cases where they were discovered by authorities climbed from 64 to 97. The main border illegal aliens are being smuggled across is the one between Germany and the Czech Republic. Mr. Hadrat, the Minister of the Interior of Saxony, is demanding more effective cooperation with the Polish and Czech authorities. The 46 Afghanis who were taken into custody yesterday in Wuerzburg were sent back to the Czech Republic.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Fire in Telekom office causes telephone chaos </field>
<field name="text">There was total chaos in Reutlingen and its surrounding areas yesterday, and approximately 72,000 telephones are still out of service.  Telephone service will probably be restored on Monday at the earliest. The reason behind the pandemonium was a major fire in a Telekom communications office in Reutlingen. One fireman was injured while extinguishing the fire. It was not only telephone service was brought to a halt; automatic bank tellers are not working, and cable television and radio stations are broadcasting only test patterns. The police and fire departments have set up contact stations throughout the city, should they need to be reached in an emergency.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Prisoner rapes daughter while on prison furlough </field>
<field name="text">A 30 year-old prisoner raped his 6 year-old daughter in Oldenburg, Lower Saxony while on a week-long prison furlough. An individual walking through the woods witnessed the suspect committing the sexual act. The 30 year-old man, who is serving a prison sentence of many years, threatened the witness with a knife and then fled with the child to her mother's apartment. The prisoner then dropped his daughter off and disappeared. The suspect was taken into police custody today.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Formula 1: Michael Schumacher only fourth in qualifying time </field>
<field name="text">MacLaren-Mercedes's "Silver Arrow" is starting in the first row at the German Grand Prix in Hockenheim. The Finnish world championship leader, Mika Haekinnen, drove the fastest qualifying time and will be in the pole position tomorrow. His Scottish teammate, Coulthard, came in second ahead of world champion Villeneuf of Canada. The best German driver was Ralf Schumacher, who finished fourth. Michael Schumacher ended up only in ninth place.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1998-08-01</field><field name="title">Tour de France: Ullrich wins stage and is now second </field>
<field name="text">Jan Ullrich has won the next-to-last stage of the Tour de France. A victory in the time trial brought Ullrich to the number two position in the overall standings. Last year's winner is 3 minutes 21 seconds behind the Italian Marco Pantani.  </field></doc></add>