<add><doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">SPD demands new elections in Hessen </field>
<field name="text">When the financial scandal of the CDU in Hessen became known, the SPD-opposition demanded new elections. The party executive committee of the SPD met at noon in Wiesbaden to decide on a request of distrust. The SPD-leader in Hessen and Federal Finance Minister, Eichel, said that the cabinet of Mr. Koch had lost its right to govern the country. He demanded new elections, because the election campaign last spring had been financed from unclear sources. But observers do not expect an early end of the era "Koch", because the red-green opposition has a lack of two seats in the Parliament. But the whole CDU is in a very bad mood and the scandal still has not been cleared up. If Koch had known from the financial scandal in his party, it is not very likely that he will keep his job.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Prosecuting attorney investigates CDU-scandal in Hessen </field>
<field name="text">The public prosecutor's office in Wiesbaden had started investigations concerning the CDU-financial scandal, because of the suspicion of unfaithfulness and fraud. The suspicion facts aim at the former CDU-treasurer in Hessen, Sein-Wittgenstein (sp?) and the former CDU-financial consultant, Weihrauch. At the same time, several CDU-/CSU-politicians like the CSU-chairman, Stoiber, and the CDU-leader in Brandenburg, Schoenbohm, asked the former country chairman of Hessen, Kanther, to withdraw from Politics. The former Minister of the Interior is still a member of the Bundestag.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Financial scandal may cause personnel consequences </field>
<field name="text">The CDU-secretary general, Angela Merkel, demanded personnel consequences as a result of the financial donations scandal. On television, she said that this should be the consequences at the end of the party internal investigation. The CDU has been hit right in its position as a member of the constitutional state. The federal deputy chairman, Wulff, declared that in case of emergency also party exclusion has to be discussed. The state premier and leader of the CDU in Hessen, Koch, can not exclude a connection between extra-accounts of the long standing CDU-chairman, Kohl, and the millions of the regional CDU-group hidden abroad. As far he knows, the tax advisor, Weihrauch, has also documents concerning the moneys of the CDU in Hessen.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Eppelmann: Other Parties should join the investigation committee </field>
<field name="text">According to the chairman of the CDU-social executive committee, Eppelmann, representatives of other parties should join the expert investigation committee. In the "Neue Osnabruecker Zeitung", Eppelmann mentioned the Vice President of the Bundestag, Vollmer, from the Greens and Mr. Schroeder, a Theologian and Social Democrat. So far, the committee only consists of the former German President, Herzog, the former chairman of the German Central Bank, Tietmeyer, and the former constitutional judge, Kirchhof.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Daeubler-Gmelin demands resignation of CDU-executive committee </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Minister of Justice, Daeubler-Gmelin, wants asked the Federal Executive Committee of the CDU to resign. Daeubler-Gmelin said on television that the CDU/CSU should elect a provisional executive committee, if they want to clear up the financial scandal. Additionally, all obligations for secrecy and confidentiality must be declared void.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Schroeder wants the Gauck-authority to continue its work </field>
<field name="text">Federal Chancellor Schroeder wants the Gauck-authority to continue its work to clear up the activities of the GDR-Secret service for a longer time. Schroeder said during a visit of the authority in Berlin, that the processing of the Stasi-files is still in the beginning. Schroeder added that the results should also be part of the political education.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Stuttgart 21 once again more probably </field>
<field name="text">It seems as if the construction of the project "Stuttgart 21" and a rapid-transit railway to Ulm is more probably. According to a speaker of the Ministry of State in Stuttgart, the project had reached a decisive stage because of the high-level conference in Berlin between Chancellor Schroeder and the State Premier of Baden-Wuerttemberg, Teufel. Schroeder confirmed the State's financial promise of 886 millions. But the total is still under budget reservation.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">No advantages of Raps oil compared with normal diesel oil </field>
<field name="text">According to the Federal Department for the Environment, diesel extracted from Raps oil has no decisive advantage compared with normal diesel. If all cultivation areas are used for planting Raps, diesel from Raps oil would cover only half a percent of the whole demand. The money used for the subsidies could better be spent for more effective ways to reduce the amount of carbon dioxide, which does a lot of damage to the environment. Furthermore the Federal Department for the Environment pointed out that the processing of Raps to diesel oil consumes energy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Swindlers caused financial damage to companies with fictive bills </field>
<field name="text">Swindler used mailbox companies to deceive about 20,000 companies. According to the public prosecutor's office in Frankfurt, two groups of swindlers sent their victims, mostly big companies, fictive bills for supposed entries in address lists. They even used the protected logo of the Deutsche Telekom. The financial damage in total is about 12 million DEM. The swindlers found the addresses and company portraits in the internet. There they also found the official file numbers used for the fraud. With this information, the public prosecutor's office in Frankfurt confirmed a report of television magazine "Report".  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Two escapees from prison Rheinbach caught </field>
<field name="text">Two of four escapees from the prison Rheinbach had been caught. The police is looking for the other two in North Rhine-Westphalia and in Rhineland-Palatine. One of them is a convicted murderer. The four prisoners escaped by the roof of the carpenter's workshop of the prison.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">2000-01-17</field><field name="title">Football: Babbel goes to Liverpool </field>
<field name="text">At the end of this season, Markus Babbel will leave the FC Bayern Muenchen and go to the FC Liverpool. Today, the English traditional club confirmed, that Babbel had signed a 4-year-contract  </field></doc></add>