<add><doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Snow and ice hamper clean-up after hurricane Lothar </field>
<field name="text">Snow and icy roads obstructed traffic in most parts of Baden Wuerttemberg. Up to 40 cm of fresh snow fell in the Black Forest. This also hampers the clean-up after hurricane Lothar.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Possibly investigations against Kohl because of donations affaire </field>
<field name="text">An investigation against former CDU president Helmut Kohl because of not declared party donations is coming closer. This evening, the prosecution has not yet decided whether to start investigations. A spokesperson for the prosecution said that any [circulating] information about imminent investigations did not originate from the prosecutor's office.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Nuclear fuel containers need new coating </field>
<field name="text">Nuclear fuel casks (CASTORs) in the intermediary storage facility in Ahaus are rusting. Now, they must be sanded and get a new coat of paint. The economics ministry of North Rhine-Westphalia stated that there was no danger for the painters.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Extra pay for work on Sundays to remain tax-free </field>
<field name="text">The extra pay for work at night, on Sundays, and on public holidays is to remain tax free. Spokespersons of SPD and Buendnis90/Gruene said the government parties had always rejected the taxation of this extra pay.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Gasoline and diesel prices increase significantly </field>
<field name="text">The prices per litre for gasoline and diesel are now just under 2 DM. Gas increased by 0.04 DM, diesel by 0.05 DM. In addition, there will be a 0.07 DM eco-tax as of January 1, 2000.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Police apprehend two teenage burglar gangs </field>
<field name="text">Police have apprehended two gangs of burglars. One group had seven members and was headed by a 12-year-old. The other gang consisted of five boys aged between 14 and 17 years. The teenagers allegedly burglarized apartments and shops in series.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-28</field><field name="title">Police search for escaped prisoner in Brandenburg </field>
<field name="text">An escaped prisoner is searched in Brandenburg. A 29-year-old murderer did not return to the Brandenburg-Havel prison after his prison holiday. The man is considered dangerous.  </field></doc></add>