<add><doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Economic research institutes predict slower growth </field>
<field name="text">The six leading economic research institutes have presented their spring forecasts for the German economy. The experts expect reduced economic growth. They predict that the German economy will grow by 2.25 percent. Last fall their prediction was still 2.5 percent. The experts also predict an average of 4.3 million unemployed, that is 300,000 more than in 1996. This contrasts with government predictions of 4.1 million unemployed for 1997. The institutes criticize the indecisive tax debate. There was no clear direction detectable, this was one reason why investors waited with their decisions. Quick decisions in tax politics could improve the German tax climate.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Comments on economic spring forecast </field>
<field name="text">Finance Minister Theo Waigel stated that the spring forecast showed the conditions for an economic upswing remained bad. The federal government would do everything to reduce the deficit to 3.0 percent of the gross national product and meet the criteria to join monetary union. According to forecasts by economic research institutes, Germany will miss the deficit criterion by 0.2 percent. They assume, however, that Germany will join the European Monetary Union at its start in 1999 even though it may miss the criteria by a small margin.  Economics Minister Guenther Rexrodt said the reforms must be put into action as quickly as possible. The SPD spokesperson for economic policy, Mr. Schwanholt (sp?), however called the forecast a slap in the face of Finance Minister Theo Waigel. The prognosis of 2.25 percent growth rejected unmistakably the government's window dressing. The Social-Democrats' main reproach is: the spring forecast made clear that still no new jobs have been created in spite of economic upswing. Theo Waigel whose economics policy has been praised today by leading economists seemed relaxed and assured that Germany would not miss the start of monetary union.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Federal cabinet passes tax reform </field>
<field name="text">The federal cabinet has passed the bill for the tax reform this morning. It will be debated as soon as Friday in the Bundestag. The bill is 400 pages thick and provides a net tax reduction. Effects for individuals remain unclear because tax benefits are supposed to be eliminated at the same time. There are also plans for increasing consumption taxes to finance the reform. The entry income tax will be reduced from 25.9 to 15 percent, the maximum tax from 53 to 39 percent. Waigel admitted that he cannot make any exact statements about the extent of the budget deficit.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Government and SPD meet for tax talks </field>
<field name="text">In spite of slim chances for agreement, government and SPD will meet tomorrow for their third tax summit. In a letter SPD chief Oskar Lafontaine accepted the wish of Christian Union and Liberals to meet in the Chancellor's Office but confirmed at the same time his party's position. SPD Secretary-General Mr. Muentefering said in view of the budget deficits in Minister Waigel's bill it was unclear how both sides could come together.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Christian Union doubt tax agreement will be reached </field>
<field name="text">CDU/CSU are sceptical that an agreement will be reached at tomorrow's tax summit. Secretary-General of the Christian Union faction Jochim Hoerster doubted SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine's will to a tax reform.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Europe to fight more strongly criminal goods transports </field>
<field name="text">European transportation ministers agreed at a conference in Berlin to fight crime related to cross-border goods transports. German Transportation Minister Matthias Wissmann said customs fraud has cost EU member states a minimum of DM750 million during 1990-1994. Without counter-measures, increasing crime would slow quick and unbureaucratic border controls. The ministers also recommended to ship more goods by rail than by road.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">End of argument between German Post and Post Bank in sight </field>
<field name="text">German Post has signed a co-operation contract with Post Bank. The contract regulates amongst others the joint use of postal outlets. For months, Post and Post Bank had negotiated without success. Yesterday, Post Minister Wolfgang Boetsch sent the two parties a draft contract for signing, not for negotiation. Post Bank will respond to the draft by 30 April.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Stiftung Warentest (Consumer Union) tests building and loan associations </field>
<field name="text">Stiftung Warentest [an independent foundation testing consumer goods and services, akin to American Consumer Union that publishes Consumer Reports] has tested the services of building and loan associations [specialized banks offering long-term combined savings and loan plans mostly for building or buying houses]. The foundation concluded that on average private banks offer better advice than state-owned public banks. The services of private building and loan associations were also better than in the previous test three years ago. Of 20 tested banks eight were rated good, the remaining did worse. Five banks were rated poor. The top banks were HUK Coburg, Schwaebisch-Hall, BHW, and LBS Wuerttemberg. Among those rated poor were Deutscher Ring, Wuestenrot, and LBS Rhineland-Palatinate.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Collective bargaining in chemical industry adjourned </field>
<field name="text">Collective bargaining talks for the west German chemical industry have been adjourned to 2 June. Unions and employers could not agree whether companies in a low order situation could temporarily pay wages below those set in the collective agreement.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Civil employees of Allied forces continue to strike </field>
<field name="text">The about 30,000 civil employees of the Allied forces in Germany continue to strike for better social security.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Alcatel employees protest against plans to close factory </field>
<field name="text">Employees of Alcatel SEL AG's Mannheim factory have protested vehemently against the planned closure of the plant. According to the workers' council many workers left their work place several hours early after a workers general assembly. Workers' council chair Mr. Schwab stated there was no reason to close the plant because there was no lack of offers for 1997 and several offers have already been secured for 1998.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Chemical accident at Main River </field>
<field name="text">>From a chemical fibre factory in Erlenbach, Lower Franconia, 270,000 litres poisonous chemicals have run into the River Main. The cause of the accident remains unclear.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Kinkel criticizes expulsion policy of federal states </field>
<field name="text">Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel has again criticized the federal states because of their way of expelling Bosnian refugees. In a newspaper interview Kinkel said it was important that the people not simply be handed over in Sarajevo. The state interior ministers ought to find a common plan for the repatriation. For this a special commissioner should be installed. CDU politician Christian Schwartz-Schilling called the states' repatriation policy simple-minded, heartless, and ignorant and one that was carried out on the back of the refugees. Meanwhile, Bosnian President Alija Izetbegovic joined the discussion about the repatriation of Bosnian war refugees by massively attacking Bosnian Serbs. In a letter to member states of the EU Izetbegovic complained the Serbs did not keep appointments. This would put the whole package of treaties at risk.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Churches warn against self-confinement </field>
<field name="text">The Churches in Germany have warned against the self-isolation of Europe against other states. In a joint declaration marking this year's Week of the Foreign Citizen the Churches stated borders must remain open for those in need.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Appeals against asylum rejection must not be dismissed without checking </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Constitutional Court in Karlsruhe has found that a court can only dismiss an appeal against an asylum rejection when the court has convinced itself that the refugee will not be placed into a no-way-out situation in his home country. The finding was in response to a constitutional challenge by a 16-year-old Kurd.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Sexual abuse in psychotherapy soon punishable </field>
<field name="text">According to Justice Minister Schmidt-Jortzig the estimated number of unrecorded cases of sexual abuse of patients in psychotherapy is about 600 annually. These offences are to be punished with up to five years imprisonment according to a bill passed today.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Scientology organization to be continued to be watched </field>
<field name="text">The government of Baden-Wuerttemberg will have the state intelligence service continue to watch the Scientology organization. Expert opinion of Tuebingen University showed that the organization remains on the border of constitutionality.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">U.S.A. call on Germany to step up position against Iran </field>
<field name="text">An official of the US Foreign Ministry said Iran was an ostracized state with aggressive intents against its neighbours. Meanwhile, Iran has begun large military exercizes according to news agency reports.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">German participation in Cannes Film Festival </field>
<field name="text">Germany will be represented by Wim Wender's film "Das Ende der Gewalt" (The End of Violence) in the 50th anniversary festival of Cannes. The festival opens with a film by French Luc Bresson (sp?).  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-22</field><field name="title">Tennis: Stich in second round, Becker eliminated </field>
<field name="text">In the Monte Carlo Tennis Tournament Michael Stich has reached the second round. He won over Australian Mark Woodforde in three sets. Boris Becker was eliminated by Italian Renzo Furlan also in three sets.  </field></doc></add>