<add><doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Government denies report about cabinet reshuffle </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Government has denied a report in the tabloid "Bild am Sonntag" about an imminent cabinet reshuffle. A government spokesman in Bonn said the report was just one of many false rumours circulating at this time. The tabloid reported that Chancellor Helmut Kohl was planning to replace Finance Minister Theo Waigel with CDU chairman Wolfgang Schaeuble next month. The Minister for the Interior, Manfred Kanther, and Minister for Building and Construction, Klaus Toepfer, were supposed to be leaving as well. The report also claimed that the Department of Construction would be integrated with the Department of Finance, and that a CSU politician would be entrusted with the Department of the Interior.  CSU regional chairman Mr. Glos emphasized that his party would continue to call for changes within the government.  In an interview with the newspaper "Frankfurter Rundschau", he said that Chancellor Helmut Kohl had decided to run again at the insistence of the CSU. However, in order to be successful in the elections next year, he would have to present a fresh team. Mr. Glos also said, without the extraordinary achievements of the CSU in Bavaria, there would be no coalition and no Chancellor Kohl.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Different signals from SPD over tax issue </field>
<field name="text">The Social Democratic Party (SPD) is giving out contradictory signals about how it intends to proceed in the tax dispute with the coalition. Ingrid Matthaeus-Maier, vice-chairman of the SPD, told the newspaper "Koelner Express" that further negotiations with Finance Minister Theo Waigel had been ruled out. SPD chairman Rudolf Scharping, on the other hand, has pleaded for a quick agreement on a small tax reform. He said an understanding must be reached on those points which transcend party differences. Mr. Mai, chairman of the Union for Public Service and Transportation, warned the Social Democrats against accepting a tax compromise. The opposition should not approach the coalition on this issue, he said. Their plans would only lead to new shortfalls in the budget and further unemployment.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Mr. Thierse clearly rejects PDS </field>
<field name="text">Wolfgang Thierse, vice-chairman of the SPD, has rejected the offer of the PDS (Party of Democratic Socialism) to work together after the next Bundestag election. Speaking in Berlin, Mr. Thierse said there would be no coalition. Yesterday during a congress meeting, the chairman of the PDS, Mr. Bisky, presented his party as a partner for the Social Democrats and the Green Party, to replace the coalition of CDU and FDP.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Companies confirm 100,000 additional training posts </field>
<field name="text">German companies have promised to create 100,000 additional training posts for this year. The Minister for Education, Mr. Ruettgers, and the Minister for Economics, Guenther Rexrodt, said today in Bonn that the new training posts would help to improve the situation on the job market. They added, however, that the employment problems were not over yet.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Mr. Henkel criticizes lack of action to improve Germany's position </field>
<field name="text">The chairman of the Federal Union of German Industry,  Mr. Henkel, has reproached major companies for their lack of action to improve Germany's economic position. In an interview with the economics journal "Impulse", Mr Henkel said he often felt isolated and that he would like more support from among his own ranks in the public debate. Employers must also make themselves heard, he said.  Many industrial managers still go suddenly quiet, when a politician comes to visit their company.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">German army will be on duty at the River Oder until October </field>
<field name="text">The work of the Bundeswehr on the banks of the River Oder will be required until at least October.  However, the number of soldiers involved (currently 3,000) will be gradually reduced, according to General Major von Kirchbach. The priority for the coming week will be the use of heavy machinery to remove damage caused by the flood. In addition, the dikes will have to be further secured and prepared for the high waters expected during winter and spring.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Nestle-Thomae blackmail case </field>
<field name="text">Investigators in the blackmail case Nestle-Thomae are working on about 500 leads from the public. However, it is too early to say whether any of them will turn out to be the right track. Since a tape recording of the blackmailer's voice was released a week ago, about 13,000 calls have been registered.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Investigation against Mr. Kirch now also underway in Switzerland </field>
<field name="text">The Munich media entrepreneur Mr. Kirch is now also being investigated in Switzerland on suspicion of tax fraud. The police is searching homes in four different regions of the country. Mr. Kirch is alleged to have withheld about 400 million DM in taxes from the Swiss treasury after a deal about film rights. The Zurich district attorney confirmed a corresponding report in the Sunday newspaper.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Schumacher wins Belgian Grand Prix </field>
<field name="text">In the Formula 1 championships, Michael Schumacher has won the Belgian Grand Prix in Spa. In his fourth victory of the season, the Ferrari driver finished well ahead of the Italian Fisicella and the Finn Mika Haekkinen, who came in second and third respectively. Heinz-Harald Frentzen in Williams-Renault finished fourth. Ralf Schumacher was forced to retire after his car went into a spin.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-24</field><field name="title">Gold and Silver medals for German swimmers in Seville </field>
<field name="text">At the European swimming championships in Seville, Kathleen Rund from Berlin has won gold in the 200 meters back-stroke. The silver medal went to Antje Busch-Schulte from Magdeburg. Another silver medal went to the men's 4x100m relay team.  In the same race Russia won gold and Poland bronze.  </field></doc></add>