<add><doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Struck reiterates his point in tax dispute </field>
<field name="text">In the internal dispute within the Social Democrats (SPD), its faction leader in the Bundestag (lower house of parliament), Peter Struck has reinforced his call for a reorientation of the party. The old motto of a workers' party - to take from the rich and to give to the poor - did not fit a modern society, said Mr Struck at a TV interview. Mr Struck also called for a complete overhaul of the tax system, though he did no longer fight for the FDP model with only three tax rates of 15, 25 and 35 per cent, previously supported by him. Instead, Mr Struck called on the government to implement after 2002 a tax reform that deserves the name.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Reintroduction of wealth tax abandoned </field>
<field name="text">The plans to reintroduce the wealth tax are now totally abandoned. The red-green coalition government in the State of Schleswig-Holstein that planned to initiated such a reintroduction of the tax in the Bundesrat (upper house of parliament) today withdraw its bill. The SPD faction leader in the state's parliament, Mr Hay, said the project failed because it did not get the support of the majority among the German states. Neither will the state Schleswig-Holstein introduce the tax just on itself. Instead, Mr Hay now strongly supports an increase in the inheritance tax. In his opinion, private assets above DM one million should be taxed more heavily. SPD faction leader in the Bundestag (lower house of parliament) Peter Struck, too, supports such an increase in the inheritance tax. Mr Struck said at an interview in the weekly "Stern", for heirs of third degree tax allowances should be decreased, and tax rates be increased.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Increase in German trade surplus </field>
<field name="text">Because of a rise in exports, the German foreign trade surplus has increased. In the month of June, goods for DM 86 billion were exported. According to the Federal Department of Statistics, this represents an increase of 4.6 per cent compared to one year ago. Imports only rose slightly to DM 73 billion, yielding to a trade surplus of more than DM 13 billion.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Constitutional Court protects right of minority stock holders </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Consitutional Court has increased the rights of minority share holders. According to a decision published today, at take overs stock holders have to be compensated with at least the market value of their shares. When determining the market value of the stock, its trading value at the stock market has to be taking into consideration. The first senate of the court cited the protection of property garanteed in the Constitution as reason for the decision.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">CEO of Bayerische Beamtenversicherung in detention </field>
<field name="text">The chief exectutive officer of Bayerische Beamtenversicherung (Bavarian public servants' insurance), Mr Schweikert, has been taken into detention pending trial in Innsbruck. This was confirmed today by the Bochum Public Prosecutor's Office. Mr Schweikert was arrested at Innsbruck airport yesterday. The manager is allegedly involved in a bribery scandal in the sale of the building of the Federal ministry for economics and cooperation. Mr Schweikert is already the third top ranking manager arrested in the bribery scandal. At the sale of the building, the three suspects allegedly made out fictitious invoices, thus fraudously cashing in several million mark.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">German General nominated as leader of Kosovo peacekeeping forces </field>
<field name="text">The German government has nominated the German general Reinhard to succeed the British general Jackson as the leader of the Kosovo peacekeeping forces. A representative of NATO's military headquarters confirmed the nomination, but emphasized that the decision rests with NATO commander-in-chief Clark and the NATO council.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Children born out of wedlock have right to know about their father </field>
<field name="text">The court has decided that a child born out of wedlock has the right to force the mother to divulge information about the father. After a ruling by the high court in Bremen, a mother who resists risks enforcing measures. A young woman who refused to tell her child the father's name, was fined 2000 DM.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">New trials for attack on Israeli consulate in February </field>
<field name="text">Two more trials against Kurds have begun at the regional court of Berlin today for the attack on the Israeli consulate general in February. The five defendants would not comment on the accusations of serious breach of peace and trespassing. During the demonstrations in February against the arrest of Kurd leader Ocalan, four Kurds were shot and killed and more were wounded by Israeli guards.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">Baden-Wuerttemberg too collects more taxes </field>
<field name="text">Baden-Wuerttemberg too has collected more taxes this year than was hitherto expected, finance minister Mr Stratthaus announced. Up to the end of July, 23 billion DM in taxes were collected, which is approximately 880 million DM, or close to 4 percent, more than was previously assumed. Despite the positive figures, Mr Strathaus warned against raising expectations too high. The present additional tax revenue is based on the favourable economic situation of the past year. It is unclear whether this development will continue.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-08-10</field><field name="title">A PhD for one thesis in both Germany and France </field>
<field name="text">A student at the Free University of Berlin has become the first German to receive a PhD in both Germany and France for the same thesis. The Free University announced that, in the spirit of the European mobility of young academics, the doctorate would be recognised in both countries. In his thesis the 28 year old student compared recruitment of the elite in Germany and France.  </field></doc></add>