<add><doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">CDU/CSU in favour of better youth protection in television </field>
<field name="text">According to a report by the daily Frankfurter Allgemeine Sonntagszeitung CDU and CSU want to improve youth protection in TV programmes. CSU member of parliament Eichhorn is reported saying that strong-violence rated movies should no longer be broadcast. If the broadcasters did not set up their own rules the broadcasting contract had to be amended. Mr. Eichhorn is president of the CDU/CSU Bundestag work-group on family, seniors, women, and youth. The SPD delegate Ms. Niehus and youth expert of Alliance90/Greens Mr.Schlauch also called for better youth protection in television.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">Baden-Wuerttemberg's economics minister and industry leaders in southern US </field>
<field name="text">Baden-Wuerttemberg's Minister of Economics Walter Doering (FDP) and representatives of the state's industry have left for a visit of the southern US. They want to explore market chances of domestic products. During the six-day visit the group will also visit the Mercedes plant in Tuscaloosa, Alabama.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">German Book Retailers' Peace Prize to Mario Vargas Llosa </field>
<field name="text">Peruvian writer Mario Vargas Llosa has been awarded the German Book Retailers' Peace Prize. At the award ceremony in the Frankfurt St. Paul's Church the 60-year-old author called on the democracies to fight dictatorships. The ceremony was attended by the German President Roman Herzog and Hesse's State Premier Hans Eichel. The award committee called Vargas Llosa a man with unusual moral courage. The prize that has been awarded since 1950 by book publishers and retailers is worth DM25,000.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">Frankfurt declaration against spelling reform </field>
<field name="text">Numerous writers, scholars of German literature and language, and journalists have protested against the spelling reform. In a Frankfurt Declaration on the Spelling Reform published today the signers of the declaration urged to keep the present rules. In view of the difficult economic situation the reform must not result in the reprinting of all textbooks, dictionaries, and encyclopaedias. The group thinks that the spelling reform will cause confusion for decades and damage the reputation of the German language inside and outside Germany. Among the signers of the declaration are writers Guenther Grass, Siegfried Lenz, and Ilse Aichinger, scholar Wolfgang Martens, and the journalists Roger Willemsen and Ernst-Dieter Lueg.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">Munich Oktoberfest closes </field>
<field name="text">The Munich Oktoberfest has closed its doors. Two hundred thousand visitors more than last year or 6.9 million have taken part. This is the highest number since more than ten years but not exactly the record of 7 million that was expected. The return of outlets and entertainers increased by 6 percent. In total 5.1 million litres of beer (c. 1.1 million gallons) have been consumed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">State Garden Exhibition of Baden-Wuerttemberg closes </field>
<field name="text">Fireworks marked the closing of the 14th Baden-Wuerttemberg Garden Exhibition. About one million people have visited the exhibition since it opened in April. The last day of the exhibition was organized by the communities and cities from the Stuttgart region. Radio Sueddeutscher Rundfunk that had a local studio at the exhibition broadcast 100 hours of radio and television.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">Goellner wins second ATP tournament </field>
<field name="text">Tennis professional Marc Kevin Goellner has won the second ATP tournament of his career. Goellner who is seated number 73 on the world list won over Alex Coreha from Spain 7:6 and 7:6.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1996-10-06</field><field name="title">Weather report </field>
<field name="text">In Bavaria, Saxony, and Bavaria covered skies and in southern Bavaria rain in the morning. Elsewhere sunny skies and dry once the fog has dissolved. Highs between 9 and 14 degrees Celsius, lows tonight in the South and East 10 to 5 degrees and in the North and West 5 to 0. Extended forecast: Monday and Tuesday partly foggy, partly sunny. Apart from foggy dew, generally dry. Highs, depending on smount of sunshine, between 10 and 19.  </field></doc></add>