<add><doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">Commission reviews suggestions to reform Greens' party structure </field>
<field name="text">The Buendnis 90/Greens party is preparing a reform of their party structure.  A commission is to review suggestions toware it, which the party council set into motion today in Bonn.  The goal is the passage of a resolution at the Federal Convention next spring.  Leadership spokeswoman Roestel emphasized that the Greens want to set focus not inly in the environmental arena, but also in economic, financial and social policy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">Criticism of considerations to raise value-added tax </field>
<field name="text">The opposition, the economy, and trade unions have critcized the considerations of the Bonn coalition to increase the value-added tax. The representative CDU leader merz demanded that the government end the debate, and bring an overall tax plan to the table.  The FDP fraction asked for a "Current Hour" of the Parliament on the topic. The trade industry, as well as the wholesale and retail industries, warned of the consequences of such a hike on the labor market.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">SPD States want value-added tax hike </field>
<field name="text">The SPD-controlled states are pressing the federal government for a value-added tax hike, as reported by the Rheinische Post newspaper. Future Finance Minister Eichel allegedly has reservations against it.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">Urig named new SPD Press Secretary </field>
<field name="text">The SPD has a new Press Secretary, Marion Urig (sp?), who was formerly the representative speaker of the SPD's parliamentary fraction.  The position of Press Secretary has been unoccupied for quite some time.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">Government demands explanation for arrest of Germans in Turkey </field>
<field name="text">The federal government has demanded a statement from the Turkish government following the arrest of 6 Germans in Turkey.  The Germans were arrested at the Kurdish Nevrot celebrations.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-03-22</field><field name="title">Sentences for accused in Schlecker proceedings </field>
<field name="text">Both main defendants in the Schlecker proceedings, Willi Hubelmaier and Herbert Jakobi, have been sentenced to 13-1/2 years in prison. Hubelmaier's brother, Dieter, was also sentenced to 7-1/2 years by the Ulm State Court.  His role was unclear up to the end of the proceedings; the prosecution was unable to present clear evidence of his involvement.  Thus Dieter Hubelmaier and his attorney are considering an appeal.  The judgement against the two other accused was clear my comparison; both confessed to three kidnappings, among them that of the Schlecker children, and 5 other offenses.  all other crimes committed by both expired under the statute of limitations.  Police were able to recover only 1.6 million Marks of the 18 million Marks taken as ransom. The rest was split between a rapid change of lifestyle, and heavy losses on the stock market.  </field></doc></add>