<add><doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Kohl is awarded Marshall Prize </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Kohl has met with President Clinton at the beginning of his visit to the U.S.A.  Among other topics, they discussed the upcoming G7 meeting, the UNO general assembly, the eastward expansion of NATO, and the future development of the European Union.  Mr. Kohl and Mr. Clinton were accompanied by their respective national security advisors. Mr. Kohl will stay in the United States for two days.  At a gala banquet, the George C. Marshall Prize will be conferred on him.  The prize is being awarded for the first time this year, marking the 50th anniversary of the Marshall plan.  The issuing foundation said Mr. Kohl had rendered outstanding services in fostering transatlantic relations.  In a newspaper interview President Clinton has called for a closer cooperation with Bonn in the fight against terrorism - a clear allusion to Bonn's attitude towards Iran.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Scharping remains chairman of European Social Democrats </field>
<field name="text">The head of the SPD parliamentary group, Mr. Scharping, has been re-elected as chairman of Europe's social-democratic parties.  At the beginning of the third convention of the European Social Democrats in the Swedish town of Malmo, he has been confirmed in office for another two years.  2000 delegates representing social-democratic parties from all 15 EU countries are participating in the three-day summit meeting.  One of the objectives is to fix their position on the reform of the Union, which will be the subject of the EU summit in mid-June in Amsterdam.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Only slight decline in unemployment in May </field>
<field name="text">4.25 million people in Germany are still without jobs.  According to the newspaper "Berliner Zeitung", unemployment fell slightly in May, but in comparison to previous years the figures are disappointing.  Traditionally, more people used to be able to find jobs in Spring.  The President of the Federal Labor Office expects an average joblessness of 4.2 million for the year.  Mr. Jagoda said this is the most difficult year in the Labor Office's history.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Health insurers in the red, despite savings measures </field>
<field name="text">Public health insurers continue to be in the red, after the first quarter of the year.  The total deficit amounts to 2.5 billion marks, Minister of Health Seehofer said.  The reason for this is that the insurers have accumulated high debts in previous years.  Even though cuts have been effective in administration, sick pay, rehabilitation and advertising since the beginning of the year, these savings were dissipated by higher costs of in-patient care and a large volume of dental treatments, the latter arising from wide-spread anxiety about the health care reform which drove people to get new dentures before the new legislation came into force.  Mr. Seehofer stressed that the debates about the reform are over now and that the Bundestag will put the new laws in effect on July 1st.  He defended the DM 5 flat deductible therein as being necessary to fund medical progress.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Tenant association against passing operating expenses onto rent-payers </field>
<field name="text">The German Association of Tenants has criticized the fact that, according to a government bill, property owners can continue passing operating expenses onto tenants.  The Association's director, Mr. Rips, said in the newspaper "Neue Osnabruecker Zeitung" that this would be inviting abuse. In the interest of millions of households, a fundamental reform is necessary, he demanded.  In the future only expenses such as water or heating, which vary according to consumption, should be picked up by the rent-payer.  All other operating expenses should become part of the rent. Mr. Rips pointed out that the cost for utilities exploded last year.  This is compounded by municipal fees which, for many households, have reached unbearable levels.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Disputes over new environmental laws </field>
<field name="text">Environmental organizations have protested against new environmental legislation passed by the Bundestag.  The President of "Bund fuer Umwelt und Naturschutz" [Organization for Environmental Protection], Mr. Weinzier, said the law is a slap in the face of environmental protection.  The SPD-run states intend to block the law in the Bundesrat.  In particular the Opposition criticized the fact that farmers are being given a green light for the excessive use of fertilizers.  SPD environmental expert Ulrike Mehl accused the government of failing to set clear guidelines for environmentally compatible farming, and instead doing the opposite by declaring current agricultural methods as standard.  Environmental Minister Angela Merkel defended the law: "Nature is always influenced by man.  What is our guiding example?  The 11th or the 12th century?  We have to accept that the environment has changed with man, and there cannot be a group within society who protects the environment for its own sake, while stigmatizing the rest of the world as evil and destructive."  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Opposition accuses government of obstinacy over issue of immigration </field>
<field name="text">The parties of the opposition have accused the government of blocking the reform of naturalization regulations and the updating of immigration legislation.  During a discussion of several proposals put forward by SPD and The Green Alliance for a liberal immigration law, the SPD expert for domestic policy, Ms. Sonntag-Wolgast, described the government's attitude as obstinate.  She and Mr. Oezdemir (The Greens) both endorsed granting German citizenship to German-born children of foreigners automatically. The spokesman on Interior Policy for CDU/CSU, Mr. Marschewski, underscored that the Coalition will reform immigration law before the end of the legislative term.  He rejected the general admission of dual citizenship just as much as a legally fixed immigration quota.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">State Environmental Ministers demand national environmental policy </field>
<field name="text">The State Environmental Ministers have urged the Federal Government to draw up a national environmental policy.  In a statement they demanded an ecologically oriented tax policy.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Prison terms for ex-soldiers </field>
<field name="text">Almost three months after the assault on foreigners in Detmold, five former Bundeswehr soldiers have been sentenced to prison terms or youth detention. The principal perpetrator has to go to jail for 14 months.  The four co-defendants were sentenced to eight and six months in prison or juvenile correction centers with the possibility of parole.  The Detmold Regional Court found them guilty of inflicting severe bodily harm.  In March, the former soldiers had assaulted a Turk and two Italians with baseball bats and knives.  The presiding judge called the deed an act of racial hatred. Two of the defendants admitted sympathizing with right-wing parties. After the incident, the soldiers were discharged from the Bundeswehr.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">March of condolence for victims of fire at Friedrichshafen </field>
<field name="text">With a march of condolence last night, about 150 people commemorated the victims of the fire at a dormitory for asylum seekers in Friedrichshafen. From the site of the incident the group moved downtown, before the city hall.  Afterwards a further 60 people held a vigil. The cause of the fire that killed a 26-year-old Kurd from Turkey and injured 53 other people is still unclear.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">Police overpower man in Stadtallendorf </field>
<field name="text">Around mid-day, the police overpowered a man who had barricaded himself inside his house in Stadtallendorf.  An 85-year-old resident died of heart failure when the police stormed the house.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-06-05</field><field name="title">German collector makes highest bid for world's most expensive wine </field>
<field name="text">Since last night, the most expensive wine in the world is a 1945 Mouton Rothschild.  A German collector made the highest bid for a case of the Bordeaux, DM 156,000.  </field></doc></add>