<add><doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">Turkey now an official candidate for EU-membership </field>
<field name="text">At their Helsinki meeting, the EU member-countries' heads of state declared Turkey to be a candidate for membership. Previously Greece had relented and stopped opposing her arch-rival's aspirations. Tonight, EU foreign politics co-ordinator Solana and Mr Verheugen, who is in charge of the extension of the EU, will fly to Ankara, to explain their decision. Other candidates are: Poland, Romania, Lithuania, Latvia, Slovakia, Malta, Hungary, Chechia, Estonia, Slovenia and Cyprus.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">EU Summit Meeting on establishment of rapid deployment force / Chechnya </field>
<field name="text">At their summit meeting, the EU heads of state decided to set up a rapid deployment force. As of 2003, 15 brigades totalling 60,000 soldiers would be available for deployment in crisis spots, provided NATO did not want to get involved. The war in Chechnya cast a shadow over the Helsinki meeting: the EU told Russia that they would think again about financial and political co-operation with Moscow if Russia did not hold their horses in the war against Chechnya. In the meantime, the Russian government unexpectedly announced negotiations about the evacuation of civilians from the encircled capital of Groszny.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">Minor CDU Party Congress this weekend / Mr Kohl will not attend </field>
<field name="text">The secondary CDU party congress next Monday will probably not shed any more light on the CDU-donations affair. Former Chancellor Kohl will not attend, according to General Secretary Merkel, and there were no new findings either. The reason was that some former CDU-politicians so far had not said what they knew about the procedures being followed under Mr Kohl. Now family policies will be on the meeting's agenda, as originally planned.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">Pension at 60: Chancellor asked to mediate </field>
<field name="text">Business and trade unions are at loggerheads over the issue of drawing a pension at age 60, and they are relying on Chancellor Schroeder for mediation as they keep discussing the 'Treaty for Work'. Two days out of the next meeting, nothing had moved, and that's why the boss of the Metalworkers' employers Stumpfe called on Mr Schroeder - just as the head of the Metalworkers' Union had done before, though the latter had also threatened to can the talks. Mr Hundt, of the Employers' Federation, could not see 'a big leap forward' happening in the next round of talks; the unions, however, expected some progress.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">Human Rights Day </field>
<field name="text">Today was Human Rights Day, and numerous organisations deplored massive violations of the UN Charter of Human Rights. According to Amnesty International, military and police kill people in 47 countries of the world. In 66 countries hundreds of thousands of political prisoners were in jail, without a proper trial. The Protestant Church deplored that 90 countries still had the death penalty, and that this year the number of people executed had even gone up.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-12-10</field><field name="title">Two dangerous inmates escape from Bruchsal jail near Karlsruhe </field>
<field name="text">Two supposedly dangerous inmates of Bruchsal jail, near Karlsruhe, have escaped. The two 33- and 35-year old men overpowered a warden and are armed with an MP. Police suggested that no-one should pick up hitch-hikers. Till Friday night, the massive manhunt had been without success. One of the men is from Romania and had been on life-imprisonment for attempted manslaughter and other crimes; the other was a German serving a sentence for robbery and blackmail.  </field></doc></add>