<add><doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Commanding officers discuss Bundeswehr right-wing extremism </field>
<field name="text">The commanding officers of the German armed forces (Bundeswehr) have assembled for their regular meeting. One of the main topics on their agenda is the improvement of the fight against right-wing extremism within the Bundeswehr. Inspector General Hartmut Bagger said these crimes were a disgrace for the army and that the soldiers involved in them would be called into full account. Bagger went on to say that the mental and moral waywardness of a few adolescents did not constitute a Bundeswehr problem but a social one.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Kohl speaks out against unreflected accusations against the Bundeswehr </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Helmut Kohl said that the Bundeswehr should not be condemned because of isolated instances of right-wing extremism. He said that the vast majority of soldiers were dedicated democrats and beyond reproach. Kohl also stated that everything possible should be done to solve these right-wing extremist crimes and prevent them from happening again.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Wage negotiations in public service sector fail </field>
<field name="text">There will be no contract for employment in the public service sector. In Stuttgart, early negotations on the securing of existing jobs failed. Unions and employers were unable to move beyond their initial positions. A major point of contention was the demand raised by federal, state, and local employers to include sick pay and preventive health costs in the negotiatons. OeTV and DAG unions refused to add these topics to the agenda. They plan to decide on their official 1998 wage increase demand in December. Both sides blamed each other for the failure of the talks.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Polen's NATO application receives support from Germany and France </field>
<field name="text">Germany and France both support Poland on its way to NATO membership. The three countries' defense ministers agreed on annual joint maneuvers of their armed forces.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">VW creates 8000 new jobs </field>
<field name="text">The Volkswagen corporation has created 8000 new jobs this year. During the first nine months of 1997, the company's profit was 852 mio. marks, already higher than the total profit in 1996.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Bautzen court judges against orthography reform </field>
<field name="text">The Bautzen High Administrative Court has halted the orthography reform, but the state of Saxony still plans to implement the new rules.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">Tennis: Steffi Graf to play again soon </field>
<field name="text">Steffi Graf is about to return to the game after a long injury. Her first match is scheduled for November 25. Graf will face Chanda Rubin in the U.S. In December, Graf plans to participate in the Frankfurt tournament.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-11-03</field><field name="title">First national soccer league: Bielefeld vs. Hamburg 0:3 </field>
<field name="text">In a Sunday game of the first national soccer league (Bundesliga), the team of the Hamburger SV defeated Arminia Bielefeld 0:3.  </field></doc></add>