<add><doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Thierse speech regarding National Mourning Day </field>
<field name="text">President of the Bundestag (parliament), Mr. Thierse, dismissed calls for putting an end to German history. "Leaving behind history and denying past horrors are impossible," Thierse said during a commemoration of National Mourning Day at the Capitol in Berlin. He added that looking onto the past does not evoke a gloomy image exclusively. "Next to mourning and many painful memories there are also hope and faith," Thierse stressed.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Chancellor Schroeder challenges party to be united </field>
<field name="text">Three weeks before the national social democratic convention in Berlin party chief Schroeder asked for unity among party ranks. At a meeting of East German State delegates in Berlin the chancellor said that people want a strong and unified social democratic party. Kicking off the conference Brandenburg Governor Stolpe warned that the topic of social justice must not be neglected. The Social Democrats must remain clearly recognizable as the party of the common man.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Klimmt demands consideration for Green Party's concerns </field>
<field name="text">Minister of Transportation, Mr. Klimmt, challenged the Social Democrats to pay more attention to the Green Party. According to the Berlin Daily News Klimmt maintained that the SPD stands for social justice, reducing unemployment and creating new jobs, while the Green Party is more concerned with abandoning nuclear energy and focusing on alternative transportation. He continued to say there is a need to be considerate, even for the bigger partner in a coalition.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Divided opinions about Otto Schily's asylum proposals </field>
<field name="text">Minister of the Interior Otto Schily's call for the reform of immigration law is leading to squabbles in the coalition. Green Party Chief Ms. Mueller said there would no tightening of the law under her party's reign. On ZDF, the German Public Broadcast, Ms. Mueller referred to the coalition treaty and added that the basic right of asylum must not degenerate into an act of mercy. A similar position was voiced by the Commissioner of Foreigners, Beck, also a member of the Green Party. In contrast, Hesse Governor Koch offered Mr. Schily the Christian Democrats' support if he were to present his ideas to reform immigration law in a comprehensive bill.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Politicians in favor of pardon for former members of the Politburo </field>
<field name="text">Politicians of all parties are in favor of pardoning the former members of the East German Politburo, Mr. Krenz, Mr. Schabowski and Mr. Kleiber. The former civil rights activist, Ms. Lengsfeld, was quoted in "Welt am Sonntag," "This will keep the defendants from being viewed as martyrs. Christian Democrat member of the parliament, Mr. Eppelmann, said that before being pardoned these former East German politicians would have to admit their fault. Mr. Krenz did not strike him with such an impression.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Free Democrats demand resignation of Gerhard in Brandenburg </field>
<field name="text">The Free Democrats in Brandenburg asked party chief Mr. Gerhardt to resign. During a special party convention in Potsdam a clear majority of delegates approved a request for a new beginning in terms of personnel and policy. The document states that Mr. Gerhard does not implement the party line effectively. His resignation would be a convincing and much expected gesture of looking toward the future.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-11-14</field><field name="title">Soccer: Otto Rehagel extends contract with Kaiserslautern </field>
<field name="text">Otto Rehagel has extended his contract as coach of 1.FC Kaiserslautern until 2002. During the last few weeks rumors had it that Rehagel would quit.  </field></doc></add>