<add><doc><field name="date">1997-08-15</field><field name="title">Government apparently wants to raise taxes on consumption </field>
<field name="text">The governing coalition-parties apparently intend to raise sales-tax by two percentage points at the beginning of next year, to pay for tax- and pension-reforms. And, according to news agencies, a rise in excise-duty on motor-spirits is being discussed as well.  The above measures would enable social-security contributions to drop by some 30 billion marks, as the opposition SPD-party had requested. Penalty-rates for after-hours work, however, would remain tax-free, according to the coalition-parties.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-15</field><field name="title">Shipbuilder Bremer Vulkan closes for good </field>
<field name="text">Bremen's shipbuilder Vulkan now definitely closed down, afer more than 100 years in the trade. When the word came through, around midday, that this would be the last shift, staff unfurled black flags and some left their hard hats outside the company's gate. Now 2000 workers lost their jobs. The last ship they had built, a container-vessel, had left the works yesterday.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-15</field><field name="title">Mr Ruehe will react to neonazis in the Armed Forces </field>
<field name="text">Defence Minister Ruehe wants strong reactions to right-wing neonazi tendencies. Following the attack, by two soldiers, on a home for persons seeking asylum in Dresden, he decided that no criminals would serve in the Armed Forces, in the future. He suggested police and courts inform the draft boards accordingly. This was not about soldiers' conscience, but rather making sure no known or active neonazi would hurt the Armed Forces by serving in them. The Soldiers' Association asked for better training as far as political science was concerned.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-08-15</field><field name="title">Berlin's SPD in favour of conscription </field>
<field name="text">Berlin's SPD-party members want to stick with conscription, having narrowly defeated a remit by some left-wing members to go for an army of professionals. At the same time the delegates spoke in favour of admitting women.  </field></doc></add>