<add><doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Food producer Thomy under extortion </field>
<field name="text">Police have found a tube of mustard containing a lethal dose of cyanide in a supermarket. According to the Saarland Criminal Police the shop was closed and all food items removed. An extortionist is trying to get several million marks from food producer Thomy that is part of the Nestle group. The perpetrators had threatened earlier to poison products of the company. According to police the extortion has already been going on for several months. Police assume that several persons are involved based on the country-wide action. Police headquarters in Frankfurt have taken over the coordination of investigations. They stated that Thomy is prepared to make contact with the extortionists in the way stipulated by the extortionist. Yesterday, the company received a letter stating that the next attack would not only target Thomy products. The letter specified three supermarkets in Regensburg, Bremen, and Saarbruecken. All three supermarkets were closed immediately. Police warned strongly against consuming foods such as mayonnaise, mustard or ketchup that was bought on or after April 1 in the Regensburg Konti-Markt, a Saarbruecken Plus-Markt, and a Bremen Lidl-Markt. Concerned peopled should not open the products but immediately call the police. A toll-free telephone hot-line has also been established. Its number is 0130-18 61 10.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Civil employees of US forces on protest </field>
<field name="text">Several thousand civil employees of the US armed forces have protested at a rally against job reductions. The civil employees are on strike since the beginning of March. They demand a collective agreement that protects their jobs from rationalization and stipulates high compensations for lay-offs. The Forces have offered one year's income as compensation, this is not satisfactory to the unions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Slight decrease of unemployment in March </field>
<field name="text">The number of unemployed has decreased to 4.48 million in March according to a report by Federal Department of Labour in Nuremberg. That is 190,000 people less than in February. The rate of unemployment for both west and east Germany is now 11.7%. The decrease of unemployment is seasonal because many workers especially in the construction industry are laid off during the winter. These people are now re-hired. The over-all trend, however, is not positive. There are still 4.5 million people without a job in Germany, that is 335,000 more than one year ago. The number of employed people also declined. There are only about 34 million employed in Germany. About 590,000 less than in 1996. This reduction was most intense in manufacturing and construction.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Employment summit in Berlin </field>
<field name="text">Unions, employers, and politicians met in Berlin to discuss the current situation on the job market. Dieter Schulte, chief of the National Federation of Unions said that in view of the economic conditions the high rate of unemployment in Germany was embarrassing. Stimulation of research and investment was necessary to create new jobs. President of the employer associations Dieter Hundt said, the German economy, too, had to take a positive attitude towards the global structural change. New jobs could only be created through innovations, new markets, and new products. The politicians had to make sure that the conditions are right, for example, competitive wages. Federal Labour Minister Norbert Bluem demanded a change of attitude in the organization of work hours. Part-time work must be encouraged, this would also correspond to the demand of many unemployed people.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Federal Labour Department calls for more training jobs </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Department of Labour has called on administration and companies to provide as quickly as possible additional training jobs. Already now there is a lack of 200,000 training jobs.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Top tax talks between SPD and government scheduled for next week </field>
<field name="text">The top talk between the heads of oppositional Social-Democrats and governing Christian Union coalition will take place coming Tuesday. Both sides have agreed on this date. The chairpersons of party and faction of SPD and coalition parties and their financial experts will take part.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Defence Minister against expulsion of Bosnian refugees into hot zones </field>
<field name="text">Defence Minister Volker Ruehe has spoken against a repatriation of Bosnian refugees into conflict zones. In a TV interview he said expelling refugees to regions that are claimed by both Serbs and Muslims would only create conflicts. The repatriates are important for rebuilding the country but the selection criteria had to be adapted to the Bosnian realities.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">East German agricultural companies must pay back GDR debts </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Constitutional Court decided that east German agricultural companies must pay back debts they made under the GDR regime. This, however, must not cause the economic survival of viable farms. The Court also found that the federal government must check till the year 2000 whether the companies can pay back the debts within reasonable time. If not, they must be granted further aid.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Fewer violent actions by extremist foreigners in Germany </field>
<field name="text">The number of extremist organizations of foreigners in Germany has increased less strongly than in previous year. The latest Domestic Intelligence report shows the Islamist organizations remain the largest group. The number of violent actions committed by extremist foreigners has for the first time declined slightly after several years of increase.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Bank robber shot dead on the run </field>
<field name="text">A 29-year-old bank robber was shot dead on the run by police in Stuttgart yesterday. In the morning he had robbed a bank in Stuttgart. Officers in a police car who were looking for the robber stopped the man. The robber seriously injured a police officer by firing a shotgun into the officer's face. Another policeman shot back at the robber who later died in a hospital. The man supposedly was a criminal offender released only recently from jail.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Anti-trust Office sanctions Tchibo's takeover of Eduscho </field>
<field name="text">The German Anti-Trust Office has agreed to coffee roaster Tchibo's takeover of its competitor, Bremen-based Eduscho group. Tchibo had announced last December that it would take over Eduscho subject to the approval of the Anti-trust Office at the beginning of this year. Eduscho's single owner, Mr. Schopf, hopes to save his financially groggy company by selling it.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Baden-Wuerttemberg presents Young Generation Future Offensive programme </field>
<field name="text">The state government of Baden-Wuerttemberg has presented the cornerstones for the Young Generation Future Offensive programme. The government wants to use the programme to focus investments on areas that are important for the economic performance, especially science, research, and new technologies. In real terms, 19 state universities will be expanded and 850 new places at universities will be created. The programme will be financed by selling state-owned Agency for State Development to state-owned State Credit Bank. The cabinet approved only yesterday to first sell shares worth DM566m. There is a controversy whether any profit could be made at all by selling the remaining shares. Although the state targets returns of approximately DM1bn, the State Credit Bank has signalled that it is not prepared to pay that much. It is said that some concerns came even from within the CDU faction. Thus, there is still need for action. The cabinet will make final decisions in two weeks' time.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Hoechst stops production of abortion pill </field>
<field name="text">Pharma group Hoechst has stopped the production of abortion pill RU486 that has been manufactured by its French daughter company Roussel-Leclave (sp?)  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Telephone network breakdown in Stuttgart and Munich </field>
<field name="text">For hours the phone networks in Stuttgart and Munich were dead when German Telekom attempted to install new software to improve its service.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Search for German tourists in Sumatra </field>
<field name="text">Police have started searching for two German tourists in the north of Sumatra. Eight days ago, the two wanted to climb a volcano and have since then disappeared.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Steffi Graf cleared from accusations </field>
<field name="text">The Women Tennis Association WTA has cleared Steffi Graf from the accusation of having accepted prohibited start premiums. The WTA stated that the case had been investigated and no violation against the rules had been found.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-04-08</field><field name="title">Two people killed in traffic accident </field>
<field name="text">At least two people were killed and 19 injured in a traffic accident in Saxony. The accident happened near Autobahn junction Nossen west of Dresden when three coaches and one truck crashed into each other. The cause is still unknown.  </field></doc></add>