<add><doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Schroeder intends to push ahead with austerity measures </field>
<field name="text">Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder intends to push ahead with the government's planned austerity measures. "The program may not be toppled" said Mr. Schroeder in a television interview. He continued that the program had to be presented to both the lower and upper houses of parliament and that obstacles would become insurmountable if there was any doubt in the proposed measures. Mr. Schroeder was convinced that the economy would improve in the second half of the year and that unemployment figures would decline.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">FDP: nearing the SPD? </field>
<field name="text">The FDP could become more interested in the SPD as a possible coalition partner if Chancellor Schroeder managed to reform the party as planned, said Guido Westerwelle, Secretary-General of the FDP said yesterday to the "Frankfurter Rundschau" newspaper. He continued that it would be exciting if the SPD were to follow a "Blair" type of course. Mr. Westerwelle said that he was watching developments with interest, in particular what direction the German Social Democrats would now take.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Klimmt plans to re-introduce tax on capital </field>
<field name="text">State Premier of the Saarland Klimmt plans to reintroduce tax on capital. The SPD politician said to the newspaper "Bild am Sonntag" that private capital in Germany had increased by 56 billion marks between 1991 and 1997. Capital taxes had only been one percent. He said this would be an indication of his plans but that he was open to suggestion.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Tougher speed limits due to summer smog </field>
<field name="text">German motorists will have to become accustomed to stricter speed limits in summer smog in the future. This was announced by Juergen Trittin, Minister of the Environment to the "Sueddeutschen Zeitung" newspaper. He said that an EU regulation would soon be passed that would rule that ozone levels may not rise above 24 mg per cubic meter of air and that this could only be achieved by stricter speed limits.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Chamber of Doctors: patient care guaranteed </field>
<field name="text">Joerg-Dietrich Hoppe, president of the Federal Chamber of Doctors, said that so-called "Hardship Program" for medical aid doctors would not endanger patient care. Patients would continue to be provided with medically necessary treatment, he said to "Die Welt" daily newspaper and that there was absolutely no "rationing" involved in the program. He continued that the program aimed at avoiding doctors reacting in "panic" when their medical-aid budgets had been exceeded.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Unsuccessful police hunt for murderer </field>
<field name="text">The alleged murderer of Remagen, Dieter Zurwehme, has managed to avoid capture once again. Police were not able to find the suspect after searching a 20 by 250 metre bushy compound in Bueckeburg in Lower Saxony on Sunday afternoon. Investigators had seen a man who fitted the police description on the grounds. The fifty-seven-year old had also just managed to avoid capture the afternoon before in Maisfeld.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Cooperation between Telekom and Telefonica </field>
<field name="text">The German telephone corporation Telekom and their Spanish counterpart Telefonica are apparently planning a cooperation agreement. According to the "Frankfurter Zeitung" newspaper, the two corporations plan to merge. Telefonica had, however, denied a planned merger only a week ago.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Annual Wagner festival in Bayreuth </field>
<field name="text">Spectators applauded wildly after the first performance of Lohengrin at the annual Wagner Festival at Bayreuth. This is "high season" for Wagner fans from all over the world. The festival will run until August 28 comprising 30 performances in all. Tickets have long been sold out.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Erik Zabel wins Green Jersey in Tour de France </field>
<field name="text">Erik Zabel has won the Green Jersey for best sprinter in the Tour de France for the third time in a row. However, he did not manage to win the last stage and came second after Australian Robby Mc Ewen. The American Lance Armstrong was the overall winner.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-07-25</field><field name="title">Grand Prix in Austria </field>
<field name="text">Eddi Irvine has won the Austrian Grand Prix. He beat David Coulthard and Mika Haekkinen. Heinz-Harald-Frentzen came fourth.  </field></doc></add>