<add><doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">German army soldier killed in field firing </field>
<field name="text">A nineteen year old soldier was killed at a nightly field firing on a training area in Bergen (Lower Saxony). A twenty-six year old soldier was injured. The police determined that orders were not followed correctly. 2 soldiers had been shooting in the training area when the nineteen year old was shot. The soldiers involved were interrogated by the state criminal police. All weapons were confiscated, and an autopsy of the body of the victim was ordered to take a closer look at the bullet. The recruits from Gosslar had practiced in two groups, one in front who shot with G3-firearms, the other one waiting behind at a distance of 100 m. It is unclear from which group the bullets were fired. Public prosecutors are examining whether the bullets were fired by accident, neglicence or on purpose.  Another soldier was killed in an accident in the district of Regensburg. A hunter shot the soldier in the head. The soldier had been training in the forest with his battalion.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Konradi defends Grass comments and criticizes their form </field>
<field name="text">Mr Konradi, the president of the German PEN centre, has defended the controversial remarks of the German author Gunther Grass regarding the deportation practices in Germany, but at the same time criticized their style. It has been necessary to clearly point out the problems of the deportation of the Kurds into Turkey, Mr Konradi told the Deutschlandfunk. He defended Grass against the attack of CDU secretary general Hintze. Mr. Hintze had called the speech at the award presentation an `intellectual low', but acknowledged that Grass had generalized.The author would have been more successful if he had presented his critique in a more diferentiated manner. Grass had told the Luebeck Nachrichten newspaper that he expected a change in the German deportation practices in response to this speech.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Merkel criticizes U.S. plan to restrain global warming </field>
<field name="text">The Federal Minister of the Environment Angela Merkel critized the U.S. plan to restrain global warming as lacking specifics. According to the plan the U.S. will not reduce emission of greenhouse gases for another 15 years.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">States want soccer games to remain on free TV channels </field>
<field name="text">Games of the national soccer team shall remain on free TV channels according to the opinion of the states. At the state premier conference in Stuttgart the heads of the states determined to negotiate with the proprietors. The 16 state premiers do not have the right to make that decision, but they can push for it. In official language this will mean that they insist on all games of the German national team to be shown on free TV channels.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">States have no plans to cut wages of Goverment officials </field>
<field name="text">The Bavarian finance minister Huber mentioned at a conference of the state finance ministers in Bonn that the states have no plans to cut wages of Government officials. There will be no special sacrifices or a reduction of Christmas bonuses. The finance ministers are also waiting for the outcome of the collective bargaining of the public sector before making further decisions.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Another violent video tape found in German army </field>
<field name="text">Another video tape depicting violence has been found in the German army. Proceedings against 8 active and former soldiers of the mountain infantry battalion in Schneeberg (Saxony) haven been taken. The video depicts violent and extreme rightist scenes. Already this summer the so-called "Hammelburger video", which was produced by soldiers of the same battalion, had caused an uproar.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">SPD demands more preventive measures against juvenile crime </field>
<field name="text">The SPD demands more preventive measures to fight juvenile crime. A speaker of the party mentioned at a press conference that according to police statistics more and more young people are committing crimes. The number of children committing robberies on the street has more than doubled within the last 3 years. The SPD wants to find the root cause of juvenile crime. When children and teenagers turn into shop-lifters and street robbers, the cause must be a social one. Youth unemployment, the loss of traditional values and family ties, increasing poverty in Germany are reasons to establish a prevention plan like street social work for endangered and violent youths.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Project leader of Daimler transferred </field>
<field name="text">Daimler-Benz has drawn personal consequences from the mishap of the construction of the new C-class motor. The project leader in charge has been transferred.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Tennis: Prinosil dropped out in Stuttgart </field>
<field name="text">David Prinosil has dropped out of the ATP tennis match in Stuttgart in the eighth finale. Prinosil lost against Rafter from Australia, winner of the US Open, in 3 sets. As a surprise came the drop out of Pete Sampras (USA). Sampras lost in 2 sets against Krajicek who had defeated Boris Becker.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1997-10-23</field><field name="title">Exchange rates and stock markets </field>
<field name="text">Selected currencies:   Selected indices:   (Errors and omissions excepted)  </field></doc></add>