<add><doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">Schili steps up efforts for dual citizenship </field>
<field name="text">Federal Minister of the Interior Schili has stepped up efforts to implement the dual citizenship plan.  Bundestag representatives from the Bavarian SPD held a meeting at the Irsee monastery (also in Bavaria).  According to Mr. Schili, the members discussed the draft of the law to be proposed next week.  The minister was satisfied that the number of people who are critical of the signature campaign headed by (CDU politicians) Stoiber and Schaeuble is growing, even within the CDU. At the same time, Mr. Schili stressed that he is still open to constructive negotiations with the FDP and the CDU.  A new election of the full executive committee will also take place at the meeting. There is little doubt that the SPD state head will be reelected.  Meanwhile, there is growing opposition from within the CDU to its proposed signature campaign in opposition to the proposed dual citizenship law.  This issue will play center stage when CDU delegates meet in Koenigswinter near Bonn.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">CDU still committed to signature campaign </field>
<field name="text">Despite criticism from within its ranks, the CDU remains committed to its signature campaign in opposition to the proposed dual citizenship law.  The campaign was approved by a large majority at a meeting of the CDU executive committee in Koenigswinter.  Only three committee members voted against the initiative.  Party head Wolfgang Schaeuble said that collecting signatures was warranted because dual citizenship should be rejected.  He said it ran counter to the goal of integrating foreigners. At the same time, the CDU would like to make immigration easier for those foreigners who choose to remain in Germany for their entire lives. A CDU counter-proposal will be released soon.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">Jagoda calls for elimination of overtime hours </field>
<field name="text">According to Bernhard Jagoda, president of the Federal Institute of Labor, the elimination of overtime hours could create up to 400,000 new jobs. In a newspaper commentary, Mr. Jagoda stated that where there is a will there is a way, both for employers and employees. Mr. Jagoda appealed for voluntary compromises. He said that a legal resolution should always be the last resort.  He recommended that employers and works councils agree on more flexible work hours. The Federal Institute of Labor released statistics yesterday which indicated the number of unemployed in Germany increased by around 250,000 in December, reaching approximately 4.5 million.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">European politicians want Euro paper currency in 2000 </field>
<field name="text">After the Euro's successful start on financial markets, CDU and FDP have called for Euro paper currency to be issued earlier. Werner Hojer of the FDP stated that politicians have underestimated citizens' adaptability to the new currency. Hojer suggested minting notes and coins as early as 2001. He added that it is technically possible to have Euro currency ready by January 1, 2000. Karl Lamers of the CDU had similar thoughts. However, the Federal Ministry of Finance argued that the three year period between the introduction of the Euro and the issuing of currency is necessary to mint the notes and coins.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">Holocaust victims in US bring new class action suit </field>
<field name="text">According to the news magazine "Der Spiegel", several German insurance companies have been charged with conspiracy.  The report says that the companies are being charged with doing everything in their power to prevent plaintiffs from making claims. The legal papers are supposed to be received by several insurance companies companies with the next few days, including Allianz, Axa Colonia and Muenchner Rueckversicherung.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">German hostage set free </field>
<field name="text">A German held hostage in Columbia by underground guerrillas has now been released. The 60 year old physician from Munich was held hostage by the National Liberation Army (NLA). The NLA stated that it was not paid any ransom to release the hostage. But, it continued, the German government did much more by agreeing to support efforts to end the civil war in Columbia.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">Women's Union for approval of abortion pill RU486 </field>
<field name="text">The CDU Women's Union is now in favor of approving the abortion pill RU486 despite criticism from churches. Rita Suessmuth, Women's Union chairperson and former Bundestag president, stated in an interview that the use of the pill in legal pregnancy terminations is a responsible choice. Suessmuth continued, "Every abortion is a pregnancy termination. One cannot approve one method and condemn another as a means of committing murder."  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-01-09</field><field name="title">Police find mountain climbers in danger </field>
<field name="text">This morning a police helicopter team rescued two mountain climbers who were missing since the day before yesterday. The rescue took place at the mountain summit. The two men were discovered near the Hoellental summit. The climbers, who were suffering from severe exhaustion, were flown by police to a district hospital in Garmisch-Partenkirchen.  </field></doc></add>