<add><doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">German KFOR soldier commits suicide </field>
<field name="text">A German Army soldier of the German KFOR contingent in Macedonia died today through a shot from his service pistol. This was acknowledged by the Federal Ministry of Defense. The closer circumstances of the suicide are still being examined. The BILD magazine claims it was suicide. The magazine reports the soldier was on the way to Skopie as a passenger in a vehicle when he suddenly pulled his pistol and shot himself.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Coalition and Union critizise Riester's pension plans </field>
<field name="text">Federal Minister of Labor Riester has encountered criticism with his pension plans within his own SPD party and at the coalition partner alliance 90/The Green party. The social-democratic Prime Minister of the Saarland, Klint, expressed opposition in a newspaper article against a temporary coupling of the pension adjustment to the inflation rate. Green executive spokeswoman Roestel deplored that a democratic factor is missing which reflects the change in the age structure of the population. Spokeswoman Mueller of the Green Party said in Bonn that if no agreement could be reached among the pension specialists in Bonn, a solution must be found in the coalition round. The CDU called the suggested mandatory private supplementary provision unconstitutional and announced proceedings against it. Speakers of DGB, IG Metall and IG Bau criticized that the additional provision should be charged alone to employees. Federal Minister of Finance Eichel rejected the criticism. He explained in Wiesbaden the age structure of society would make a private provision necessary.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Continued discussion about 630-DM-Law </field>
<field name="text">The controversy over the 630-DM-Law and over the reorganization of the currency independence continues. The Union faction today presented the Bundestag in Bonn with a request in which the government is requested to take the amendment back immediately. The laws are a slap in the face for industrious persons and promote moonlighting, criticized DCU Social Expert Schnieber-Jastram. The SCU delegate Ramsauer referred to the fact that even leading Social Democrats would see the necessity for the rework of the 630-DM-Law. SPD politician Onur, on the other hand, defended the amendment. According to her, it stopped the escape from Social Security. Mrs. Onur accused the union of making the affected persons nervous. Her party colleague Dresen as well as the alliance-green Wolf promised meanwhile modifications of the reorganization to the containment of the currency independence.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Bundestag opposes loans for Ukraine atomic power plants </field>
<field name="text">The Bundestag expressed itself against western loans for two new atomic power plants in the Ukraine. The decision had majority votes of the SPD party and the Greens. According to the vote of parliament the Federal Government is to exert itself with the European Bank for reconstruction for the fact that no loans are granted.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Bundestag discusses rehabilitation of victims </field>
<field name="text">At noon the Bundestag discussed an improvement of vocational rehabilitation of humans affected by injustice of the Socialist Unity Party of Germany. The President of the Bundestag Thierse commemorated the victims of the rebellion in the GDR on June 17th, 1953.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Commemoration ceremony for June 17th in Berlin </field>
<field name="text">With a commemoration ceremony for June 17th in Berlin the governing mayor Diepgen announced a brisk implementation of the planned memorial for the protest of the people.  </field>
</doc>
<doc><field name="date">1999-06-17</field><field name="title">Church demands exemption of debts for developing countries </field>
<field name="text">Participants of the Evangelist church conference in Stuttgart requested from Federal Chancellor Schroeder to support the exemption of debts of the poorest developing countries on the world economy summit. In an assertion of the "forum globalization" it is stated that the created funds should be used for social development in the high-indebted states. In the future the survival rights of the poor would have to be protected by an international insolvency law. As host, Mr Schroeder is expected to present approximately 15 million signatures of a world-wide appeal to the remission of debts.  </field></doc></add>